<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Latest Data breaches</title><link>https://securenza.github.io/SecurityFeed/</link><description></description><item><title>Ukrainian Railways hit by ‘large-scale, targeted cyberattack’</title><link>https://databreaches.net/2025/03/24/ukrainian-railways-hit-by-large-scale-targeted-cyberattack/</link><author>Dissent</author><category>databreach</category><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:50:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://databreaches.net/">Recent Data breaches</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Martin Fornusek reports: Ukrainian Railways (Ukrzaliznytsia) was the target of a large-scale and sophisticated cyberattack, the company said on March 24, adding that the restoration of all systems is ongoing. “Ukrzaliznytsia’s online systems have been subjected to a large-scale, targeted cyberattack,” the state railway operator said in a statement. The company’s website and application became...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Over 3 million applicants’ data leaked on NYU’s website</title><link>https://databreaches.net/2025/03/23/over-3-million-applicants-data-leaked-on-nyus-website/</link><author>Dissent</author><category>databreach</category><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 11:28:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://databreaches.net/">Recent Data breaches</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dharma Niles, Krish Dev and Yezen Saadah report: A hacker took over NYU’s website for at least two hours Saturday morning to expose over 3 million applicants’ names, test scores, majors and zip codes, as well as information related to family members and financial aid dating back to at least 1989. The university’s website was...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trump Administration Begins Shifting Cyberattack Response to States</title><link>https://databreaches.net/2025/03/23/trump-administration-begins-shifting-cyberattack-response-to-states/</link><author>Dissent</author><category>databreach</category><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 11:02:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://databreaches.net/">Recent Data breaches</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Angus Loten and James Rundle report: The Trump administration wants state and local governments to play a bigger role in protecting water utilities, ports and other critical infrastructure from cyberattacks. In an executive order signed Tuesday, President Trump directed White House senior security advisers to draw up a national resilience plan to protect critical infrastructure...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Union County’s computer network breached, personal information accessed</title><link>https://databreaches.net/2025/03/23/union-countys-computer-network-breached-personal-information-accessed/</link><author>Dissent</author><category>databreach</category><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 11:01:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://databreaches.net/">Recent Data breaches</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[John Beauge reports: Personal information including Social Security numbers may be at risk as the result of unauthorized access and acquisition of data stored on a Pennsylvania county’s computer network. “We determined that the cyber criminals took certain data from our network, which included personally identifiable information,” the Union County commissioners revealed Friday. “The affected...]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Attorney General James Secures $975,000 from Auto Insurance Company over Data Breach</title><link>https://databreaches.net/2025/03/23/attorney-general-james-secures-975000-from-auto-insurance-company-over-data-breach/</link><author>Dissent</author><category>databreach</category><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 11:00:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://databreaches.net/">Recent Data breaches</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[From a March 20 press release from NY Attorney General Letitia James: NEW YORK – New York Attorney General Letitia James today secured $975,000 in penalties from Root, an auto insurance company, for failing to protect the personal information of approximately 45,000 New Yorkers. The data breach was part of an industry-wide campaign to steal consumers’...]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>