<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Youtube</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>The Future Night Skies Are Going to Be Unprecedented, Here&apos;s What&apos;s Changing</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CJ5OpCDVmaI</link><author>Astrum</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CJ5OpCDVmaI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 21:30:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-9b7aDP6ZN0coj9-xFnrtw">Astrum</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The familiar view of stars in our night sky is changing, fast! What has caused it? And what will it look like in the Future? 🔒Remove your personal information from the web at https://joindeleteme.com/ASTRUM and use code ASTRUM for 20% off 🙌 DeleteMe international Plans: https://international.joindeleteme.com

Astrum Podcast: https://www.buzzsprout.com/2250635/share
Displate Posters: https://astrumspace.info/Displates
Astrum Merch! https://astrum-shop.fourthwall.com/
Join us on the Astrum discord: https://discord.gg/TKw8Hpvtv8

SUBSCRIBE for more videos about space and astronomy. 
Subscribe! http://goo.gl/WX4iMN
Facebook! http://goo.gl/uaOlWW
Twitter! http://goo.gl/VCfejs

A huge thanks to our Patreons who help make these videos possible. Sign-up here: https://bit.ly/4aiJZNF

Astrum Spanish: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumespanol
Astrum Portuguese: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChn_-OwvV63mr1yeUGvH-BQ

Credits
Writer: Chris Bartlett
Editor: Nick Shishkin
Thumbnail Designer: Peter Sheppard
Producer: Alex McColgan / Raquel Taylor 

With special thanks to:
NASA/ESO/ESA
@astrobloke

Find out more about Dark Sky areas:
https://darksky.org/
https://www.lightpollutionmap.info

#astrum #astronomy #universe #darkskies #stargazing #nightsky #space]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Approval from the King! 📜 #FindingYourRoots #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MNeDeg19ptw</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MNeDeg19ptw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Rubén Blades ancestor in 1700s Panama was, at first, not able to be a notary because of his African ancestry. A quadroon, or in Spanish: cuarterón, was a term for a person with one quarter African ancestry. The decision was appealed to the King of Spain, Carlos III, who reversed the decision in a written letter, allowing Rubén's ancestor to become a notary!

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS App!

#history #panama #spanishhistory #ancestry 

Finding Your Roots
For more than a decade, renowned Harvard scholar Henry Louis Gates, Jr. has helped to expand America’s sense of itself, stimulating a national conversation about identity with humor, wisdom, and compassion. Professor Gates has explored the ancestry of dozens of influential people from diverse backgrounds, taking millions of viewers deep into the past to reveal the connections that bind us all.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A Mysterious Square &quot;ALIEN&quot; Structure on Mars? 🪐🔴👽</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ODqDQvAcDXs</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ODqDQvAcDXs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 19:04:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Keep an open mind and Keep Looking Up ! 🔭

🪐🔴👽 to watch our latest video with Neil deGrasse Tyson discussing that mysterious square "alien" structure on Mars! 

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hoff Twins for the win</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NmKiyu2lbNQ</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NmKiyu2lbNQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 18:17:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How farmers are protecting the soil and our food security | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k_RiNPKJNdE</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/k_RiNPKJNdE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 17:00:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[For a long time, soil was all but ignored. But for years, the valuable humus layer has been thinning. Farmers in Brandenburg are clearly feeling the effects of this on their sandy fields. Many are now taking steps to prepare their farms for the future.

Years of drought, record rainfall and failed harvests: we are becoming increasingly aware of how sensitively our environment reacts to extreme weather conditions. Farmers' livelihoods are at stake. So is the ability of consumers to afford food. 
For a few years now, agriculture that focuses solely on maximum yields has been regarded with increasing skepticism. It is becoming more and more clear just how dependent we are on healthy soils.
Brandenburg is the federal state with the worst soil quality in Germany. The already thin, fertile humus layer has been shrinking for decades. Researchers and farmers who are keen to experiment are combating these developments and looking for solutions. Priority is being given to building up the humus layer, which consists of microorganisms and fungi, as well as springtails, small worms and centipedes. 
For Lena and Philipp Adler, two young vegetable farmers, the tiny soil creatures are invaluable helpers. On their three-hectare organic farm, they rely on simple, mechanical weed control, fallow areas where the soil can recover, and diversity. Conventional farmer Mark Dümichen also does everything he can to protect soil life on his land. For years, he has not tilled the soil after the harvest and sows directly into the field. His yields have stabilized since he began to work this way.
Isabella Krause from Regionalwert AG Berlin-Brandenburg is convinced after the experiences of the last hot summers that new crops will thrive on Brandenburg's fields in the long term. She has founded a network of farmers who are promoting the cultivation of chickpeas with support from the scientific community. 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #germany #agriculture 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How to bowl perfectly</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mqo1lQL59VI</link><author>Veritasium</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mqo1lQL59VI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 16:49:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA">Veritasium</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[What is the optimal strategy for bowling? #science #veritasium #physics #bowling]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What Falling in Love Does to You #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KmgRBiRMmAU</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KmgRBiRMmAU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 15:00:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Being in love impacts your brain and body significantly! No matter which stage you're in, be it Attraction, Attachment, or Long-term commitment, each one triggers different hormones.

#kurzgesagt
#inanutshell #kurzgesagt_inanutshell #learnwithshorts #science 

Sources & further reading: 
https://sites.google.com/view/kgs-tiktok-sources

Follow us for more sciencey content! 🦆

OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤ https://shop.kgs.link/shorts
Become a Part of kurzgesagt by joining the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The Kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of Kurzgesagt Soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Neurodiversity Can Help Your Life, Team &amp; Business • Katrine Hald Kjeldsen • GOTO 2024</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CIBlbmk1U_c</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CIBlbmk1U_c?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This presentation was recorded at GOTO Copenhagen 2024. #GOTOcon #GOTOcph
https://gotocph.com

Katrine Hald Kjeldsen - Neuro-inclusion Specialist @katrinehaldkjeldsen6145 

ORIGINAL TALK TITLE
Change Your Life, Help Your Team & Boost Your Business with Neurodiversity

RESOURCES
https://www.linkedin.com/in/katrinekjeldsen

ABSTRACT
Are you a little spicy? If not, your colleague most probably is. Either way, this talk is for you.

In this session, Katrine will shine a light on neurodiversity and the transformative impact it can have on your life, your team, and your business.

Neurodiversity is not only abundantly prevalent in tech organizations; it is a powerful, often underutilized asset that manifests in every corner of our work environments. It is paramount that we adjust our understanding and strategies around this diversity to thrive. Katrine will explore how neurodiversity shows up in the most unexpected ways and why it’s both surprisingly easy and surprisingly challenging to harness its potential in team collaboration and leadership.

This talk will emphasize practical daily strategies to strengthen collaboration and leverage the advantages of neurodiversity in everyday work contexts, whether it’s adopting clear communication methods, allowing flexible work arrangements, or designing team workflows that play to diverse cognitive strengths. [...]

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
04:58 Neurodivergent
16:37 Dopamine & ADHD
21:25 Autism
24:47 Diverse perspective
34:40 Conclusions
42:52 Outro

Download slides and read the full abstract here:
https://gotocph.com/2024/sessions/3472

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Ph.D. Thomas Armstrong • The Power of Neurodiversity • https://amzn.to/3OrbPOg
Maureen Dunne • The Neurodiversity Edge • https://amzn.to/494dGSE
Emily Kircher-Morris & Amanda Morin • Neurodiversity-Affirming Schools • https://amzn.to/3ZjJRdI
Nancy Doyle & Almuth McDowall • Neurodiversity Coaching • https://amzn.to/4fGDdnn

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#Neurodiversity #Neurodivergent #Autism #ADHD #ParallelPlay #DeepCuriosity #Diversity #Inclusivity #Autism #DiverseTeams #Teams #KatrineHaldKjeldsen

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Learning Microsoft Azure • Jonah Andersson &amp; Håkan Silfvernagel</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gEQZBmoN8LM</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gEQZBmoN8LM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 10:41:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for the GOTO Book Club.
http://gotopia.tech/bookclub

Read the full transcription of the interview here
 (https://gotopia.tech/episodes/339) 
Jonah Andersson - Senior Azure Consultant at Solidify & Author of "Learning Microsoft Azure"
Håkan Silfvernagel - Senior AI Architect at Sopra Steria & Microsoft AI MVP

RESOURCES
Jonah
https://x.com/cjkodare
https://medium.com/@jonah.andersson
https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonahandersson
https://github.com/jonahandersson
https://jonahandersson.tech

Håkan
https://x.com/agrevlis
https://www.linkedin.com/in/hakansilfvernagel
https://sessionize.com/hakan-silfvernagel

Links
https://www.meetup.com/azureusergroupsundsvallsverige
https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/extendwomenintechpodcast

DESCRIPTION
Jonah Andersson, interviewed by Håkan Silfvernagel, shared her experiences writing "Learning Microsoft Azure". With a focus on making the content accessible for beginners, she carefully structured the book to cover essential Azure topics such as cloud computing fundamentals, security, and AI, while drawing on insights from experts in her network, including Microsoft Certified Trainers and MVPs.

Over nearly two years, Jonah Andersson navigated the challenges of a rapidly evolving tech landscape, incorporating emerging trends like generative AI. Passionate about fostering inclusivity in tech, she emphasized the importance of mentorship and community support for underrepresented groups, particularly women. Looking ahead, Jonah Andersson expressed a desire to write a biography that reflects her life lessons and professional journey in technology.

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Jonah Andersson • Learning Microsoft Azure
 (https://amzn.to/48cOw3T) Adrienne Braganza Tacke • "Looks Good to Me": Constructive Code Reviews
 (https://amzn.to/3E75XrD) Adrienne Braganza Tacke • Coding for Kids
 (https://amzn.to/3Ukd5Gw) Martin Fowler • Refactoring
 (https://amzn.to/3EVcHXQ) Matthew Skelton & Manuel Pais • Team Topologies (http://amzn.to/3sVLyLQ) 


Bluesky (https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com) 
Twitter (https://twitter.com/GOTOcon) 
Instagram (https://www.instagram.com/goto_con) 
LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-) 
Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences) 

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket: gotopia.tech (https://gotopia.tech) 

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL (https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1)  - new videos posted daily!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Can Japan’s Carmakers Survive China’s EV Threat?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y7aZfU6u2lU</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Y7aZfU6u2lU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 09:00:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Japanese carmakers like Honda and Nissan are losing market share at an alarming rate, especially in Southeast Asia. Their decline comes just as China is taking the lead in electrification. 

This raises the question: Can the once mighty Japanese car brands rally in the face of this threat? 

Get the Hyperdrive newsletter, your guide to the future of cars, from reporters around the world:
https://www.bloomberg.com/account/newsletters/hyperdrive?sref=omvmmwIg?utm_medium=social&utm_source=youtube&utm_campaign=originals&utm_content=article

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for $1.99/month for the first 3 months: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals

Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg Quicktake for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What’s Up With That Square Structure on Mars</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dYDa9cZptTY</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/dYDa9cZptTY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 22:30:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/startalk to stay fully informed on the latest Space and Science news. Save 40% off through our link for unlimited access to the Vantage plan this month.

What's up with the square structure discovered on Mars? Neil deGrasse Tyson breaks down the Mars Global Surveyor, the images we have of Mars, and our urge to blame things on aliens. 

Timestamps: 
00:00 - What's Up With The Mars Square? 
00:10 - The Mars Global Surveyor
2:50 - Pareidolia & Other Things We’ve Spotted
6:30 - “IT’S ALIENS!”

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Were These Ancient Civilizations So Mysteriously Advanced?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EtqbZx_7szk</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EtqbZx_7szk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 22:00:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Discover the mind-blowing engineering feats of ancient civilizations, from towering pyramids to advanced navigation tools that shaped our modern world. Unravel the secrets behind their mysterious innovations and see how their genius still influences technology today.

Discover the past on History Hit with ad-free exclusive podcasts and documentaries released weekly presented by world renowned historians Dan Snow, Suzannah Lipscomb, Matt Lewis and more. Get 50% off your first 3 months with code 'TIMELINE' 👉 https://historyhit.com/subscribe 

You can find more from us on:

https://www.facebook.com/timelineWH

https://www.tiktok.com/@timelineworldhistory

https://www.instagram.com/timelineWH

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Final Barrier to (Nearly) Infinite Energy</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nAJN1CrJsVE</link><author>PBS Space Time</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/nAJN1CrJsVE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 21:15:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC7_gcs09iThXybpVgjHZ_7g">PBS Space Time</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Thanks to Radiacode for sponsoring this video. Use the promo code "PBS" to get an exclusive 10% discount at: https://103.radiacode.com/PBS 

They say fusion is 50 years away, no matter when you ask. Then why are billions suddenly being pumped into fusion startups? Yes to train LLMs, but there's a reason the technobrats are bullish on fusion in particular. The fact is, the technological challenges have been chipped away and in many cases solved over the past decades, and there's really no one deal-breaker difficulty remaining. One of the final challenges is deciding on the physical vessel to contain our mini artificial stars--and we have some pretty sci-fi options that are nearly ready to go.

PBS Member Stations rely on viewers like you. To support your local station, go to:http://to.pbs.org/DonateSPACE

Sign Up on Patreon to get access to the Space Time Discord!
https://www.patreon.com/pbsspacetime

Check out the Space Time Merch Store
https://www.pbsspacetime.com/shop

Sign up for the mailing list to get episode notifications and hear special announcements!
https://mailchi.mp/1a6eb8f2717d/spacetime

Search the Entire Space Time Library Here: https://search.pbsspacetime.com/

Hosted by Matt O'Dowd
Written by Matt Caplan, Jake Mitstifer, & Matt O'Dowd 
Post Production by Leonardo Scholzer, Yago Ballarini & Stephanie Faria
Directed by Andrew Kornhaber
Associate Producer: Bahar Gholipour
Executive Producer: Andrew Kornhaber
Executive in Charge for PBS: Maribel Lopez
Director of Programming for PBS: Gabrielle Ewing
Assistant Director of Programming for PBS: John Campbell

Spacetime is a production of Kornhaber Brown for PBS Digital Studios.
This program is produced by Kornhaber Brown, which is solely responsible for its content.
© 2024 PBS. All rights reserved.

End Credits Music by J.R.S. Schattenberg: https://www.youtube.com/user/MultiDroideka

Space Time Was Made Possible In Part By: 

Big Bang
Wojciech Szymski
Bryce Fort
Peter Barrett
Alexander Tamas
Morgan Hough
Juan Benet
Vinnie Falco
Mark Rosenthal

Supernova
Grace Biaelcki
Glenn Sugden
Ethan Cohen
Stephen Wilcox
The Tyacke boys
Mark Heising

Hypernova
Ulrich and Alexandre Francois
Spencer Jones
Dean Galvin
Michael Tidwell
Stephen Spidle
Massimiliano Pala
Justin Lloyd
David Giltinan
Kenneth See
Gregory Forfa
Alex Kern
Scott Gorlick
Paul Stehr-Green
Ben Delo
Scott Gray
Антон Кочков
Robert Ilardi
John R. Slavik
Donal Botkin
chuck zegar
Daniel Muzquiz

Gamma Ray Burst
Bryan White
Eric Raschke
Aaron Pinto
Kacper Cieśla
Satwik Pani
Param Saxena
John De Witt
Nathaniel Bennett
Sandhya Devi
Michael Oulvey
Arko Provo Mukherjee
Mike Purvis
Christopher Wade
Anthony Crossland
Grace Seraph
Stephen Saslow
Robert DeChellis
Tomaz Lovsin
Anthony Leon
Lori Ferris
Koen Wilde
Nicolas Katsantonis
Richard Steenbergen
Joe Pavlovic
Chuck Lukaszewski
Cole B. Combs
Jerry Thomas
Nikhil Sharma
John Anderson
Bradley Ulis
Craig Falls
Kane Holbrook
Ross Story
Harsh Khandhadia
Matt Quinn
Michael Lev
Rad Antonov
Terje Vold
James Trimmier
Jeremy Soller
Paul Wood
Kent Durham
Jim Bartosh
John H. Austin, Jr.
Faraz Khan
Almog Cohen
Daniel Jennings
David Johnston
Michael Barton
Isaac Suttell
Bleys Goodson
Mark Delagasse
Mark Daniel Cohen
Shane Calimlim
Tybie Fitzhugh
Eric Kiebler
Craig Stonaha
Frederic Simon
Jim Hudson
Michael Purcell
John Funai
Adrien Molyneux
Bradley Jenkins
Vlad Shipulin
Justin Waters
Thomas Dougherty
Zac Sweers
Dan Warren
Joseph Salomone]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Roman Gods and Religion in the Empire | Life in Ancient Times with @DariusArya</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BcW5rZiKdRw</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/BcW5rZiKdRw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Explore the complex religious life of ancient Rome, where religion played a vital role in the political, social, and personal aspects of people's lives. From the Temple of Jupiter Optimus Maximus in Rome’s port city of Ostia to local shrines and colossal structures like the Pantheon, the ancient Romans worshipped a pantheon of gods, some local and others imported from across the Mediterranean.

One key feature of Roman religion was its ability to adapt and innovate. New gods were welcomed into the Roman pantheon, often from the peoples Rome conquered or traded with, such as the Egyptian goddess Isis, who became immensely popular by the Imperial period and received a large temple in the Campus Martius. Another example is Mithras, a mysterious god with Persian origins whose worship involved secret underground rituals and appealed particularly to Roman soldiers.

Public temples were monumental structures that marked sacred spaces. They served both religious and practical functions, often housing libraries, halls, and spaces for the public to gather. Temples were dedicated to the well-being of the state, such as the Temple of Saturn, which doubled as the city treasury, or the Temple of Castor and Pollux, linked to military victories.

Made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS App: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

#romanempire #religion #anthropology 

Life in Ancient Times with Darius Arya
Embark on an unforgettable voyage across the ancient world with archaeologist @DariusArya to unearth the secrets of civilizations past, delving into the daily rituals, extraordinary achievements, and cultural legacies that shaped our world as we know it today.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Andrew talks modern journalism &amp; legacy media</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4q-hwlIi8Ds</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4q-hwlIi8Ds?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 19:13:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Germany At War: The Brutal Fight for Survival</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YA0Yq5Aqi9k</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/YA0Yq5Aqi9k?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 18:00:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[From the trenches to the Third Reich, never before seen diaries & photos reveal life of German Solider & Teacher Wilhelm Kurtz.

Hidden away since his death, they chart his life on the front during the first world war where he served on the western front against the French and English from 1914 to 1918. 

Writing on the morning of the 11th November, Wilhelm reveals in depth his and his comrades feelings and thoughts about the armistice - giving us never before heard insight into those final moments.

His letters and diaries from 1929 onwards reveal the rise of Hitler and the Nazis and his own involvement and ultimately the defeat of Nazi Germany and his own experience of the denazification process. 

00:00:00 Introduction
00:02:12 Title Sequence
00:02:44 Wilhelm Kurts
00:03:35 War!
00:04:19 German Army Advances
00:04:50 Mobilisation 
00:05:43 August 1914
00:06:31 Wilhelm Goes To War
00:07:16 Journey To The Front
00:08:07 First Graves
00:09:02 The Front
00:09:45 Christmas 1914
00:11:13 1929 The Great Depression 
00:13:22 Hitlers Ascent
00:13:49 1915 Back On The Front
00:16:20 Kaisers Birthday
00:17:03 Defences
00:18:22 Preparation 
00:19:01 The First Assault 
00:20:42 French Counterattacks 
00:21:48 The Face Of War
00:23:41 Casualties 
00:23:58 1934 Hitler's Power Grab
00:25:17 1916 Verdun
00:26:40 Advance 
00:27:39 Attack The Ridge
00:30:46 The Injured
00:32:15 French Bombardment
00:33:16 1935 Nazification 
00:38:09 1917 
00:38:56 French POWS
00:39:43 Mines
00:41:51 Re-deployment 
00:42:43 Night Bombardment & Gassing 
00:43:33 1939 German Invasion of Poland. WW2 Begins.
00:45:05 1918 Operation Michael
00:46:31 Operation Georgette 
00:47:41 Over The Top
00:49:30 Allies Assault's 
00:51:13 The Black Day Of The German Army
00:51:57 Retreat
00:53:07 English Attack
00:53:47 October 1918
00:57:15 Anger & Despair 
00:58:02 Withdrawal 
00:58:25 Politcal Unrest 
00:59:02 November 1918
00:59:22 Rebellions & Kaisers Abdication 
01:00:13 Delegation Leaves Germany To Begin Peace Talks
01:01:39 11 November 1918
01:03:26 Marching Into Darkness
01:06:18 1946 Germany In Ruins
01:07:33 Denazification 
01:08:36 Wilhelm's Account
01:11:12 The Initial Verdict 
01:12:44 Wilhelm Fights To Clear His Name
01:13:31 Final Verdict 

We are grateful to the family for allowing us to tell this story.

Special thanks to Bart Degroote, Zeitgeist Tours, Hoodge Crater Museum, Niek Benoot & Phillippe, Oosterlinck.

To get closer to WW1 check out the tours and sessions provided by https://www.zeitgeisttours.com/

Discover the past on History Hit with ad-free exclusive podcasts and documentaries released weekly presented by world renowned historians Dan Snow, Suzannah Lipscomb, Lucy Worsely, Mary Beard and more. Watch, listen and read history wherever you are, whenever you want it. Available on all devices: Apple TV, Amazon Prime Video, Android TV, Samsung Smart TV, Roku, Xbox, Chromecast, and iOs & Android.

We're offering a special discount to History Hit for our subscribers, get 50% off your first 3 months with code YOUTUBE: https://www.historyhit.com/subscription/?utm_source=youtube&utm_medium=description&utm_campaign=YouTube2024

#historyhit #ww1history #rarefootage]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>If a frozen Ice Age puppy is a pupsicle, is a frozen kitten a cubsicle?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cGe4GxuAtqE</link><author>PBS Eons</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cGe4GxuAtqE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 17:15:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzR-rom72PHN9Zg7RML9EbA">PBS Eons</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[*****
PBS Member Stations rely on viewers like you. To support your local station, go to http://to.pbs.org/DonateEons
*****

Eons is a production of Complexly for PBS Digital Studios.

Super special thanks to the following Patreon patrons for helping make Eons possible:
Ruth Orr, Randall George, Morgan, Kevin Lacson, Marco Narajos, Ian Leavitt, Collin Dutrow, Pope John XII, Aaditya Mehta, AllPizzasArePersonal, John H. Austin, Jr., Alex Hackman, Stephen Patterson, Gizmo, Karen Farrell, Jason Rostoker, Jonathan Rust, Mary Tevington, Bart & Elke van Iersel - De Jong, Irene Wood, Mark Talbott-Williams, Nomi Alchin, Hillary Ryde-Collins, Duane Westhoff, Yu Mei, Albert Folsom, Dan Caffee, Nick Ryhajlo, Jeff Graham

If you'd like to support the channel, head over to http://patreon.com/eons and pledge for some cool rewards!

Want to follow Eons elsewhere on the internet?
Facebook - https://www.facebook.com/eonsshow
Twitter - https://twitter.com/eonsshow
Instagram - https://www.instagram.com/eonsshow/
#Eons]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why the giant kapok tree is so important for the ecosystem in the Amazon rainforest | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-iuG7TMBFIY</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-iuG7TMBFIY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The majestic kapok tree in the Amazon rainforest forms a gigantic habitat. Its canopy of leaves, almost 50 meters high, towers over the crowns of the forest. The tree shapes the myths of the indigenous Wayana people.

With over 80,000 plant species and hundreds of thousands of animal species, the Amazon rainforest is a green ocean of life. In the midst of this ecosystem, the kapok tree provides both shelter and crucial spaces for reproduction. Numerous animal species could not survive without the kapok tree. 
Dragonflies and damselflies buzz around the spines on its trunk to lay their larvae in the bromeliad ‘air plants’ that grow on the tree. Here, the smallest influences the largest - and vice versa. Bromeliad plants do double duty, acting as floating water reservoirs: they store up to 50,000 liters of water per hectare of forest.

When the forest floor is under water during the rainy season, the fish become gardeners. They feed on the seeds that have fallen from the trees and spread them all over the Amazon region. The kapok tree is firmly anchored in the ground with its huge roots until the next dry season. The whole forest breathes, from the moss on the ground to the treetops. This gas exchange makes life on earth possible. But dangers such as deforestation and climate change threaten this unique ecosystem.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #amazonrainforest #kapok  
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Save the Cows</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bVSGSQQenSE</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bVSGSQQenSE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 16:58:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Should we get rid of pregnancy?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h0rWp3GF_6s</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/h0rWp3GF_6s?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Ada imagines a life where she could have children without giving birth. Would artificial wombs give us more choice or less?

--

This is episode 3 of the animated series, “Ada.” This 5-episode narrative follows the young library assistant Ada as she juggles two worlds: her daily mundane reality and the future she vividly imagines for all humanity. Traveling through her visions of potential futures, Ada grapples with the ethical and social implications of new technologies and how they could shape the world.

Written by Elizabeth Cox, directed by Elizabeth Cox & Kirill Yeretsky. 

This video was produced by Should We Studio.
Learn more about how TED-Ed partnerships work: https://bit.ly/TEDEdPartners

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/should-we-get-rid-of-pregnancy-ada-ep-3
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/should-we-get-rid-of-pregnancy-ada-ep-3/digdeeper
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Kyanta Yap, Rebecca Reineke, William Biersdorf, Patricia Alves Panagides, Yvette Mocete, Cyrus Garay, Samuel Barbas, LadyGeek, Marin Kovachev, Penelope Misquitta, Hans Peng, Gaurav Mathur, Erik Biemans, Tony, Michelle, Katie and Josh Pedretti, Hoai Nam Tran, Kack-Kyun Kim, Michael Braun-Boghos, zjweele13, Anna-Pitschna Kunz, Edla Paniguel, Thomas Mungavan, Jaron Blackburn, Venkat Venkatakrishnan, ReuniteKorea, Aaron Henson, Rohan Gupta, Begum Tutuncu, Brian Richards, Jørgen Østerpart, Tyron Jung, Carsten Tobehn, Katie Dean, Ezgi Yersu, Gerald Onyango, alessandra tasso, Doreen Reynolds-Consolati, Manognya Chakrapani, Ayala Ron, Eunsun Kim, Phyllis Dubrow, Ophelia Gibson Best, Paul Schneider, Joichiro Yamada, Henrique Cassús, Karthik Cherala, Clarence E. Harper Jr., Vignan Velivela, Ana Maria, Exal Enrique Cisneros Tuch, and Tejas Dc.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Life as a trans boy | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=69qK9vlrPwQ</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/69qK9vlrPwQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Luca has known he is trans from a young age, which has allowed him to grow and develop in the way he feels most comfortable. This freedom has come with its own set of challenges, especially in terms of how he’s seen and accepted by others. 

Watch the documentary on our channel.  

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #trans #transyouth #queerrights
______

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Better Value Sooner Safer Happier • Simon Rohrer &amp; Eduardo da Silva • GOTO 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8oqT5tjqf-0</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8oqT5tjqf-0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:00:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for the GOTO Book Club. #GOTOcon #GOTObookclub
http://gotopia.tech/bookclub

Read the full transcription of the interview here:
https://gotopia.tech/episodes/356

Simon Rohrer - Co-Author of "Better Value Sooner Safer Happier" & Senior Director at Saxo Bank @SimonRohrer 
Eduardo da Sliva - Independent Consultant on Organization, Architecture, and Leadership Modernization @emgsilva 

RESOURCES
Simon
https://bsky.app/profile/simon.bvssh.com
https://mastodon.social/@simonr
https://x.com/sirohrer
https://www.linkedin.com/in/simonrohrer
https://github.com/sirohrer
https://www.soonersaferhappier.com

Eduardo
https://bsky.app/profile/esilva.net
https://mastodon.social/@eduardodasilva
https://x.com/emgsilva
https://www.linkedin.com/in/emgsilva
https://github.com/emgsilva
https://esilva.net

Links
https://youtu.be/oOYddleBsuk
https://youtu.be/ESOaDiv3lXA
https://youtu.be/B3b4tremI5o
https://youtu.be/WPCrGYjrJ1Y
https://youtu.be/48g7CRlMUD8
https://youtu.be/86-Dy5U2p5Y
https://youtu.be/l1tyfb5we7I
https://youtu.be/B7JqZh9A2pQ
https://youtu.be/yuEbZYKgZas
https://youtu.be/hBxV3Cr0lXY
https://youtu.be/HKS5sKsIkkc

DESCRIPTION
Eduardo da Silva and Simon Rohrer discuss the core ideas of "Better Value Sooner Safer Happier" diving into the principles of organizational transformation.

Simon shares insights on the shift from output-driven to outcome-focused thinking, emphasizing value over productivity, and the need for continuous improvement in delivery speed, stakeholder satisfaction, and safety.
The conversation explores key concepts like technical excellence, integrating safety into development, and balancing incremental changes with occasional larger steps.

Simon Rohrer discusses organizational patterns and the importance of decentralizing decision-making, recommending a flexible, context-driven approach to transformation. The session concludes with practical advice on how to start implementing these ideas, using the book’s map to guide organizations toward the right transformation strategy based on their specific goals.

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
01:55 The journey to "Better Value Sooner Safer Happier"
06:14 Antipatterns & patterns for business agility
14:09 Embracing continuous attention to technical excellence
24:43 Embedding safety in continuous delivery
33:31 Balancing incremental change & big leaps in transformation
40:18 Exploring organizational patterns
44:12 Outro

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Jonathan Smart, Zsolt Berend, Myles Ogilvie & Simon Rohrer • Sooner Safer Happier • https://amzn.to/3Emm9p2
Stephen Fishman & Matt McLarty • Unbundling the Enterprise • https://amzn.to/3W2EcXw
Carliss Y. Baldwin • Design Rules, Vol. 2 • https://amzn.to/4hdllRr
Matthew Skelton & Manuel Pais • Team Topologies • http://amzn.to/3sVLyLQ
Forsgren, Humble & Kim • Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and DevOps • https://amzn.to/3tCz1xO
Kim, Humble, Debois, Willis & Forsgren • The DevOps Handbook • https://amzn.to/47oAf3l

https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#BetterValue #SoonerSaferHappier #OrganizationalTransformation #BusinessAgility #Agility #ValueOverProductivity #ContinuousDelivery #ContinuousAttention #Safety #TechnicalExcellence #BookClub

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>3 thing the M4 Sherman did BETTER than the rest</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G2Eye9ICYZo</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/G2Eye9ICYZo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Ted Leonsis Wants to Build a &apos;Super City&apos; of Sports Teams | The Deal</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eZtSKgjILKw</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eZtSKgjILKw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 23:00:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode of The Deal, Alex Rodriguez and Jason Kelly sit with Ted Leonsis, founder of Monumental Sports and Entertainment, to discuss how he came to dominate the Washington DC sports scene. Leonsis shares what he learned from the “world’s worst deal” at AOL and how he’s helping the US capital become a “super city” by investing in its teams. 

Listen to The Deal on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, iHeart, Bloomberg Carplay, or wherever you get your podcasts. You can also watch The Deal on Bloomberg Originals and Bloomberg TV.

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for $1.99/month for the first 3 months: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals

Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg Quicktake for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ancient Egyptian Mega Tomb Mystery | Full Documentary | Secrets of the Dead | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CaXuVJqfYw4</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CaXuVJqfYw4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 23:00:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch more: https://to.pbs.org/3mHxfbj | #SecretsDeadPBS
The discovery of a rare mass grave with the bones of nearly 60 people outside Luxor sends archaeologists on a quest to find out who the remains belong to, why they were buried the way they were and what was happening in ancient Egypt that would have led to a mass burial. Could the collapse of the empire’s Old Kingdom provide any clues? [Originally aired in 2019]

Following the long reign of Pepi II, a series of weak kings ruled ineffectively. Without a strong central government, local leaders asserted themselves, fracturing the country’s power base. As the climate shifted all over the world, the country was then hit by a decades-long drought that caused a great famine and economic failure.

Go behind the scenes with archaeologists and scientists as they venture through Africa – from the Pyramids to the glaciers of Mt. Kilimanjaro – in search of clues to solve the mystery of the mass grave, examining the political and environmental catastrophes that plunged Egypt and its people into anarchy. Were the bodies found victims of the famine, civil war or something else?

Egypt's Darkest Hour | Secrets of the Dead

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS App: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW PBS:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

Secrets of the Dead on YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/@secretsofthedead

#SecretsoftheDead #Egypt #archaeology #history #ancientegypt 

Secrets of the Dead
Part detective story, part true-life drama, @secretsofthedead unearths evidence from around the world, challenging prevailing ideas and throwing fresh light on unexplained events.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Unboxing a Zilpzalp keyboard &amp; 0xCB 1337 macropad!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vpTjt1Fw7hU</link><author>Chyrosran22</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vpTjt1Fw7hU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 17:34:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCD0y51PJfvkZNe3y3FR5riw">Chyrosran22</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get them here:
https://keeb.supply/products/zilpzalp
https://keeb.supply/products/0xcb-1337
Today we're unboxing.... whatever the hell this thing is xD . Hope you enjoy the video! :)

Intro by Kyle Carter
Outro by Facundo Cabanne

My keyboard reviews: http://bit.ly/1TbOtft
My switch teardowns: http://bit.ly/2C1QGHz
My TOP X videos: http://bit.ly/2FmpZfd
My XL typing demos: https://bit.ly/2OoAW3w
My tutorials and featurettes: https://bit.ly/2OrkLUh
My unboxing videos: https://bit.ly/2TSrr0m

I'm Thomas and I do videos and reviews on mechanical keyboards ranging from the most sickening modern RGB gaming keyboards to vintage hardware relics, or sometimes keycaps or keyswitches ranging from Cherry MX to Alps SKCM to IBM buckling springs and anything in between.

Follow me on Twitter for updates on my keyboard videos! https://twitter.com/chyrosran22]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What is this Weapon Presents: Antiques Gunshow 2 with Dave Jewitt and Jonathan Ferguson</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4o1Mk8M-AtU</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4o1Mk8M-AtU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 17:18:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Royal Armouries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dave and Jonathan return for a repeat of the museum supermarket sweep that is 'Antiques Gunshow'. This time, the category is: Video Games.

In other exciting news, Jonathan will be returning on Saturdays to expertly react to more cursed video game guns on Dave & Co's new channel @WatchEXP .

0:00 Intro
1:52 Cue Montage
2:38 Round 1: Pistols
13:58 Round 2: Secondary
28:52 Dave's Special Announcement
29:48 Round 3: Primary
38:48 Bonus Round: 'Overkill'
48:22 Outro

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Stone Age diet - What did our human ancestors eat? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Ij-guv8GE0</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/3Ij-guv8GE0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[What did man's ancestors eat? How did they prepare their food? How did their food contribute to their evolution and their anatomical and cognitive development? This film provides answers based on new research findings.

Food. Since the beginning of time, obtaining food has been one of the most important activities of mankind. Research using new methods for examining and analyzing human fossils reveals previously unknown facets of prehistoric man. The results demonstrate the central role that food plays in the anatomical, genetic and social evolution of humans.
Until the beginning of agriculture in the Neolithic period, the first humans fed on what nature provided for them. Their diet shaped their evolution and humanity as we know it today.
This two-part documentary invites you on a journey into the past and shows the complexity and diversity of prehistoric life based on scientific findings from around the world. Suzana Herculano-Houzel explains how the cooking of food influenced the mental performance of early humans. Delphine Vettese from the Natural History Museum in Paris shows how cutting techniques for mincing meat and scraping out bone marrow were passed down from generation to generation. João Zilhão and Ernestina Badal present the results of their research into prehistoric food remains.
From archaeological sites in the Dordogne to Portugal, the USA and Jordan, the film shows spectacular images of caves, semi-caves and other prehistoric sites in nature.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #archaeology #food #ancestors #stoneage 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is it WISE to admit you&apos;re IGNORANT?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZGEfnMjcW58</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZGEfnMjcW58?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 16:23:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Apache Kafka Meets Apache Iceberg: Real-Time Data Streaming • Kasun Indrasiri • GOTO 2024</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bzVjBu5nhyM</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bzVjBu5nhyM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 13:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This presentation was recorded at GOTO Chicago 2024. #GOTOcon #GOTOchgo
https://gotochgo.com

Kasun Indrasiri - Author of "Microservices for the Enterprise" @kasunindrasiri 

ORIGINAL TALK TITLE
Kafka Meets Iceberg: Real-Time Data Streaming into Modern Data Lakes & Warehouses

RESOURCES
https://twitter.com/kasunindrasiri
https://medium.com/@kasunindrasiri
https://www.linkedin.com/in/kasun-indrasiri

ABSTRACT
In this talk, we'll explore how Kafka serves as a powerful platform for capturing real-time streaming data and how organizations are increasingly adopting Apache Iceberg table format to store data in data lakes and data warehouses. We'll discuss the key benefits of using Apache Iceberg tables in your data lake such as schema evolution, ACID transactions, hidden partitioning, time traveling and efficient querying.

Next, we'll dive into how to efficiently stream data from Kafka into Iceberg-based data lakes. Confluent Tableflow will be introduced as a potential solution for streamlining the ingestion of Kafka streams into Iceberg tables within your data lake. A live demo will showcase the seamless integration of Kafka with Iceberg, equipping participants with practical knowledge to enhance their data architectures for powerful real-time analytics.

• The role of Kafka in real-time data streaming
• Why Apache Iceberg is essential for data lakes and data warehouses
• Iceberg fundamentals: Core concepts and key features
• Streaming data from Kafka to Iceberg tables in data lakes
• Use case: Leveraging Confluent Tableflow to stream Kafka data into data lakes and warehouses [...]

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
01:10 Overview
02:06 Kafka is the standard for operational data
03:41 Iceberg for analytical data in data lakes
04:42 Apache Iceberg
05:27 Why Iceberg?
12:24 Structure of an Iceberg table
16:40 Streaming to data lakes is complicated
20:47 Tableflow materialize Kafka topics as Iceberg tables
23:47 Demo
35:37 Outro

Download slides and read the full abstract here:
https://gotochgo.com/2024/sessions/3370

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Kasun Indrasiri & Sriskandarajah Suhothayan • Design Patterns for Cloud Native Applications • https://amzn.to/3szGx0p
Kasun Indrasiri & Danesh Kuruppu • gRPC: Up and Running • https://amzn.to/3sBGBJJ
Kasun Indrasiri & Prabath Siriwardena • Microservices for the Enterprise • https://amzn.to/40FhxkQ
Kasun Indrasiri • Beginning WSO2 ESB • https://amzn.to/3sx9NF0

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#ApacheKafka #Kafka #ApacheIceberg #Iceberg #AmazonAthena #DataStreaming #DataLake #DataWarehouse #ACIDTransactions #KafkaStreams #Confluent #Tableflow #ConfluentTableflow #KasunIndrasiri

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nicest man on Earth</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-tGlrDmWk9w</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-tGlrDmWk9w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 02:49:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Great Migrations with Henry Louis Gates, Jr. | Full Episode 3 | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W5LfjimV6vM</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/W5LfjimV6vM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 02:00:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Official website: https://to.pbs.org/4hthArc | #GreatMigrationsPBS
Episode 3 of Great Migrations reflects on how the 1970s marked a turning point in American history. For the first time in 60 years, more Black people were moving to the South than leaving it. Driven by mass movements and economic change, the reverse migration shows how Black Americans’ never-ending search for freedom and opportunity continues to shape the country today.

Great Migrations: A People on the Move | Episode 3 | One Way Ticket Back

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Explore our shared histories with Professor Henry Louis Gates, Jr. through iconic series like Making Black America, Finding Your Roots, and The Black Church: https://pbs.org/professorgates

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS App: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

#history #blackhistory #americanhistory 

Great Migrations: A People on the Move explores the transformative impact of Black migration on American culture and society. From the waves of Black Americans to the North—and back South—over the last century to the growing number of immigrants from Africa and the Caribbean today, the film shows how movement is a defining feature of the Black experience.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Adolf Hitler And The Women Who Loved Him</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=llKuKjGQQUo</link><author>Timeline - World History Documentaries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/llKuKjGQQUo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 22:00:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC88lvyJe7aHZmcvzvubDFRg">Timeline - World History Documentaries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Hitler attracted fanatical devotion from all across German society, including women. However, for some this fanaticism would go even further, becoming an infatuation with one of history's greatest monsters. Discover the toxic relationships Hitler had with women and the role they played in the Third Reich. 

Discover the past on History Hit with ad-free exclusive podcasts and documentaries released weekly presented by world renowned historians Dan Snow, Suzannah Lipscomb, Matt Lewis and more. Get 50% off your first 3 months with code 'TIMELINE' 👉 https://historyhit.com/subscribe 

You can find more from us on:

https://www.facebook.com/timelineWH

https://www.tiktok.com/@timelineworldhistory

https://www.instagram.com/timelineWH

This channel is part of the History Hit Network. Any queries, please contact owned-enquiries@littledotstudios.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Answering Questions About Why the Big Bang Happened, The Shape of the Universe &amp; More</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QEoL0PNaIK4</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/QEoL0PNaIK4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:23:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Could slowing time increase mass? Do particles ever collide or do they just get really really close? Did anything go “bang” during the Big Bang? Neil deGrasse Tyson, co-host Paul Mecurio, and astrophysicist Charles Liu tackle these cosmic questions and more!

Shouldn’t the vacuum of space cause interstellar gas clouds to disperse evenly? We break down how diffusion works and how different forces come together to keep gas clouds intact. What’s in these clouds, and why does some gas get left behind during star formation? Next, we confront the Big Bang itself: what exactly went “bang”? We dive into the misconceptions surrounding the term and its origins with Fred Hoyle. 

What can we learn from gravitational waves beyond just detecting them? We explore the structure of spacetime and the speed of gravity. How do gravitational waves offer a deeper understanding of the universe’s invisible framework? Could slowing down time increase mass? We discuss the manipulation of time and the nature of scientific inquiry. 

As the discussion turns to cosmic collisions, we explore how galaxies interact without stars ever touching. Do particles ever collide or do they just get really really close? What forces govern these interactions, and how do fields and forces influence the behavior of matter? Charles reveals the almost magical dynamics of gravitational and electromagnetic forces, while Neil ties it back to Newton and Einstein.

Finally, we look back in time to the earliest generations of stars. How do we study stars that existed billions of years ago, and what did these stellar giants sacrifice to forge the elements of life? Charles delivers a heartfelt tribute to these cosmic ancestors, reminding us how the light of the past illuminates our understanding of the universe today.

Timestamps:
00:00 - Introduction: Charles Liu
02:15 - Why Don’t Gas Clouds Disperse? 
10:01 - What Went “Bang”?
22:56 - What Will We Learn From Gravitational Waves? 
31:15 - Do Particles Ever Touch? 
39:55 - Observing Early Generation Stars
46:28 - Could Slowing Time Make You More Massive? 
49:57 - Closing

Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The F-14s Swing Wing Explained</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7ogwLyAkNBU</link><author>Real Engineering</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7ogwLyAkNBU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 18:55:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCR1IuLEqb6UEA_zQ81kwXfg">Real Engineering</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Are Virgin Islands Schools Still in Crisis Years After the Hurricanes? | PBS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eeWT96Vm0DE</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eeWT96Vm0DE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Examine the state of public schools in the U.S. Virgin Islands 7 years after back-to-back Category 5 Hurricanes Maria and Irma made landfall. Through interviews with local officials, educators, and students, the film outlines the daily challenges and crumbling infrastructure that students and educators face while billions of dollars in federal aid to rebuild remains out of reach.

'HOMEGROWN: A Part Of/Apart From' is a collection of short films from the U.S. territories and Hawaiʻi exploring issues of cultural identity, sovereignty, and agency, as residents and members of the diaspora grapple with what it means to be “a part of and apart from” the mainland U.S.

What The Storms Taught Us | HOMEGROWN

This program is made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Subscribe to the PBS channel for more clips:  https://www.youtube.com/PBS/

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS App: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

FOLLOW US:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/PBS/
X: https://twitter.com/PBS/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/PBS/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@pbs
Threads: https://www.threads.net/@pbs

#usvirginislands #hurricanemaria #hurricaneirma #publicschool #shortdocumentary]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Did the Catholic Church in Germany hide abusers abroad? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K3L7FVaKjMk</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/K3L7FVaKjMk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:00:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Priests accused of sexual abuse in Germany went to work overseas as missionaries. Did the Catholic Church help them? A research team spent months investigating.

After two teenagers accused Catholic priest Dieter Scholz of abuse in 1963, he disappeared overseas. He went to work in Bolivia as a missionary with the approval of his archdiocese. After his return to Germany, he went on to abuse many others. Even though church authorities were aware of the accusations against him, he was allowed to continue in his post. Priest Josef Zottmann was also able to vanish abroad. In his case, he was trying to escape a warrant for his arrest. Five school girls had reported him to the police for sexual abuse in 1969. The diocese of Eichstätt continued to finance Zottmann abroad by concealing it as a "mission donation.” High-ranking church officials in Germany and Brazil were informed about the police investigation, but they did not cooperate with the authorities. Zottmann returned to Germany in the 1980s after the crimes reached their statute of limitations.

Lawyer Bettina Janssen has also come across other cases that match this profile. The Catholic Church, including the German Bishops’ Conference, has commissioned her to look through their files. She concluded that: "People found diverse ways of keeping priests under cover and concealing their ties to a diocese, of sweeping incidents under the rug, and of providing financial support.” Janssen regards such practices as "a form of obstruction of justice”. No consideration at all was given to the victims. 

So did the Catholic Church consciously hide perpetrators of abuse abroad? A documentary team went looking for answers in Germany and South America.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #catholic #church #germany #southamerica 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How A Chinese Villager Shook Silicon Valley [DeepSeek Founder]</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hd1-CKDyHXE</link><author>ColdFusion</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hd1-CKDyHXE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 16:34:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC4QZ_LsYcvcq7qOsOhpAX4A">ColdFusion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://ground.news/coldfusion to stay fully informed on every side of every story.

Liang Wenfeng, you may not know his name, but you know his company: DeepSeek. In recent weeks it's sent shockwaves around the world. But who is it's mysterious founder? And what is his philosophy? In this episode we find out.

ColdFusion Podcast: 

https://www.youtube.com/@ThroughTheWeb 

Watch or listen to ColdFusion on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/1YEwCKoRz8fEDqheXB6UJ1


ColdFusion Music: 

https://www.youtube.com/@ColdFusionmusic
http://burnwater.bandcamp.com   

Get my book: 

http://bit.ly/NewThinkingbook 

ColdFusion Socials: 

https://discord.gg/coldfusion
https://facebook.com/ColdFusionTV 
https://twitter.com/ColdFusion_TV 
https://instagram.com/coldfusiontv

Created by: Dagogo Altraide
Producers: Tawsif Akkas, Dagogo Altraide]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The medieval legend of Tristan and Isolde - Iseult Gillespie</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kgifhh4pQ10</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Kgifhh4pQ10?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dig into the tragic myth of Tristan and Princess Isolde, and how they fall in love despite her being promised to another.

--

After witnessing a bird carrying a single golden hair, King Mark of Cornwall declared his future bride must have equally radiant locks. The only royal matching this description was Princess Isolde of Ireland. So the king sent Tristan, his bravest knight, to extend an olive branch to the royal family and deliver his proposal of marriage. Iseult Gillespie shares the tale of Tristan and Isolde.

Lesson by Iseult Gillespie, directed by Ciara Nolan, Paper Panther.

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-tragic-romance-of-tristan-and-isolde-iseult-gillespie
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-tragic-romance-of-tristan-and-isolde-iseult-gillespie/digdeeper

Animator's website: https://www.paperpanther.ie
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Francisco Amaya, Daisuke Goto, Matt Switzler, Peng, Tzu-Hsiang, Bethany Connor, Jeremy Shimanek, Mark Byers, Avinash Amarnath, Xuebicoco, Rayo, Po Foon Kwong, Boffin, Jesse Jurman, Scott Markley, Elija Peterson, Ovidiu Mrd, paul g mohney, Steven Razey, Nathan Giusti, Helen Lee, Anthony Benedict, Karthik Balsubramanian, Annastasshia Ames, Amy Lopez, Vinh-Thuy Nguyen, Liz Candee, Ugur Doga Sezgin, Karmi Nguyen, John C. Vesey, Yelena Baykova, Nick Johnson, Carlos H. Costa, Jennifer Kurkoski, Ryan B Harvey, Akinola Emmanuel, Jose Arcadio Valdes Franco, Sebastiaan Vleugels, Karl Laius, JY Kang, Abhishek Goel, Heidi Stolt, Nicole Sund, Karlee Finch, Mario Mejia, Denise A Pitts, Doug Henry, Keven Webb, Mihai Sandu, Deepak Iyer, and Javid Gozalov.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Mountains Make Evolution Weird</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C6koLzdSves</link><author>PBS Eons</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/C6koLzdSves?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 15:00:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzR-rom72PHN9Zg7RML9EbA">PBS Eons</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Mountains have a unique effect on diversity, messing with our understanding of animals through time, and pretty much just making evolution weird. And they would eventually reveal something even stranger about a group of mammals even closer to home: primates.

*****
PBS Member Stations rely on viewers like you. To support your local station, go to http://to.pbs.org/DonateEons
*****

Eons is a production of Complexly for PBS Digital Studios.

Super special thanks to the following Patreon patrons for helping make Eons possible:
Ruth Orr, Randall George, Morgan, Kevin Lacson, Marco Narajos, Ian Leavitt, Collin Dutrow, Pope John XII, Aaditya Mehta, AllPizzasArePersonal, John H. Austin, Jr., Alex Hackman, Stephen Patterson, Gizmo, Karen Farrell, Jason Rostoker, Jonathan Rust, Mary Tevington, Bart & Elke van Iersel - De Jong, Irene Wood, Mark Talbott-Williams, Nomi Alchin, Hillary Ryde-Collins, Duane Westhoff, Yu Mei, Albert Folsom, Dan Caffee, Nick Ryhajlo, Jeff Graham

If you'd like to support the channel, head over to http://patreon.com/eons and pledge for some cool rewards!

Want to follow Eons elsewhere on the internet?
Facebook - https://www.facebook.com/eonsshow
Twitter - https://twitter.com/eonsshow
Instagram - https://www.instagram.com/eonsshow/
#Eons #primates 

References: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nAgxOWJgLyYj5NRhWUPjDMfOKcKcH6e1iNHt2LiQPFM/edit?usp=sharing]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How artificial light affects animals | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hYYw87lpn-A</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hYYw87lpn-A?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The use of artificial light at night has been around for far longer than you would think, dating back to the discovery of fire.  

Since then, humans have made use of different kinds of torches to navigate the world at night. From the Egyptians to the Romans, to the Chinese, oil lamps were common in the cities of ancient civilizations. The real boom, however, came with the discovery of electricity, which eventually led to the global grid of artificial lighting we have today. 

But most of life on Earth has evolved to rely only on the light of the moon and the stars at night. Anything brighter than that creates an imbalance that can have deadly consequences. And this isn’t only true for nocturnal creatures. We are also affected by exposure to artificial light and can develop serious conditions because of it, like sleep disorders, diabetes and even cancer. 

Watch the documentary on our channel.  

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #light #lightpollution #insects 
______

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>From XP to TCR &amp; Limbo • Kent Beck &amp; Daniel Terhorst-North • GOTO 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48g7CRlMUD8</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/48g7CRlMUD8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for GOTO Unscripted. #GOTOcon #GOTOunscripted
https://gotopia.tech

Read the full transcription of this interview here:
https://gotopia.tech/articles/355

Kent Beck - Software Engineer & Creator of Extreme Programming @KentLBeck 
Daniel Terhorst-North - Originator of Behavior Driven Development (BDD) & Principal at Dan North & Associates @daniel-terhorst-north 

RESOURCES
Kent
https://bsky.app/profile/kentbeck.bsky.social
https://www.kentbeck.com
https://github.com/KentBeck
https://twitter.com/KentBeck
https://www.linkedin.com/in/kentbeck

Daniel
https://bsky.app/profile/tastapod.com
https://twitter.com/tastapod
https://linkedin.com/in/danielterhorstnorth
https://github.com/tastapod
https://mastodon.social/@tastapod
http://dannorth.net/blog

Links
https://youtu.be/tgaKAF_eiOg
https://youtu.be/k9lwn-RqEsE
https://youtu.be/Saaz6D1azlU
https://youtu.be/lOcXdXRxFgA
https://youtu.be/klqo1oPdbpM
https://youtu.be/ShAzlhS_TCg
https://youtu.be/86-Dy5U2p5Y
https://youtu.be/yuEbZYKgZas
https://youtu.be/-4Ybn0Cz2oU
https://youtu.be/XShcmCBK93E

DESCRIPTION
Kent Beck and Daniel Terhorst-North reflect on the evolution of Extreme Programming (XP) and its lasting impact on agile software development. They explore the importance of short feedback loops, iterative learning, and adaptability in different phases of product development, as outlined in Beck’s 3X model (Exploration, Expansion, Extraction).

Kent introduces radical techniques like Test && Commit || Revert (TCR) and Limbo, which challenge traditional coding and collaboration practices by emphasizing tiny, safe iterations. The conversation ties in psychological safety, a key factor in high-performing teams, as outlined by Amy C. Edmondson.

Kent envisions a future where software development scales in real-time, pushing teams to embrace faster experimentation, responsibility, and continuous learning in a rapidly evolving tech landscape. [...]

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
00:53 Extreme Programming (XP)
03:09 The power of feedback & Continuous Delivery
07:44 Evolution of XP: From practices to people
11:39 3X Model: Managing risk through software evolution
25:02 TCR, Limbo & the future of software development
33:28 The importance of psychological safety for high-performing teams
39:32 Outro

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Kent Beck • Tidy First? • https://amzn.to/4gscjjK
Kent Beck & Cynthia Andres • Extreme Programming Explained • https://amzn.to/3sBASDG
Amy C. Edmondson • The Fearless Organization • https://amzn.to/3Q5QPxu
Amy C. Edmondson • Right Kind of Wrong • https://amzn.to/3CRbiTD
Jez Humble & David Farley • Continuous Delivery • https://amzn.to/452ZRky

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#XP #EmpiricalDesign #ExtremeProgramming #Explore #Expand #Extract #3X #TDD #TCR #Limbo #PsychologicalSafety #Programming #SoftwareEngineering #KentBeck #DanNorth #DanielTerhorstNorth

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is it time to worry about bird flu?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0wGIl2KDJrQ</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0wGIl2KDJrQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A practical guide to your bird flu fears.

In 2021, at the height of the Covid-19 pandemic, avian flu began aggressively circulating in wildlife. Dead and sick birds began showing up on shorelines. Poultry farms were forced to cull millions of animals, often in horrific ways, to help stop the spread. Egg prices skyrocketed. Farmers lost millions of dollars. The problem doesn’t stop with birds; avian flu has also been found in a wide range of mammals. More than 24,000 sea lions in South America have reportedly died from it. Then, on January 6, 2025, the US reported the first human death. It’s an alarming development, but fortunately an outlier. The truth is avian flu still poses little threat to humans. But if we’re not worried now, when should we be? 


Support our work. Become a Vox Member today: http://www.vox.com/memberships

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Sources and further reading:

Resources on Avian flu from the CDC: 
https://www.cdc.gov/bird-flu/situation-summary/index.html
https://www.cdc.gov/bird-flu/avian-timeline/2020s.html

For more from the USDA including a map of where it is on farms:
https://www.aphis.usda.gov/livestock-poultry-disease/avian/avian-influenza/hpai-detections/mammals

For more coverage from Vox:
https://www.vox.com/even-better/370804/bird-flu-h5n1-missouri-human-cows-raw-milk
https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/362527/bird-flu-100-million-chickens-dead-risk-humans
https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/394511/bird-flu-eggs-human-death-prices-government-response
https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/5/3/24147217/bird-flu-h5n1-chickens-covid-pandemic-cattle-milk-virus-coronavirus
https://www.vox.com/even-better/24145304/bird-flu-h5n1-avian-influenza-pandemic
https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24128700/bird-fludairy-meat-industry-h5n1-cows-milk-eggs-safety
https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24155545/bird-flu-vaccines-h5n1-avian-flu-cows


Subscribe to our channel! http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on Facebook: http://goo.gl/U2g06o
Or Twitter: http://goo.gl/XFrZ5H]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Shermans could BEAT Tiger Tanks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-t7ZIZcQy_0</link><author>Imperial War Museums</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-t7ZIZcQy_0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3uAjWoLZ4bSi6qI9SjALxA">Imperial War Museums</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The original “Black Friday” in LA</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IANPoB-1J9M</link><author>Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IANPoB-1J9M?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:36:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-AQKm7HUNMmxjdS371MSwg">Channel 5 with Andrew Callaghan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Surviving the K-Pg Extinction with...dinosaur meat?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zw1ZPjdNAtc</link><author>PBS Eons</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zw1ZPjdNAtc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 21:30:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzR-rom72PHN9Zg7RML9EbA">PBS Eons</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[*****
PBS Member Stations rely on viewers like you. To support your local station, go to http://to.pbs.org/DonateEons
*****

Eons is a production of Complexly for PBS Digital Studios.

Super special thanks to the following Patreon patrons for helping make Eons possible:
Ruth Orr, Randall George, Morgan, Kevin Lacson, Marco Narajos, Ian Leavitt, Collin Dutrow, Pope John XII, Aaditya Mehta, AllPizzasArePersonal, John H. Austin, Jr., Alex Hackman, Stephen Patterson, Gizmo, Karen Farrell, Jason Rostoker, Jonathan Rust, Mary Tevington, Bart & Elke van Iersel - De Jong, Irene Wood, Mark Talbott-Williams, Nomi Alchin, Hillary Ryde-Collins, Duane Westhoff, Yu Mei, Albert Folsom, Dan Caffee, Nick Ryhajlo, Jeff Graham

If you'd like to support the channel, head over to http://patreon.com/eons and pledge for some cool rewards!

Want to follow Eons elsewhere on the internet?
Facebook - https://www.facebook.com/eonsshow
Twitter - https://twitter.com/eonsshow
Instagram - https://www.instagram.com/eonsshow/
#Eons]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Battlefield Surgery In The Age of Gunpowder</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rf56-4nBWs0</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/rf56-4nBWs0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 18:00:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Historian Dan Snow meets Kevin Goodman to learn how battlefield surgery progresses in the 16th/17th centuries to deal with a deadly new technology - gunpowder

00:35 Intro
01:20 The invention of firearms
03:29 Extracting a musket ball 
06:43 Cauterizing 
07:35 Antiseptic oils
10:32 Gunpowder burns
13:13 Amputation
15:03 Trepanning

Discover the past on History Hit with ad-free exclusive podcasts and documentaries released weekly presented by world renowned historians Dan Snow, Suzannah Lipscomb, Lucy Worsely, Mary Beard and more. Watch, listen and read history wherever you are, whenever you want it. Available on all devices: Apple TV, Amazon Prime Video, Android TV, Samsung Smart TV, Roku, Xbox, Chromecast, and iOs & Android.

We're offering a special discount to History Hit for our subscribers, get 50% off your first 3 months with code YOUTUBE: https://www.historyhit.com/subscription/?utm_source=youtube&utm_medium=description&utm_campaign=YouTube2024

#historyhit #battlefieldsurgery #historyofmedicine]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>92-year-old describes her morning walk 🐿️ #JoyRidePBS #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cFMv_UH6fcg</link><author>PBS</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cFMv_UH6fcg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 17:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgyeJxD05YnoDquRMNBfBqw">PBS</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Brigitta Bexelius, 92, starts her days at Wood Glen Hall in Santa Barbara with a walk, where she gets to enjoy nature. She meets with John who will pilot her trishaw ride.

Made possible by viewers like you. Support your local PBS station: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Enjoy full episodes of your favorite PBS shows anytime, anywhere with the free PBS App: https://to.pbs.org/2QbtzhR

#elderlycare #seniorcitizens #inspirational

JOYRIDE is a short-form interview series that pairs younger generations with older adults as they explore the world together on trishaw bikes. The show is inspired by the global non-profit, Cycling Without Age, which takes older adults on trishaw outings to feel the wind in their hair. From the Santa Barbara coastline to Barcelona beaches, each episode unlocks the lived experiences of today’s older generation, who have become increasingly removed from the flow of daily life. This series will create new conditions for generations to collide, share experiences, and be inspired by a sense of place and nostalgia.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Young and radical - Why right-wing populism is on the rise | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CSl4HIONvjc</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CSl4HIONvjc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 17:00:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[There has recently been a trend in elections in Europe: young voters are turning to right-wing populist and right-wing extremist parties. Why is this happening?

In the Netherlands researchers say it was 18-34 year olds who helped the right-wing populist Geert Wilders to victory in the parliamentary elections. In Italy too, the Brothers of Italy, a party that is considered post-fascist, is in power. In Germany, there will be an early federal election at the end of February. According to surveys, the AfD, parts of which have been classified as right-wing extremist, has a good chance of significantly increasing its share of the vote. The renowned youth researcher Prof. Klaus Hurrelmann says that the success of such parties is also due to their aggressive advertising towards young voters in the digital sphere. In their report, Alexandra von Nahmen and Finlay Duncan examine the question of what else makes radical parties so attractive to young people that they end up voting for them.

00:00 Introduction
00:49 Rome – Why are young people fans of fascism?
02:50 Rome – At the HQ of Forza Nouva
04:00 An expert’s take - Prof Hurrelmann
04:42 Netherlands – A dinner party with right-populists
07:00 Netherlands – How right-wing populists use social media
08:41 Germany – Protests against Alternative of Germany
09:20 Germany – Inside an AfD rally
10:47 Simple answers to complex issues?

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #reporter #politics #elections #europe 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/dwdochindi
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Was Interstellar WRONG? Kip Thorne ANSWERS!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QAY0B1ked54</link><author>StarTalk</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/QAY0B1ked54?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqoAEDirJPjEUFcF2FklnBA">StarTalk</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out our second channel, @StarTalkPlus

Get the NEW StarTalk book, 'To Infinity and Beyond: A Journey of Cosmic Discovery' on Amazon: https://amzn.to/3PL0NFn

Support us on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/startalkradio

FOLLOW or SUBSCRIBE to StarTalk:
Twitter: http://twitter.com/startalkradio
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/StarTalk
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/startalk

About StarTalk: 
Science meets pop culture on StarTalk! Astrophysicist & Hayden Planetarium director Neil deGrasse Tyson, his comic co-hosts, guest celebrities & scientists discuss astronomy, physics, and everything else about life in the universe. Keep Looking Up!

#StarTalk #NeildeGrasseTyson]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>