<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>World News</title><link>https://securenza.github.io/SecurityFeed/</link><description></description><item><title>US deports alleged Venezuelan gang members to El Salvador | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vixkLiOKEgE</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vixkLiOKEgE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 20:37:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[More than 200 alleged Venezuelan gang members were deported from the US to El Salvador’s mega-prison after Donald Trump invoked the 1798 Alien Enemies Act to rapidly deport them bypassing immigration courts.
#News #Reuters #Newsfeed #elsalvador #terrorism #venezuela #unitedstates 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/3DySnO5

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Brick Lane, London</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1jcszfz/brick_lane_london/</link><author>/u/novitasdigital</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 19:05:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>French politician says US should give back Statue of Liberty</title><link>https://www.lemonde.fr/en/politics/article/2025/03/16/french-mep-says-us-should-give-back-statue-of-liberty_6739217_5.html</link><author>/u/pierrepaul</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 18:19:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[France should take back the Statue of Liberty because the US no longer represents the values that led France to offer the statue, a French member of the European Parliament said Sunday, March 16. "Give us back the Statue of Liberty," centre-left politician Raphaël Glucksmann said at a convention of his Place Publique center-left movement."We're going to say to the Americans who have chosen to side with the tyrants, to the Americans who fired researchers for demanding scientific freedom: 'Give us back the Statue of Liberty,'" he told cheering supporters. "We gave it to you as a gift, but apparently you despise it. So it will be just fine here at home," he added.The Statue of Liberty was unveiled in New York City's harbour on October 28, 1886, for the centennial of the American Declaration of Independence as a gift from the French people to America. It was designed by Frenchman Auguste Bartholdi. Paris does have a far smaller copy of the statue on a small island on the Seine in Paris.Glucksmann, a staunch defender of Ukraine, has strongly criticized President Donald Trump's radical change of US policy on the war. He also took aim at Trump's cuts to US research institutions, which have already prompted a French government initiative to attract some of them to work in France."The second thing we're going to say to the Americans is: 'If you want to fire your best researchers, if you want to fire all the people who, through their freedom and their sense of innovation, their taste for doubt and research, have made your country the world's leading power, then we're going to welcome them,'" continued Glucksmann.Since Trump returned to the White House in January, his government has cut federal research funding and sought to dismiss hundreds of federal workers working on health and climate research.Glucksmann also criticized far-right leaders in France, accusing them of being a "fan club" for Trump and billionaire Elon Musk, who is spearheading the president's efforts to cut spending.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ecuadorians worry river oil spill will affect their health and crops | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p3lpjAFPx1Q</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/p3lpjAFPx1Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 18:13:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Residents fear an oil spill in Ecuador’s Viche River will affect their health and crops. The spill caused by a damaged pipeline heavily polluted the river.
#News #Reuters #Newsfeed #ecuador #oilspill 

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>SpaceX capsule arrives at ISS to relieve stranded crew | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u1DOxQ3o-DQ</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/u1DOxQ3o-DQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:05:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A SpaceX capsule delivered four astronauts to the International Space Station in a NASA crew-swap mission that will allow Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams to Earth after nine months.
#News #Reuters #Newsfeed #spacex #internationalspacestation #nasa 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/3FILpGC

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nightclub fire in North Macedonia leaves dozens dead | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SU_i0oFE5kk</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SU_i0oFE5kk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 15:58:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dozens of people were killed and more than 100 injured when a fire broke out in a nightclub in the North Macedonian town of Kočani, Interior Minister Pance Toskovski said.
#News #Reuters #Newsfeed #macedonia 

Read the story here: https://reut.rs/43NeDhA

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>London</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1jco47i/london/</link><author>/u/wrapityup</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 15:35:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Capital is flowing from the U.S. to Europe</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1jcnpwl/capital_is_flowing_from_the_us_to_europe/</link><author>/u/PjeterPannos</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 15:17:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>#Trump takes aim at Biden&apos;s Chips and Science Act #tech</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pE2EtATV9E0</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pE2EtATV9E0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 15:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[President Trump called for ending a bipartisan $52 billion semiconductor subsidy program that’s spurred more than $400 billion in investments from companies like TSMC, Intel and Samsung.
Kailey Leinz explains https://trib.al/y15Pik7]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Unity protects us</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1jcn126/unity_protects_us/</link><author>/u/PjeterPannos</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Macron to EU colleagues: Stop buying American, buy European</title><link>https://www.politico.eu/article/macron-to-eu-colleagues-stop-buying-american-buy-european/</link><author>/u/Deedogg11</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 13:41:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The two also agreed “to continue working towards restoring communication between the United States and Russia,” Washington says.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Macron to EU colleagues: Stop buying American, buy European</title><link>https://www.politico.eu/article/macron-to-eu-colleagues-stop-buying-american-buy-european/</link><author>/u/Deedogg11</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 13:37:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The two also agreed “to continue working towards restoring communication between the United States and Russia,” Washington says.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>50% of Moscow’s fuel supply at risk after Ukrainian drone strike on its largest oil refinery</title><link>https://euromaidanpress.com/2025/03/16/frontline-report-50-of-moscows-fuel-supply-at-risk-after-ukrainian-drone-strike-on-its-largest-oil-refinery/</link><author>/u/eaglemaxie</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 13:31:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Today, there are a lot of interesting updates from the Russian Federation.Ukrainian drones penetrated deep into Russian territory, and explosions lit up the skies over Moscow and several key cities. While strikes on oil refineries and military targets were significant, one attack stood out—the hit on the Druzhba pipeline—creating international ripple effects beyond Russia’s borders as exports suddenly dropped.As you remember from a previous report, Ukrainians destroyed a significant number of Russian air defenses in Crimea, along the front line, and deep in the rear while also threatening to strike the Kerch Strait Bridge again. This forced Russia to relocate air defense systems to cover newly exposed weak spots. However, this played into Ukraine’s strategy, as the large-scale redeployments left several key targets vulnerable.This allowed Ukrainians to deploy hundreds of drones to penetrate Russia’s air defense grid, which was spread thin by the countless destroyed systems and subsequent relocations. As a result, Ukrainian drones reached as far as Moscow, with the first confirmed strike hitting the Oka-Center oil depot in the town of Serpukhov in Moscow Oblast, inflicting significant damage during the day.What followed was Russia’s most restless night yet. Russian reports state that over 337 Ukrainian drones struck Moscow, Kursk, Belgorod, Oryol, Lipetsk, Bryansk, and Ryazan in the largest drone strike to date. Strikes hit oil refineries in the Moscow area, including the city’s largest refinery, which supplies up to 50% of its diesel and gasoline consumption.Ukraine targets Russian oil: Druzhba pipeline and refineries disruptedExplosions near the Ryazan military airfield put all Russian airports on high alert, undermining the Russian Air Force’s rapid response capabilities. Additionally, a control station for the Druzhba pipeline in Oryol was hit, halting Russian oil exports to Central Europe, particularly Hungary.The Druzhba pipeline—one of the world’s largest, with a capacity of 2 million barrels per day—is a critical conduit for Russian oil exports to Central European refineries. Hungary imports most of its crude oil and gas via the Druzhba pipeline, with over 40% of Hungarian gas being Russian, making the strike on the control station particularly devastating for them. As a result, the Hungarian Foreign Minister, Péter Szijjártó, called it an attack on their sovereignty.When the oil and gas supply stopped, the halt of operations of the Druzhba pipeline meant that Hungary would have to import much more expensive oil and gas from allies like the USA and Norway. The cancellation of Russian oil and gas exports to Hungary could jeopardize Russia’s hold on the Hungarian energy sector, as the country would have to increase its overall reliance on Europe for its energy needs.Besides gas, the second-largest Hungarian energy source is nuclear power from its only nuclear power plant in Paks. This nuclear power plant depends on Russia’s nuclear fuel, uranium rods, and Russian engineers and expertise, consolidating Russia’s monopoly on the Hungarian energy sector. Through this, Russia maintains strict control over Hungary, as only Russian specialists and companies can currently maintain the reactors and supply critical equipment and fuel for their maintenance. Since nuclear power generates over a third of the country’s electricity, Hungary remains reliant on Russia to sustain its energy infrastructure.The Hungarian Foreign Minister stated that he had discussed the situation with the Deputy Russian Energy Minister, who assured him that pipeline control station repairs were underway and supplies would resume soon.Ukraine’s strategy: escalation or ceasefire leverage?If Russia does not accept a ceasefire—at least in the air—Ukraine can exert much more pressure on Russia’s energy hold on Hungary by launching follow-up strikes to destroy critical export infrastructure further and delay repairs.Overall, Ukrainian drone strikes on Russian oil refineries and energy infrastructure are escalating. The latest attack hit Moscow’s main refinery, which supplies half the city’s energy needs. Additionally, damage to the Druzhba pipeline control station temporarily halted Russian energy exports to Hungary. Continued strikes could strain Russia’s economy and weaken its geopolitical influence, potentially pushing it toward negotiating a ceasefire—at least in the airspace over Russia and Ukraine., we pair up with the military blogger Reporting from Ukraine to keep you informed about what is happening on the battlefield in the Russo-Ukrainian war.You could close this page. Or you could join our community and help us produce more materials like this. 

We keep our reporting open and accessible to everyone because we believe in the power of free information. This is why our small, cost-effective team depends on the support of readers like you to bring deliver timely news, quality analysis, and on-the-ground reports about Russia's war against Ukraine and Ukraine's struggle to build a democratic society.

A little bit goes a long way: for as little as the cost of one cup of coffee a month, you can help build bridges between Ukraine and the rest of the world, plus become a co-creator and vote for topics we should cover next. or see other ways to Become a Patron!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Russia has lost 100,000 military personnel in 2025, says Ukraine&apos;s commander-in-chief</title><link>https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2025/03/16/7503132/</link><author>/u/eaglemaxie</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 13:22:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Oleksandr Syrskyi, Commander-in-Chief of the Armed Forces of Ukraine, has reported that the total losses of the Russians in military personnel have exceeded 100,000 since the beginning of 2025. Syrskyi on Facebook "Thanks to the coordinated and professional work of our defenders, the total losses of the occupiers in personnel have surpassed 100,000 since the beginning of this year." Syrskyi said that Ukraine’s defence forces continue to destroy Russian troops along the entire line of contact.Support Ukrainska Pravda on]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why some investors want to do business with #Russia #politics #podcast</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1wxj3YsKngw</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1wxj3YsKngw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On this episode of the Big Take podcast, @sarahsholder and @tonyhalpin discuss why some investors are eager to start doing business with Russia again and what that could mean for Russia and Ukraine’s economies https://trib.al/ABS5OBn]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Guess who claims all the credits</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1jckiur/guess_who_claims_all_the_credits/</link><author>/u/A_Lazko</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 12:38:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The solution is a federal Europe! Federalists in Rome</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1jck95y/the_solution_is_a_federal_europe_federalists_in/</link><author>/u/EUstrongerthanUS</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 12:21:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Apres Netflix: Reed Hastings&apos; Second Act at Powder</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eJZ6XY7usaY</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eJZ6XY7usaY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Reed Hastings, co-founder and former CEO of Netflix, is picking up speed — on the slopes. At nearly 10,000 feet above sea level, Reed is hard at work on a new project: creating a private ski community at Powder Mountain, Utah. We sit down with the former CEO to talk about his career, legacy and the lessons he is applying to his new venture.
--------
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
 
Get more of Wall Street Week here:
https://www.bloomberg.com/btv/series/wall-street-week
 
Watch the show live on Fridays at 6 p.m. New York time, then again on Saturdays at 10 a.m. and Sundays at 9 a.m.
We're on Bloomberg Television, Radio, the Terminal or here on YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iEpJwprxDdk
 
Listen to the Wall Street Week podcast on Spotify or Apple: https://www.bloomberg.com/podcasts/series/wall-street-week
 
Sign up for the newsletter here:
https://www.bloomberg.com/account/newsletters/wall-street-week?source=wswintro
 
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>‘We must stop Putin’: Zelensky says Russians launched 1,020 attack drones, 1,360 guided aerial bombs this week</title><link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/russians-launched-over-1-020-attack-drones-1-360-guided-aerial-bombs-zelensky-says-we-must-stop-putin-together/amp-11742121335892.html</link><author>/u/sweatycat</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 11:46:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[“Hundreds of attacks on our cities and communities this week: Chernihiv, Kherson, Donetsk, Kharkiv, Dnipro, Odesa, Poltava, Kyiv, Mykolaiv, Zaporizhzhia, and Sumy regions. The Russians launched over 1,020 attack drones, nearly 1,360 guided aerial bombs, and more than 10 missiles of various types,” said Zelensky in a post on X.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Not for Russia to decide on peacekeepers in Ukraine, Macron says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/not-russia-decide-peacekeepers-ukraine-macron-says-2025-03-16/</link><author>/u/sweatycat</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 11:03:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What the #Trump trade war means for the economy and consumer #politics #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LY_Hm1-34nM</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LY_Hm1-34nM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[After weeks of uncertainty, Trump's 25% tariffs on steel and aluminum imports are here.
On this episode of the Big Take DC podcast, we discuss the fallout — and what this all means for the economy and the US consumer. Listen to the full episode wherever you get your podcasts https://trib.al/evP6SmW]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What’s at Stake as Trump Targets the Education Department</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CDuVENKMsQA</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CDuVENKMsQA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Department of Education is facing a reckoning under President Trump. Akayla Gardner explains what's at stake.
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Finland turns down US request for eggs | Yle News</title><link>https://yle.fi/a/74-20149786</link><author>/u/redditforcedmesignup</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hungarian Opposition Rallies in Massive Protest Against Orbán’s Rule</title><link>https://www.kyivpost.com/post/48992</link><author>/u/Yveliad</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 10:01:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Massive crowds rallied in Budapest on Saturday as Hungarian opposition activists came out in force to call for an end to Prime Minister Viktor Orbán’s 15-year rule.Around 50,000 protesters descended on the capital on Hungary’s national day to support Peter Magyar, a former government insider turned leader of the anti-Orbán camp.Magyar told his supporters the “time has come” for his Tisza party, which is leading the prime minister’s Fidesz party in most opinion polls ahead of elections in 2026, Reuters reported.Speaking to TVP World during the demonstration, Tisza’s deputy chair Zoltán Tarr said that his movement faced significant operational challenges under the current government, which has been accused of undermining press freedom and curbing democracy.“The biggest challenge is that Orbán’s government is doing everything in its power to somehow control and limit our activities,” Tarr claimed.“They also go after people who openly say that they want change and say that they would like to belong to the Tisza movement. That is one of the biggest challenges, because obviously everyone is worried about his or her own existence, and this government is very particular in going after people one by one, singling them out.”He added that state “propaganda” was spreading falsehoods about the opposition.“They constantly make up stories which are not true but which are able to lead people in a different direction, [they] mislead them by spreading lies about us,” he said.Magyar and his party are set to launch a popular survey on 12 key economic and political issues to give citizens a voice in the movement’s political platform in the run-up to next year’s vote.The 43-year-old MEP has also vowed to make Hungary part of a strong Europe, in contrast to Orbán’s Euroscepticism, which has seen him regularly clashing with politicians in Brussels and other European capitals.Speaking at a separate rally on Saturday, the 61-year-old Orbán said it was time to eliminate what he called a “shadow army” of NGOs, journalists, judges and politicians receiving payments from abroad.He has already announced plans to crack down on organizations funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) – which is now being dismantled by Trump – and Budapest-born billionaire George Soros, a supporter of liberal causes.This week Orbán’s Fidesz party submitted constitutional changes that would permit the expulsion of dual citizens deemed to pose a threat to Hungary’s sovereignty.While the Tisza movement may be riding high in recent polls, unseating Orbán would be a significant achievement. In the last parliamentary elections in 2022, a united front of anti-Fidesz candidates fell well short of Orbán’s party, which won over half of the popular vote.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Finland turns down US request for eggs</title><link>https://yle.fi/a/74-20149786</link><author>/u/Beo1217</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 09:07:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A work by Ben Jennings for The i Paper</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/1jcgv2h/a_work_by_ben_jennings_for_the_i_paper/</link><author>/u/CorleoneBaloney</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 08:19:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trump&apos;s 200% Tariff on EU Wine, Alcohol: What Happens If It Goes Ahead?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XlYX0VonjOQ</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XlYX0VonjOQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 08:00:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[US President Donald Trump's threat to impose 200% tariffs on EU alcohol imports would send some companies out of business, according to Ignacio Sanchez Recarte, Secretary General of the Comité Européen des Entreprises Vins, CEEV, which represents European wine companies.  He spoke with Tom Mackenzie on "Daybreak Europe" on Bloomberg TV on March 14 on the potential impact to the industry as well as his hopes to de-prioritize the US market.
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Africa&apos;s Vast Mineral Wealth: What You Need to Know</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fcooh1xPXrc</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Fcooh1xPXrc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 06:00:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Africa sits on one of broadest and most diverse array of mineral wealth in anywhere in the world. Bloomberg's Samuel Etienne breaks down exactly why the continent is a major destination for miners.
Watch the full episode of Bloomberg Next Africa: https://youtu.be/TTw0Elsvksc
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>EU&apos;s Kallas says there are no winners in trade wars #china #politics</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VvYUvXjwzuA</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/VvYUvXjwzuA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[European Commission Vice President Kaja Kallas discusses US President Donald Trump's tariff policy as 25% tariffs on steel and aluminum imports from every country in the world went into effect on Wednesday morning https://trib.al/ye9YVFy]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>America strikes Houthis; Starmer convenes “coalition of the willing”, and more</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/theeconomistmorningbriefing/episodes/america-strikes-houthis-starmer-convenes-coalition-of-the-wi</link><author></author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/theeconomistmorningbriefing/e/67d6431234deae95a5ce4ee5/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJpbiI6Imh0dHBzOi8vczMuYW1hem9uYXdzLmNvbS9hc3NldHMucGlwcGEuaW8vc2hvd3MvNjJlMjg2YTkzNGQ0ZDkwNmUzODc0MjRiLzE3NDIwOTUwNjY2MTYtNWNlNTU4MzgtNzQzMi00ZTVhLTllNmMtODVhOTVhNWNmMzI1LXB1YmxpY0ludHJvLm1wMyIsIm91dCI6Imh0dHBzOi8vczMuYW1hem9uYXdzLmNvbS9hc3NldHMucGlwcGEuaW8vc2hvd3MvNjJlMjg2YTkzNGQ0ZDkwNmUzODc0MjRiLzE3NDIwOTUwNzI2ODYtY2IxMDdkZWItNzcxNS00ZWE1LTk4NjktZjJkNWNkMzNmMWU1LXB1YmxpY091dHJvLm1wMyIsInN0YXR1cyI6InB1YmxpYyJ9&amp;sig=SO7csPpSu2fzm5CeEy_q40ZosXniXY_0wxMvMlYT7rc" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 03:22:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.economist.com/audio/podcasts/the-world-in-brief">News - Daily Brief</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>NASA’s SpaceX Crew-10 Launches Successfully</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ke7mtPZKMHk</link><author>Bloomberg Television</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ke7mtPZKMHk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 03:04:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIALMKvObZNtJ6AmdCLP7Lg">News - Bloomberg </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[NASA and SpaceX Crew-10 Mission to the International Space Station launched successfully.  The crew will be headed to the International Space Station to take over for the two Americans stuck in orbit, who are slated to return home March 19 at the earliest.
--------
More on Bloomberg Television and Markets
 
Like this video? Subscribe and turn on notifications so you don't miss any videos from Bloomberg Markets & Finance: https://tinyurl.com/ysu5b8a9
Visit http://www.bloomberg.com for business news & analysis, up-to-the-minute market data, features, profiles and more.
 
Connect with Bloomberg Television on:
X: https://twitter.com/BloombergTV
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BloombergTelevision
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergtv/
 
Connect with Bloomberg Business on:
X: https://twitter.com/business
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/bloombergbusiness
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/bloombergbusiness/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@bloombergbusiness?lang=en
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/bloomberg/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/company/bloomberg-news/
 
More from Bloomberg:
Bloomberg Radio: https://twitter.com/BloombergRadio

Bloomberg Surveillance: https://twitter.com/bsurveillance
Bloomberg Politics: https://twitter.com/bpolitics
Bloomberg Originals: https://twitter.com/bbgoriginals
 
Watch more on YouTube:
Bloomberg Technology: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergTechnology
Bloomberg Originals: https://www.youtube.com/@business
Bloomberg Quicktake: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergQuicktake
Bloomberg Espanol: https://www.youtube.com/@bloomberg_espanol
Bloomberg Podcasts: https://www.youtube.com/@BloombergPodcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trump limits Kellogg’s role to Ukraine envoy after Russian complaints</title><link>https://www.straitstimes.com/world/europe/trump-limits-kelloggs-role-to-ukraine-envoy-after-russian-complaints</link><author>/u/Silly-avocatoe</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 02:49:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Macron asserts: &apos;If Kyiv invites allies onto its soil, Moscow has no say&apos;</title><link>https://www.bfmtv.com/international/asie/russie/guerre-en-ukraine-moscou-n-a-pas-son-mot-a-dire-si-kiev-demande-a-des-forces-alliees-d-etre-sur-son-territoire-affirme-macron_AD-202503150383.html</link><author>/u/Wonderful-Excuse4922</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:42:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dans un entretien accordé à plusieurs journeaux régionais français, Emmanuel Macron a par ailleurs affirm qu'il faudra, selon lui, des "échanges directs" avec son homologue russe Vladimir Poutine "et entre négociateurs français et russes pour clarifier cet agenda" sur les garanties de sécurité à apporter à l'Ukraine.Emmanuel Macron a affirmé que la Russie n'avait pas à "accepter ou pas" l'envoi en Ukraine de "forces alliées" si Kiev en fait la "demande" pour garantir un éventuel accord de paix, dans un entretien publié samedi 15 mars par plusieurs journaux régionaux français.En revanche, "à partir du moment où on rentrerait dans cette phase de cessez-le-feu" proposée par Washington et Kiev, il faudra selon lui des "échanges directs" avec son homologue russe Vladimir Poutine "et entre négociateurs français et russes pour clarifier cet agenda" sur les garanties de sécurité à apporter à l'Ukraine.Depuis son retour à la Maison-Blanche en janvier, le président américain Donald Trump martèle sa volonté de mettre fin au conflit, trois ans après l'invasion russe de l'Ukraine, et a opéré un rapprochement spectaculaire avec le maître du Kremlin. Après une phase de tensions maximales, Américains et Ukrainiens ont renoué le dialogue cette semaine en proposant une trêve d'un mois, que la Russie n'a pas encore acceptée."C'est un moment de vérité parce que si la Russie ne s'engage pas sincèrement dans la paix", "le président Trump va durcir les sanctions et les représailles et donc on changera totalement de dynamique", a estimé Emmanuel Macron.Selon le chef de l'Etat français, "plusieurs pays européens, et d'ailleurs non européens, ont manifesté leur volonté de se joindre" à un éventuel envoi de troupes en Ukraine pour garantir un futur accord de paix avec la Russie. Il s'agirait de "quelques milliers d'hommes" par Etat, déployés "dans des points-clés, pour faire des programmes d'entraînement" et "montrer notre soutien dans la durée", a-t-il assuré. Jusqu'ici, Moscou s'oppose fermement à un tel déploiement."Les Ukrainiens ne peuvent en aucun cas faire des concessions territoriales et n'avoir aucune garantie de sécurité", a-t-il prévenu.S'agissant du renforcement massif de la défense acté par l'Union européenne la semaine dernière, il a expliqué avoir demandé aux industriels français de l'armement réunis vendredi à l'Elysée de "démarcher les Etats européens qui ont pris l'habitude d'acheter américain"."Ceux qui achètent (des missiles) Patriot, il faut leur proposer le SAM-T nouvelle génération franco-italien; ceux qui achètent du F35, il faut leur proposer du Rafale", a-t-il martelé. Il entend d'ailleurs "produire plus" de ces avions de chasse du groupe Dassault Aviation "plutôt que d'accélérer le programme d'avion du futur".]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trump launches strikes against Yemen&apos;s Houthis | REUTERS</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d89Hy4EjrbY</link><author>Reuters</author><category>news</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/d89Hy4EjrbY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 22:53:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChqUTb7kYRX8-EiaN3XFrSQ">News - Reuters </source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Donald Trump launched military strikes against Yemen's Iran-aligned Houthis over the group's attacks on Red Sea shipping, warning ‘hell will rain down upon you.'

#News #Reuters #Newsfeed #yemen #houthis #donaldtrump #iran 

Read the story here:  https://reut.rs/41TjFGJ

👉  Subscribe: http://smarturl.it/reuterssubscribe

Keep up with the latest news from around the world: https://www.reuters.com/
Follow Reuters on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Twitter: https://twitter.com/Reuters
Follow Reuters on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/reuters/?hl=en]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A river ‘died&apos; overnight in Zambia after an acidic waste spill at a Chinese-owned mine</title><link>https://apnews.com/article/mining-pollution-china-zambia-environment-93ee91d1156471aaf9a7ebd6f51333c1?fbclid=IwY2xjawJC4UNleHRuA2FlbQIxMQABHSYwd6jBPc-9Ud0ih68QPHXuoDjTBNrmdrbkPe0fy6N_USmK-YK8TgyUmw_aem_jM_aBoBLBDU9_TRAxkBalA</link><author>/u/kalahiki808</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 22:41:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - World News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The moment LRAD (owned by the Serbian police) was used during 15 minutes of silence - Belgrade, Serbia</title><link>https://n1info.rs/vesti/video-trenutak-incidenta-upotrebljen-zvucni-top-oruzje-koje-poseduje-bezbednosni-sistem-srbije/</link><author>/u/SkyLunat1c</author><category>news</category><category>reddit</category><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 22:03:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/top/?sort=top&amp;t=day&amp;limit=10">News - Reddit - Europe</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Zvuk koji je prekinuo petnaestominutnu tišinu na današnjem studentskom protestu i izazvao paniku među okupljenima je zvučno oružje ili "zvučni top" koji poseduje bezbednosni sistem Srbije, rekao je za N1 Aleksandar Radić, vojni analitičar.Radić navodi da je u pitanju američko neletalno, agresivno, zvučno oružje koje za cilj ima da onemogući metu, odnosno, da služi za onesposobljavanje.„Najveći problem u večerašnjem događaju je – ko je došao na ideju da se takvo oružje upotrebi? U situaciji kada su svi demonstranti bili mirni, kada se odavala petnaestominutna pošta nastradalima oružje je upotrebljeno. Jedini cilj tog čina je brutalan prikaz sile, dokaz arogancije, a motiv mržnja prema sopstvenom narodu“, navodi za portal N1 Radić.On kaže da „zvučni top“ od pre nekoliko godina poseduje bezbednosni sistem Srbije.Narodni poslanik Zdravko Ponoš, takođe, navodi i da je prema informacijama koje je on dobio u pitanju zvučno oružje.„Ta reakcija okupljenih, da imaju osećaj kao da je nešto prošlo pored njih je posledica upotrebe zvuka, a sa ciljem da se uplaše“, rekao je Ponoš.On je objasnio i da osim što se njime izazvala panika, ta vrsta oružja može da se koristi na više načina.„Upotreba tog oružja može naštetiti i zdravlju, a to što je upotrebljena u vreme dok je odavana pošta nastradalima je potpuni skandal“, naveo je Zdravko Ponoš.]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>