<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Security News</title><link>https://securenza.github.io/SecurityFeed/</link><description></description><item><title>Fake &quot;Security Alert&quot; issues on GitHub use OAuth app to hijack accounts</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/fake-security-alert-issues-on-github-use-oauth-app-to-hijack-accounts/</link><author>Lawrence Abrams</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 18:36:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A widespread phishing campaign has targeted nearly 12,000 GitHub repositories with fake "Security Alert" issues, tricking developers into authorizing a malicious OAuth app that grants attackers full control over their accounts and code. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Malicious Adobe, DocuSign OAuth apps target Microsoft 365 accounts</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/malicious-adobe-docusign-oauth-apps-target-microsoft-365-accounts/</link><author>Bill Toulas</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 14:19:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Cybercriminals are promoting malicious Microsoft OAuth apps that masquerade as Adobe and DocuSign apps to deliver malware and steal Microsoft 365 accounts credentials. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New Akira ransomware decryptor cracks encryptions keys using GPUs</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/gpu-powered-akira-ransomware-decryptor-released-on-github/</link><author>Bill Toulas</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 14:16:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Security researcher Yohanes Nugroho has released a decryptor for the Linux variant of Akira ransomware, which utilizes GPU power to retrieve the decryption key and unlock files for free. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Malicious PyPI Packages Stole Cloud Tokens—Over 14,100 Downloads Before Removal</title><link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/malicious-pypi-packages-stole-cloud.html</link><author>The Hacker News</author><category>security</category><enclosure url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjCKm0W6Smhs8d_aZlimvRWcIqLvORW1VZ14ceCMMgi4kB2tYz_2dxEmBi0by3FAB7IsKgDcM69Of_yBcT-XP0_gbCEYC9QEXTwPTgVrTV-H07kxGA5f5ekvjLUA390B6O111GoIZhPXtXcfT3otnfkataMHrCktMHgrtNj3pXGzbqIn3WhWCXHNIdhDIAl/s1600/supply-chain.png" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 05:55:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://thehackernews.com/">The Hacker News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Cybersecurity researchers have warned of a malicious campaign targeting users of the Python Package Index (PyPI) repository with bogus libraries masquerading as "time" related utilities, but harboring hidden functionality to steal sensitive data such as cloud access tokens.
Software supply chain security firm ReversingLabs said it discovered two sets of packages totaling 20 of them. The packages]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Coinbase phishing email tricks users with fake wallet migration</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/coinbase-phishing-email-tricks-users-with-fake-wallet-migration/</link><author>Lawrence Abrams</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 22:35:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A large-scale Coinbase phishing attack poses as a mandatory wallet migration, tricking recipients into setting up a new wallet with a pre-generated recovery phrase controlled by attackers. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ClickFix: How to Infect Your PC in Three Easy Steps</title><link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/clickfix-how-to-infect-your-pc-in-three-easy-steps/</link><author>BrianKrebs</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 22:15:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://krebsonsecurity.com/">Krebs on Security</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A clever malware deployment scheme first spotted in targeted attacks last year has now gone mainstream. In this scam, dubbed “,” the visitor to a hacked or malicious website is asked to distinguish themselves from bots by pressing a combination of keyboard keys that causes  to download password-stealing malware.ClickFix attacks mimic the “Verify You are a Human” tests that many websites use to separate real visitors from content-scraping bots. This particular scam usually starts with a website popup that looks something like this:This malware attack pretends to be a CAPTCHA intended to separate humans from bots.Clicking the “I’m not a robot” button generates a pop-up message asking the user to take three sequential steps to prove their humanity.Executing this series of keypresses prompts Windows to download password-stealing malware.Step 1 involves simultaneously pressing the keyboard key with the Windows icon and the letter “R,” which opens a Windows “Run” prompt that will execute any specified program that is already installed on the system.Step 2 asks the user to press the “CTRL” key and the letter “V” at the same time, which pastes malicious code from the site’s virtual clipboard.Step 3 — pressing the “Enter” key — causes Windows to download and launch malicious code through “,” a Windows program designed to run Microsoft HTML application files.“This campaign delivers multiple families of commodity malware, including XWorm, Lumma stealer, VenomRAT, AsyncRAT, Danabot, and NetSupport RAT,”  wrote in a blog post on Thursday. “Depending on the specific payload, the specific code launched through mshta.exe varies. Some samples have downloaded PowerShell, JavaScript, and portable executable (PE) content.”According to Microsoft, hospitality workers are being tricked into downloading credential-stealing malware by cybercriminals impersonating . The company said attackers have been sending malicious emails impersonating Booking.com, often referencing negative guest reviews, requests from prospective guests, or online promotion opportunities — all in a bid to convince people to step through one of these ClickFix attacks.In November 2024, KrebsOnSecurity reported that hundreds of hotels that use booking.com had been subject to targeted phishing attacks. Some of those lures worked, and allowed thieves to gain control over booking.com accounts. From there, they sent out phishing messages asking for financial information from people who’d just booked travel through the company’s app.Earlier this month, the security firm warned about ClickFix attacks targeting people working in the healthcare sector. The company said those attacks leveraged malicious code stitched into the widely used physical therapy video site HEP2go that redirected visitors to a ClickFix prompt.An alert (PDF) released in October 2024 by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services warned that the ClickFix attack can take many forms, including fake  error pages and popups that spoof .ClickFix tactic used by malicious websites impersonating Google Chrome, Facebook, PDFSimpli, and reCAPTCHA. Source: Sekoia.The ClickFix attack — and its reliance on mshta.exe — is reminiscent of phishing techniques employed for years that hid exploits inside . Malicious macros became such a common malware threat that Microsoft was forced to start blocking macros by default in Office documents that try to download content from the web.Alas, the email security vendor  has documented plenty of ClickFix attacks via phishing emails that include HTML attachments spoofing Microsoft Office files. When opened, the attachment displays an image of Microsoft Word document with a pop-up error message directing users to click the “Solution” or “How to Fix” button.HTML files containing ClickFix instructions. Examples for attachments named “Report_” (on the left) and “scan_doc_” (on the right). Image: Proofpoint.Organizations that wish to do so can take advantage of Microsoft Group Policy restrictions to prevent Windows from executing the “run” command when users hit the Windows key and the “R” key simultaneously.]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>