<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Security News</title><link>https://securenza.github.io/SecurityFeed/</link><description></description><item><title>Is Security Human Factors Research Skewed Towards Western Ideas and Habits?</title><link>https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/03/is-security-human-factors-research-skewed-towards-western-ideas-and-habits.html</link><author>Bruce Schneier</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 11:10:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.schneier.com/">Schneier on Security</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[: In human factor fields such as human-computer interaction (HCI) and psychology, researchers have been concerned that participants mostly come from WEIRD (Western, Educated, Industrialized, Rich, and Democratic) countries. This WEIRD skew may hinder understanding of diverse populations and their cultural differences. The usable privacy and security (UPS) field has inherited many research methodologies from research on human factor fields. We conducted a literature review to understand the extent to which participant samples in UPS papers were from WEIRD countries and the characteristics of the methodologies and research topics in each user study recruiting Western or non-Western participants. We found that the skew toward WEIRD countries in UPS is greater than that in HCI. Geographic and linguistic barriers in the study methods and recruitment methods may cause researchers to conduct user studies locally. In addition, many papers did not report participant demographics, which could hinder the replication of the reported studies, leading to low reproducibility. To improve geographic diversity, we provide the suggestions including facilitate replication studies, address geographic and linguistic issues of study/recruitment methods, and facilitate research on the topics for non-WEIRD populations.The moral may be that human factors and usability needs to be localized.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Microsoft Warns of StilachiRAT: A Stealthy RAT Targeting Credentials and Crypto Wallets</title><link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/microsoft-warns-of-stilachirat-stealthy.html</link><author>The Hacker News</author><category>security</category><enclosure url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj4UQvJMRpqbL6RzzQypEGHMxf74IOtKNCrYK853AToX1QIq0XRnS28nHFDbCPfjOLRThz37pTRPUTwsUlMKhr3FoEAPtpI-puHr-b2uyPE8OSp6cwiiGGAoPL8F-9sPASlvrpB8RXMcwa_vXiLReutIR1Pv80PiogITxsszkCpOvxCoDkDQ0HTK-i4cMUQ/s1600/malware.png" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://thehackernews.com/">The Hacker News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Microsoft is calling attention to a novel remote access trojan (RAT) named StilachiRAT that it said employs advanced techniques to sidestep detection and persist within target environments with an ultimate aim to steal sensitive data.
The malware contains capabilities to "steal information from the target system, such as credentials stored in the browser, digital wallet information, data stored]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>BlackLock ransomware claims nearly 50 attacks in two months</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/blacklock-ransomware-claims-nearly-50-attacks-in-two-months/</link><author>Bill Toulas</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:40:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A ransomware-as-a-service (RaaS) operation called 'BlackLock' has emerged as one of the more active ransomware operations of 2025. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Telegram CEO leaves France temporarily as criminal probe continues</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/telegram-ceo-leaves-france-temporarily-as-criminal-probe-continues/</link><author>Sergiu Gatlan</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 20:13:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[French authorities have allowed Pavel Durov, Telegram's CEO and founder, to temporarily leave the country while criminal activity on the messaging platform is still under investigation. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Microsoft: New RAT malware used for crypto theft, reconnaissance</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsoft-new-rat-malware-used-for-crypto-theft-reconnaissance/</link><author>Sergiu Gatlan</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 18:59:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[​Microsoft has discovered a new remote access trojan (RAT) that employs "sophisticated techniques" to avoid detection, maintain persistence, and extract sensitive data. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>OKX suspends DEX aggregator after Lazarus hackers try to launder funds</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/okx-suspends-dex-aggregator-after-lazarus-hackers-try-to-launder-funds/</link><author>Bill Toulas</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 18:23:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[OKX Web3 has decided to suspend its DEX aggregator services to implement security upgrades following reports of abuse by the notorious North Korean Lazarus hackers, who recently conducted a $1.5 billion crypto heist. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Apache Tomcat Vulnerability Actively Exploited Just 30 Hours After Public Disclosure</title><link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/apache-tomcat-vulnerability-comes-under.html</link><author>The Hacker News</author><category>security</category><enclosure url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg0nugq6YDZ6vsyietw1RguIQKa3G8dT9wfvkaAuR2RFuKdA_Iu9watKuRW7Cfef6bFpYipIdW4Fipxfwm1_ZS1Sn9mf7jgxycnIJS8mVKdKFWW-mQ1ptkjYu-3-Blh9Ht5eWad5MNtWKCDSuQqmcr-Zin8Wg228EgjSZXdXsBl4wqeiJZGMljuCBeQ3vlm/s1600/apache.png" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://thehackernews.com/">The Hacker News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A recently disclosed security flaw impacting Apache Tomcat has come under active exploitation in the wild following the release of a public proof-of-concept (PoC) a mere 30 hours after public disclosure.
The vulnerability, tracked as CVE-2025-24813, affects the below versions -

Apache Tomcat 11.0.0-M1 to 11.0.2
Apache Tomcat 10.1.0-M1 to 10.1.34
Apache Tomcat 9.0.0-M1 to 9.0.98

It]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Supply chain attack on popular GitHub Action exposes CI/CD secrets</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/supply-chain-attack-on-popular-github-action-exposes-ci-cd-secrets/</link><author>Bill Toulas</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:24:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A supply chain attack on the widely used 'tj-actions/changed-files' GitHub Action, used by 23,000 repositories, potentially allowed threat actors to steal CI/CD secrets from GitHub Actions build logs. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Improvements in Brute Force Attacks</title><link>https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/03/improvements-in-brute-force-attacks.html</link><author>Bruce Schneier</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.schneier.com/">Schneier on Security</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ Key lengths in symmetric cryptography are determined with respect to the brute force attacks with current technology. While nowadays at least 128-bit keys are recommended, there are many standards and real-world applications that use shorter keys. In order to estimate the actual threat imposed by using those short keys, precise estimates for attacks are crucial.In this work we provide optimized implementations of several widely used algorithms on GPUs, leading to interesting insights on the cost of brute force attacks on several real-word applications.In particular, we optimize KASUMI (used in GPRS/GSM),SPECK (used in RFID communication), andTEA3 (used in TETRA). Our best optimizations allow us to try 2, 2, and 2 keys per second on a single RTX 4090 GPU. Those results improve upon previous results significantly, e.g. our KASUMI implementation is more than 15 times faster than the optimizations given in the CRYPTO’24 paper [ACC+24] improving the main results of that paper by the same factor.With these optimizations, in order to break GPRS/GSM, RFID, and TETRA communications in a year, one needs around 11.22 billion, and 1.36 million RTX 4090GPUs, respectively.For KASUMI, the time-memory trade-off attacks of [ACC+24] can be performed with142 RTX 4090 GPUs instead of 2400 RTX 3090 GPUs or, when the same amount of GPUs are used, their table creation time can be reduced to 20.6 days from 348 days,crucial improvements for real world cryptanalytic tasks.Attacks always get better; they never get worse. None of these is practical yet, and they might never be. But there are certainly more optimizations to come.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Microsoft: March Windows updates mistakenly uninstall Copilot</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-march-windows-updates-mistakenly-uninstall-copilot/</link><author>Sergiu Gatlan</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:39:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[​Microsoft says the March 2025 Windows cumulative updates automatically and mistakenly remove the AI-powered Copilot digital assistant from some Windows 10 and Windows 11 systems. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Critical RCE flaw in Apache Tomcat actively exploited in attacks</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/critical-rce-flaw-in-apache-tomcat-actively-exploited-in-attacks/</link><author>Bill Toulas</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:29:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A critical remote code execution (RCE) vulnerability in Apache Tomcat tracked as CVE-2025-24813 is actively exploited in the wild, enabling attackers to take over servers with a simple PUT request. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Unpatched Edimax Camera Flaw Exploited for Mirai Botnet Attacks Since Last Year</title><link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/unpatched-edimax-camera-flaw-exploited.html</link><author>The Hacker News</author><category>security</category><enclosure url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgctze-3Q0u5grlct5oCBo9ofcjfAUbLKmU16r5UvmUsjvjDaK_6ILc_NWXsFCmJ-KSm6wOrqOYs0SFu3mUP-FW_0lTbn9Krd1zcjW-iy8HVoz4lHZJmcXPyQ2o5x8rKOsgzCw4zFPoq5l9vdTs224q44i8v-gDe5fsLmG9VmQcUmtyQ3xRxc23aNFPNV9A/s1600/camera.png" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://thehackernews.com/">The Hacker News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[An unpatched security flaw impacting the Edimax IC-7100 network camera is being exploited by threat actors to deliver Mirat botnet malware variants since at least May 2024.
The vulnerability in question is CVE-2025-1316 (CVSS v4 score: 9.3), a critical operating system command injection flaw that an attacker could exploit to achieve remote code execution on susceptible devices by means of a]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Cybercriminals Exploit CSS to Evade Spam Filters and Track Email Users&apos; Actions</title><link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/cybercriminals-exploit-css-to-evade.html</link><author>The Hacker News</author><category>security</category><enclosure url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhsMxsDv3SbHg6LFIAs_0efpe3OOGYhasxKJ8gBjpGhNsr-0jO_Ga7Kta4N4OgbhOmtY-XRryUXaulPfEMsfYO5MRvfPENY1VW2KvaYozRcc1zrxs1DXYDXqPYO9K8RxCEKlAj0EnufRe6fuN4J8MqM1yVTTUQA4vCnm8zEXcsIH8OcL4xcUbHTsATcn4Sh/s1600/css.png" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:52:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://thehackernews.com/">The Hacker News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Malicious actors are exploiting Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), which are used to style and format the layout of web pages, to bypass spam filters and track users' actions.
That's according to new findings from Cisco Talos, which said such malicious activities can compromise a victim's security and privacy.
"The features available in CSS allow attackers and spammers to track users' actions and]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>⚡ THN Weekly Recap: Router Hacks, PyPI Attacks, New Ransomware Decryptor, and More</title><link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/thn-weekly-recap-router-hacks-pypi.html</link><author>The Hacker News</author><category>security</category><enclosure url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhOeJNcy9pX7fDb_FdXXSSF8be6Hb0ICSj3bA0nEwZdC1Q3UFHuEH2qUKBU58jHu1EBZzqBf45HbPH4TOVeNuGARQsVcWFu3irkv1NK4F9yX6ux0k82pBDC-IQFV0BXlUOr_hNxrt2b-8eOY98C3-Anl31BD7LOLgofv75o7fVyCpvqVjK053rEfILQ0TJ9/s1600/recap.png" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://thehackernews.com/">The Hacker News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[From sophisticated nation-state campaigns to stealthy malware lurking in unexpected places, this week’s cybersecurity landscape is a reminder that attackers are always evolving. Advanced threat groups are exploiting outdated hardware, abusing legitimate tools for financial fraud, and finding new ways to bypass security defenses. Meanwhile, supply chain threats are on the rise, with open-source]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>SANS Institute Warns of Novel Cloud-Native Ransomware Attacks</title><link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/sans-institute-warns-of-novel-cloud.html</link><author>The Hacker News</author><category>security</category><enclosure url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEigJPlhdwtJqr91kNwKVbD0VlBM5hFPvJiHovNIcJZ64xO10ex7bo4uLlt3oecccpX-r8yZjw6dazKCBZ1Qfm50R2GiVfg1c0Jbgf-tj8io4DdXNAYt7608tnLeVH8Ljolpd8xbkmOwWnWP_6pL77ZsIvGyzJwAln6w5qBB0KnEVSAd6_wta0Z3sQ7-ZVw/s1600/webcast_.png" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://thehackernews.com/">The Hacker News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The latest Palo Alto Networks Unit 42 Cloud Threat Report found that sensitive data is found in 66% of cloud storage buckets. This data is vulnerable to ransomware attacks. The SANS Institute recently reported that these attacks can be performed by abusing the cloud provider’s storage security controls and default settings.
“In just the past few months, I have witnessed two different methods for]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>GitHub Action Compromise Puts CI/CD Secrets at Risk in Over 23,000 Repositories</title><link>https://thehackernews.com/2025/03/github-action-compromise-puts-cicd.html</link><author>The Hacker News</author><category>security</category><enclosure url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi4uCoSeJGTGQHDHpY8aWzjTeRGWJdiDrNTvY3S3jUElG52fxb_2txsJoLoP_zZrZXmuvl2_ce3-11NSERhbnsDXuH7Sf2BZGKh6sf1ReTo6QvNuojoZmf_r1b6i8v-B4oBafqEqCbjGh55a09mQJYRF_nFxYe64K20xY_MSnM3iq01M-AIhC6UrhEJe7g6/s1600/github.png" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://thehackernews.com/">The Hacker News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Cybersecurity researchers are calling attention to an incident in which the popular GitHub Action tj-actions/changed-files was compromised to leak secrets from repositories using the continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) workflow.
The incident involved the tj-actions/changed-files GitHub Action, which is used in over 23,000 repositories. It's used to track and retrieve all]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fake &quot;Security Alert&quot; issues on GitHub use OAuth app to hijack accounts</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/fake-security-alert-issues-on-github-use-oauth-app-to-hijack-accounts/</link><author>Lawrence Abrams</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 18:36:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A widespread phishing campaign has targeted nearly 12,000 GitHub repositories with fake "Security Alert" issues, tricking developers into authorizing a malicious OAuth app that grants attackers full control over their accounts and code. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Malicious Adobe, DocuSign OAuth apps target Microsoft 365 accounts</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/malicious-adobe-docusign-oauth-apps-target-microsoft-365-accounts/</link><author>Bill Toulas</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 14:19:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Cybercriminals are promoting malicious Microsoft OAuth apps that masquerade as Adobe and DocuSign apps to deliver malware and steal Microsoft 365 accounts credentials. [...]]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New Akira ransomware decryptor cracks encryptions keys using GPUs</title><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/gpu-powered-akira-ransomware-decryptor-released-on-github/</link><author>Bill Toulas</author><category>security</category><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 14:16:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/">BleepingComputer</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Security researcher Yohanes Nugroho has released a decryptor for the Linux variant of Akira ransomware, which utilizes GPU power to retrieve the decryption key and unlock files for free. [...]]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>