<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Podcasts</title><link>https://konrad.website/liveboat-github-runner/</link><description></description><item><title>NEW: Philip Goff and Helen De Cruz on Finding (and Losing) Religion</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rfHdoNEVGrc</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/rfHdoNEVGrc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:00:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On February 17 at 11am ET, watch the live premiere of our exclusive interview with Philip Goff and Helen De Cruz where they discuss moving toward and away from religion and why: https://shorturl.at/66uzy #shorts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Jonathan Schooler - Can AI Become Conscious?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vp8jXryNpFU</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Vp8jXryNpFU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:00:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, perspectives, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

AI consciousness, its possibility or probability, has burst into public debate, eliciting all kinds of issues from AI ethics and rights to artificial intelligence going rogue and harming humanity. We explore diverse views; we argue that AI consciousness depends on theories of consciousness.

Show your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Jonathan Schooler is an American psychologist and Distinguished Professor of Psychological and Brain Sciences at the University of California, Santa Barbara, who researches various topics that intersect aspects of both cognitive psychology and philosophy such as: Belief in free will, Meta-awareness, Mindfulness, Mind-Wandering, Memory, Creativity, and Emotion. Schooler is also known for his sometimes controversial research on topics such as Anomalous Cognition and the decline effect.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Discovering discovery coding (Friends)</title><link>https://changelog.com/friends/80</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/friends/80/changelog--friends-80.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Fire up a REPL, grab your favorite Stephen King novel, and hold on to the seat of your pants! Jimmy Miller returns to reveal why, at least for some of us, discovery coding is where it’s at.Changelog++ members save 9 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Temporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
Augment Code – Developer AI that uses deep understanding of your large codebase and how you build software to deliver personalized code suggestions and insights. Augment provides relevant, contextualized code right in your IDE or Slack. It transforms scattered knowledge into code or answers, eliminating time spent searching docs or interrupting teammates.
Notion – Notion is a place where any team can write, plan, organize, and rediscover the joy of play. It’s a workspace designed not just for making progress, but getting inspired. Notion is for everyone — whether you’re a Fortune 500 company or freelance designer, starting a new startup or a student juggling classes and clubs.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Bernard Carr - Physics and Cosmology: The Anthropic Principle</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IcTPh6HnmjY</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IcTPh6HnmjY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 16:00:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Shop Closer To Truth merch like apparel, home goods, and more to show your support of the show: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

We should expect to observe that the universe in which we live must conform to the conditions required for our presence as observers. This is the unremarkable “Weak Anthropic Principle”: our universe has fundamental constants that happen to fall within the narrow range thought to be compatible with life. The “Strong Anthropic Principle” makes the teleological claim that the universe must have those properties that allow or require intelligent life to develop, that the universe is in some sense compelled to bring forth conscious life. Does anything meaningful follow from these ideas?

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Bernard J. Carr is a British Bernard J. Carr is a British professor of mathematics and astronomy at Queen Mary University of London. His research interests include the early universe, dark matter, general relativity, primordial black holes, and the anthropic principle.   of mathematics and astronomy at Queen Mary University of London. His research interests include the early universe, dark matter, general relativity, primordial black holes, and the anthropic principle.

Contribute what you can to Closer To Truth and help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions without the need for paywalls: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Evolving Workflow Orchestration // Alex Milowski // #291</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/Evolving-Workflow-Orchestration--Alex-Milowski--291-e2us8at</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/98492189/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2025-1-14%2F394870366-44100-2-f81b1b5d49c1e.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 14:39:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ is a researcher, developer, , mathematician, and .Evolving Workflow Orchestration // MLOps Podcast #291 with Alex Milowski, Entrepreneur and Computer Scientist.// AbstractThere seems to be a shift from workflow languages to code - mostly annotation pythons - happening and getting us. It is a symptom of how complex workflow orchestration has gotten. Is it a dominant trend or will we cycle back to “DAG specifications”? At Stitchfix, we had our own DSL that “compiled” into airflow DAGs and at MicroByre, we used a external workflow langauge. Both had a batch task executor on K8s but at MicroByre, we had human and robot in the loop workflows.// BioDr. Milowski is a serial entrepreneur and computer scientist with experience in a variety of data and machine learning technologies. He holds a PhD in Informatics (Computer Science) from the University of Edinburgh, where he researched large-scale computation over scientific data. Over the years, he's spent many years working on various aspects of workflow orchestration in industry, standardization, and in research.// MLOps Swag/Merchhttps://shop.mlops.community/// Related LinksWebsite: https://www.milowski.com/ --------------- ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ -------------Join our slack community: https://go.mlops.community/slackFollow us on Twitter: @mlopscommunitySign up for the next meetup: https://go.mlops.community/registerCatch all episodes, blogs, newsletters, and more: https://mlops.community/Connect with Demetrios on LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dpbrinkm/Connect with Alex on LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexmilowski/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Bombing of Dresden</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-bombing-of-dresden</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/67acbf38b468a1d76f07cfe4/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=4t-ogoVsYhBL5G4XkWv7VG90QBldYnzKndFl63Zs2Qk" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[As the Second World War neared its bloody climax, Allied bombers unleashed a devastating firestorm on Dresden. In just two days the historic city was reduced to rubble, and tens of thousands were killed. The question remains - was this a legitimate military operation, or an unjustifiable act of destruction?For the latest episode in our 'D-Day to Berlin' series, we're joined by Sinclair McKay, author of 'Dresden: The Fire and the Darkness'. Aided by the words of Victor Gregg, a British POW who was in the city that fateful night, Sinclair unpacks one of the most controversial events of the Second World War.Warning: This episode contains detailed discussion of events that some listeners may find upsetting.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2273 - Adam Curry</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IYGG84s1a28</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IYGG84s1a28?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 18:00:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Adam Curry is an internet entrepreneur, former MTV VJ, and podcasting pioneer. He is the co-host, along with John C. Dvorak, of the "No Agenda" podcast.
http://www.noagendashow.net

This episode is brought to you by ZipRecruiter — 4 out of 5 employers who post on ZipRecruiter get a quality candidate within the first day. Try ZipRecruiter FOR FREE at http://ziprecruiter.com/rogan

Go to https://www.expressvpn.com/ROGANYT and find out how you can get 4 months of ExpressVPN free!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Michael Almeida - Did God Create Abstract Objects?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CFiQtdz3LLc</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CFiQtdz3LLc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 16:00:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Follow us on Instagram for daily news, announcements, and exciting updates: https://shorturl.at/p2IhM

Abstract objects, like numbers and logic, give God problems. Because they always exist and exist necessarily, abstract objects cannot be created or destroyed. But could God have created abstract objects? If so, how? If not, God would no longer be all-powerful and 100 percent sovereign, as theology requires, because he would not have created everything that exists.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Mike Almeida is Professor of Philosophy and chair of the Department of Philosophy and Classics at the University of Texas at San Antonio.

Get member exclusives like early access to new content with a free Closer To Truth account: https://closertotruth.com/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fostering open source culture (Interview)</title><link>https://changelog.com/podcast/628</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/podcast/628/the-changelog-628.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Arun Gupta is back, this time with his latest book in hand titled “Fostering Open Source Culture” to share his wisdom and experiences of fostering open source culture. BTW you can use the code  to get 20% off (both print and e-book). Use this link and enjoy.Changelog++ members save 8 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Temporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
Augment Code – Developer AI that uses deep understanding of your large codebase and how you build software to deliver personalized code suggestions and insights. Augment provides relevant, contextualized code right in your IDE or Slack. It transforms scattered knowledge into code or answers, eliminating time spent searching docs or interrupting teammates.
Notion – Notion is a place where any team can write, plan, organize, and rediscover the joy of play. It’s a workspace designed not just for making progress, but getting inspired. Notion is for everyone — whether you’re a Fortune 500 company or freelance designer, starting a new startup or a student juggling classes and clubs.
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps close to your users — global Anycast load-balancing, zero-configuration private networking, hardware isolation, and instant WireGuard VPN connections. Push-button deployments that scale to thousands of instances. Check out the speedrun to get started in minutes.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Andrew Briggs - Is the Universe Theologically Ambiguous?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N9f-aPMvJk4</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/N9f-aPMvJk4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 20:00:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Follow us on Instagram for daily news, announcements, and exciting updates: https://shorturl.at/p2IhM

Although many physicists, astronomers, cosmologists do not believe in God, many do. Why the stark division — divided both by what they believe and by how they interpret the same evidence. A cosmos of order or disorder? A cosmos life friendly or life hostile? A cosmos of meaning or no meaning? Both sides using the same evidence!

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

George Andrew Davidson Briggs is a British scientist. He is Professor of Nanomaterials in the Department of Materials at the University of Oxford. He is best known for his early work in acoustic microscopy and his current work in materials for quantum technologies.

Get member exclusives like early access to new content with a free Closer To Truth account: https://closertotruth.com/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2272 - Mike Benz</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XPPc8OVNngg</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XPPc8OVNngg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 18:00:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Mike Benz is a former official with the U.S. Department of State and current Executive Director of the Foundation For Freedom Online, is a free speech watchdog organization dedicated to restoring the promise of a free and open Internet.
http://www.foundationforfreedomonline.com

For a FREE trial and 10% off your first Squarespace website or domain, visit www.squarespace.com/ROGAN

This episode is brought to you by BetterHelp.
Get working on a better you with therapy.
Visit http://BetterHelp.com/JRE today to get 10% off your first month.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Elliott Sober - Why Philosophy of Biology?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZgfYtfjC5Do</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZgfYtfjC5Do?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Explore the process of science with the content of biology. Life’s nature and structure. Evolution’s challenges. Examine race, sex and gender, cognition, culture, morality, religion, alien life, and more.

Follow Closer To Truth on Instagram for daily updates and exciting announcements: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

Elliott R. Sober is an American philosopher. He is noted for his work in philosophy of biology and general philosophy of science. Sober is Hans Reichenbach Professor and William F. Vilas Research Professor Emeritus in the Department of Philosophy at the University of Wisconsin–Madison.

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Subsea Cable Network with Josh Dzieza</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2025/02/12/the-subsea-cable-network-with-josh-dzieza/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-subsea-cable-network-with-josh-dzieza</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED7608490746.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Subsea cables are high-capacity fiber-optic lines laid along the ocean floor to enable global communication by transmitting data between continents. Spanning thousands of miles, they carry an estimated 95% of international internet, phone, and data transmissions.Critically, these cables are vulnerable to sabotage by state actors, as they form critical infrastructure for global communication and economic stability. Indeed, Russia and China have been implicated in activities targeting subsea cables as recently as November 2024, and experts warn that these networks are likely to be focal points in future conflicts, heightening geopolitical tensions.Josh Dzieza is a reporter for The Verge and has covered the subsea cable industry and the strategic importance of subsea cables. He joins the podcast alongside Gregor Vand to discuss this invisible, and increasingly important, network infrastructure.You can check out Josh’s reporting here.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Siege of Malta: Knights Hospitaller vs The Ottomans</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-siege-of-malta-knights-hospitaller-vs-the-ottomans</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/67a63d193ef0b176eafa7ee8/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=F_U55i3qpFBZTvkEYRup-TJymIak6Rw0nDC-hqCM6rg" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This is the story of Suleiman the Magnificent's attempt to conquer Malta, the headquarters of a Catholic military order that had become a thorn in his side. They were known as the Knights Hospitaller, and the siege to come would pit Grand Master Jean de Valette and his force of outnumbered defenders against an elite Ottoman army.For this, we're joined by Marcus Bull, author of 'The Great Siege of Malta'. Marcus takes us through this tale of siege warfare and explains how luck as much as skill helped the defenders to hold out long enough for the siege to be broken.Produced by James Hickmann and edited by Matthew Peaty.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ken Mogi on computation theory</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XF-wFHlubJ0</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XF-wFHlubJ0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:00:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Neuroscientist Ken Mogi wants to redefine how we think about computation theory (the idea that the mind is a computational system) and materialism when it comes to human consciousness #shorts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2271 - John Reeves</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JTd43tFzuG4</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JTd43tFzuG4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 18:00:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[John Reeves is an Alaskan gold miner who first came to public prominence on the 2012 National Geographic docu-series "Goldfathers." More recently, his ongoing search for gold uncovered the remains of thousands of Ice Age animals lying beneath the permafrost on his property. The discovery is featured in the 2019 documentary "Boneyard Alaska" and popular Instagram account @theboneyardalaska.

http://www.fairbanksgoldco.com



This episode is brought to you by AG1.

Take ownership of your health with AG1 and get a FREE bottle of Vitamin D3+K2 AND 5 free Travel Packs with your first subscription.

Go to http://drinkag1.com/joerogan]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Insights from Cleric: Building an Autonomous AI SRE // Willem Pienaar // #290</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/Insights-from-Cleric-Building-an-Autonomous-AI-SRE--Willem-Pienaar--290-e2unikg</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/98338896/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2025-1-11%2F394679162-44100-2-e1c6c10bbd504.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 16:32:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ is the Co-Founder and CTO of. He previously worked at Tecton as a Principal Engineer. Willem Pienaar attended the Georgia Institute of Technology.Insights from Cleric: Building an Autonomous AI SRE // MLOps Podcast #289 with Willem Pienaar, CTO & Co-Founder of Cleric.// AbstractIn this MLOps Community Podcast episode, Willem Pienaar, CTO of Cleric, breaks down how they built an autonomous AI SRE that helps engineering teams diagnose production issues. We explore how Cleric builds knowledge graphs for system understanding, and uses existing tools/systems during investigations. We also get into some gnarly challenges around memory, tool integration, and evaluation frameworks, and some lessons learned from deploying to engineering teams.// BioWillem Pienaar, CTO of Cleric, is a builder with a focus on LLM agents, MLOps, and open source tooling. He is the creator of Feast, an open source feature store, and contributed to the creation of both the feature store and MLOps categories.Before starting Cleric, Willem led the open-source engineering team at Tecton and established the ML platform team at Gojek, where he built high-scale ML systems for the Southeast Asian Decacorn.// MLOps Swag/Merchhttps://shop.mlops.community/// Related LinksWebsite: willem.co --------------- ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ -------------Join our slack community:https://go.mlops.community/slackFollow us on Twitter:@mlopscommunitySign up for the next meetup:https://go.mlops.community/registerCatch all episodes, blogs, newsletters, and more:https://mlops.community/Connect with Demetrios on LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/dpbrinkm/Connect with Willem on LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/willempienaar/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Jean-Luc Jucker - How Does the Human Mind Work?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W_6gEODOcb4</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/W_6gEODOcb4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 16:00:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sign up for a Closer To Truth membership to receive special exclusives like early access to new episodes and more: https://closertotruth.com/.

How does human thinking and feeling affect human culture? How does collective society emerge from individual mentalities?

Give what you can to support the show and help Closer To Truth continue exploring life's deepest questions: shorturl.at/OnyRq

Jean-Luc Jucker is an anthropologist expert in interdisciplinary research and mixed methods.

Follow Closer To Truth on Instagram for new videos, announcements, and more: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>LangChain and Agentic AI Engineering with Erick Friis</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2025/02/11/langchain-and-agentic-ai-engineering-with-erick-friis/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=langchain-and-agentic-ai-engineering-with-erick-friis</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED4262555283.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 10:00:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[LangChain is a popular open-source framework to build applications that integrate LLMs with external data sources like APIs, databases, or custom knowledge bases. It’s commonly used for chatbots, question-answering systems, and workflow automation. Its flexibility and extensibility have made it something of a standard for creating sophisticated AI-driven software.Erick Friis is a Founding Engineer at LangChain and he leads their integrations and open source efforts. Erick joins the podcast to talk about what inspired the creation of LangChain, agentic flows vs. chained flows, emerging patterns of agentic AI design, and much more.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Tech is supposed to make our lives easier (News)</title><link>https://changelog.com/news/131</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/news/131/changelog-news-131.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Bill Maher excoriates the software industry for making our lives more difficult, two professors from the University of Washington put together a curriculum to help us manage life in the ChatGPT world, Daniel Delaney thinks deeply on chat as a dev tool UI, Benedict Evans explores our assumptions that computers be ‘correct’ & the Thoughtbot team writes up six cases when not to refactor.Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!Augment Code – Developer AI that uses deep understanding of your large codebase and how you build software to deliver personalized code suggestions and insights. Augment provides relevant, contextualized code right in your IDE or Slack. It transforms scattered knowledge into code or answers, eliminating time spent searching docs or interrupting teammates.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Philip Goff &amp; Helen De Cruz on Finding (and Losing) Their Religion | Closer To Truth Chats</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qrgbZVLpc1I</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qrgbZVLpc1I?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 20:24:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Two notable Closer To Truth contributors—and two good friends—discuss their intellectual, philosophical, and spiritual journeys in what seems to be opposite directions: one toward a form of Christianity and the other away from it.

Philip Goff is a British author, idealist philosopher, and professor at Durham University whose research focuses on philosophy of mind and consciousness. Specifically, it focuses on how consciousness can be part of the scientific worldview. He is the author most recently of the book "Why? The Purpose of the Universe": https://amzn.to/4jPRu3C

Helen De Cruz is a Belgian philosopher and Danforth Chair of Philosophy at Saint Louis University who specializes in philosophy of religion, experimental philosophy, and philosophy of cognitive science. She is also an activist supporting the rights of EU citizens in the context of Brexit. Her most recent book is "Wonderstruck: How Wonder and Awe Shape the Way We Think": https://amzn.to/4guu1Cn

Watch more CTT Chats here: https://t.ly/jJI7e]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2270 - Bridget Phetasy</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HigVe4IqsBM</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HigVe4IqsBM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 18:32:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Bridget Phetasy is a writer and stand-up comedian. She hosts the show “Dumpster Fire" and also the podcast “Walk-Ins Welcome.”
http://www.phetasy.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nancey Murphy - Is the Soul Immortal?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s-3B_mEB5FY</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/s-3B_mEB5FY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Are you a Closer To Truth member? Sign up for free to receive exclusive benefits like early access to episodes, event discounts, and more at https://closertotruth.com/.

The claim that human beings have or are an ‘immortal soul’ goes back to the ancient Greeks, if not further. In a pre-scientific world, it would seem absurd for our inner awareness not to continue, irrespective of what happens to our bodies. Today science rejects the soul, yet there are diverse viewpoints around.

Support the show with a donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring life's deepest questions: shorturl.at/OnyRq

Nancey Murphy is an American philosopher and theologian who is Professor of Christian Philosophy at Fuller Theological Seminary, Pasadena, CA. She received the B.A. from Creighton University in 1973, the Ph.D. from University of California, Berkeley in 1980, and the Th.D. from the Graduate Theological Union in 1987.

Like us on Facebook for daily videos, updates, and more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Iwo Jima: WWII in the Pacific</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/iwo-jima-wwii-in-the-pacific</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/67a5ffad9c6f7f7f28ca817f/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=XmWKIvY0PzYQ9laffKEQzYQFNIzxWzY8Lxz6KuHWGpU" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[80 years ago, on the rocky volcanic island of Iwo Jima, the vicious battle for the Pacific reached ever bloodier crescendos. As Allied forces crossed the Rhine in Europe, American Marines won a costly victory on Iwo Jima in their island-hopping campaign towards the Japanese mainland.For the latest instalment of our 'D-Day to Berlin' series, we're joined by Timothy Heck, an artillery officer in the US Marine Corps Reserve and a supervisory historian with Naval History and Heritage Command. Tim explains why the battle happened, and how the Americans overcame the tenacious Japanese defenders.Produced by James Hickmann and edited by Matthew Peaty.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rodney Holder - Christology and Science?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MGrYfxT9TVk</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MGrYfxT9TVk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Feb 2025 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Find us on Facebook for daily videos, updates, and more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

Christology is the theology of Jesus—the person, life, nature, essence and meaning of the Godhead Being who was incarnated in the human person Jesus. Some Christian theologians claim that aspects of Christology can articulate with fundamental understandings of science. Most scientists would be baffled by the claim.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

The Revd Dr. Rodney Holder was Course Director of the Faraday Institute from its inception in 2006 until 2013, and remains a Bye Fellow of St. Edmund’s College and a Faraday Associate.

Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Alan Love - Philosophy of Reductionism &amp; Emergence</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FLlFxTU_vfY</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FLlFxTU_vfY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Feb 2025 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help support Closer To Truth continue making content like this: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Can biology be explained entirely in terms of chemistry and then physics? If so, that’s “reductionism.” Or are there “emergent” properties at higher levels of the hierarchy of life that cannot be explained by properties at lower or more basic levels?

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Alan C. Love, Ph.D., is a professor in the College of Liberal Arts at the University of Minnesota. He also serves as director of the Minnesota Center for Philosophy of Science.

Shop Closer To Truth merchandise for unique items like notebooks, mugs, and sweatshirts: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>JRE Fight Companion - February 8, 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IGL1vitx_rM</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IGL1vitx_rM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Feb 2025 07:45:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Joe is joined by Matt Serra, Brendan Schaub & Bryan Callen to watch the fights on February 8, 2025.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The state of homelab tech (2025) (Friends)</title><link>https://changelog.com/friends/79</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/friends/79/changelog--friends-79.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Feb 2025 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Techno Tim joins Adam to catch up on the state of Homelab for 2025, the state of AI at home and on-prem (AI Homelab) and where that’s heading, building a creator PC, choosing the parts for your build, GPU availability, Windows being user hostile, and why Tim is happy to be using Windows, Mac AND Linux.Changelog++ members save 8 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelogTemporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
DeleteMe – Text  to 64000 to join DeleteMe. They make it quick, easy, and safe to remove your personal data online.
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps close to your users — global Anycast load-balancing, zero-configuration private networking, hardware isolation, and instant WireGuard VPN connections. Push-button deployments that scale to thousands of instances. Check out the speedrun to get started in minutes.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>David Hunt - Big Questions in Free Will</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d-GhJlwgD3w</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/d-GhJlwgD3w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Feb 2025 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Follow us on X for daily articles, updates, and more: https://x.com/CloserToTruth

Free will seems obvious, simple, common; but it’s subtle, profound, maddening. Free will probes the deep nature of human existence. But big questions have big problems. How to make progress? Can bringing together scientists, philosophers and theologians help? That’s what the ‘Big Questions in Free Will’ project is doing.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help support Closer To Truth continue making content like this: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

David Hunt was a Professor and Department Chair of the Department of Philosophy at Whittier College in Whittier, CA. He earned a BA from Pomona College and a PhD from Vanderbilt University. His academic interests included Ancient and Early Medieval Philosophy (especially Plato, Plotinus, and Augustine), Metaphysics, Action Theory, and the Philosophy of Religion.

Shop Closer To Truth merchandise in our Bonfire storefront to support the show: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Lawrence Krauss - Are there Extra Dimensions?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HEJhpTRzNgQ</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HEJhpTRzNgQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Feb 2025 16:00:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Shop Closer To Truth merch like apparel, home goods, and more to show your support of the show: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Extra dimensions—beyond length, width, height—seem like the stuff of science fiction. What would extra dimensions be like? Is time the fourth dimension? Does string theory require ten or eleven dimensions? Could deep reality be so strange? And, anyway, why would we care?

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Lawrence Maxwell Krauss is a Canadian-American theoretical physicist and cosmologist who taught at Arizona State University, Yale University, and Case Western Reserve University. He founded ASU's Origins Project in 2008 to investigate fundamental questions about the universe and served as the project's director.

Make a donation to Closer To Truth to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions without the need for paywalls: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Robustness, Detectability, and Data Privacy in AI // Vinu Sankar Sadasivan // #289</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/Robustness--Detectability--and-Data-Privacy-in-AI--Vinu-Sankar-Sadasivan--289-e2ui4si</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/98160978/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2025-1-7%2F394458992-44100-2-ab419176af6b.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Feb 2025 14:44:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[is a CS PhD ... Currently, I am working as a full-time  on jailbreaking multimodal AI models.

Robustness, Detectability, and Data Privacy in AI // MLOps Podcast #289 with Vinu Sankar Sadasivan, Student Researcher at Google DeepMind.

// Abstract
Recent rapid advancements in Artificial Intelligence (AI) have made it widely applicable across various domains, from autonomous systems to multimodal content generation. However, these models remain susceptible to significant security and safety vulnerabilities. Such weaknesses can enable attackers to jailbreak systems, allowing them to perform harmful tasks or leak sensitive information. As AI becomes increasingly integrated into critical applications like autonomous robotics and healthcare, the importance of ensuring AI safety is growing. Understanding the vulnerabilities in today’s AI systems is crucial to addressing these concerns.

// Bio
Vinu Sankar Sadasivan is a final-year Computer Science PhD candidate at The University of Maryland, College Park, advised by Prof. Soheil Feizi. His research focuses on Security and Privacy in AI, with a particular emphasis on AI robustness, detectability, and user privacy. Currently, Vinu is a full-time Student Researcher at Google DeepMind, working on jailbreaking multimodal AI models. Previously, Vinu was a Research Scientist intern at Meta FAIR in Paris, where he worked on AI watermarking.

Vinu is a recipient of the 2023 Kulkarni Fellowship and has earned several distinctions, including the prestigious Director’s Silver Medal. He completed a Bachelor’s degree in Computer Science & Engineering at IIT Gandhinagar in 2020. Prior to their PhD, Vinu gained research experience as a Junior Research Fellow in the Data Science Lab at IIT Gandhinagar and through internships at Caltech, Microsoft Research India, and IISc.

// MLOps Swag/Merch
https://shop.mlops.community/

// Related Links
Website: https://vinusankars.github.io/
 
--------------- ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ -------------
Join our slack community: https://go.mlops.community/slack
Follow us on Twitter: @mlopscommunity
Sign up for the next meetup: https://go.mlops.community/register
Catch all episodes, blogs, newsletters, and more: https://mlops.community/

Connect with Demetrios on LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dpbrinkm/
Connect with Richard on LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vinusankars/

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nostradamus</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/nostradamus</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/679cc24fc4b7d8845b36df9e/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=tJID3CacAlgwHCr-e1tu9CX9tQRepvmUuo5lvYGT7OQ" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Feb 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[For centuries, Nostradamus has been hailed as the man who saw the future—his cryptic quatrains allegedly foretelling everything from the French Revolution and the rise of Hitler to the 9/11 attacks and the Covid-19 pandemic. But how much is true, and how much is myth?Joining Dan in this episode to unravel the true history of the French soothsayer is John Hogue, a renowned Nostradamus scholar. Together they explore Nostradamus' life as a plague doctor, the occult during the Renaissance, his most famous predictions and why they still captivate us today.With special thanks to listener Tamarah Palmer.Produced by Mariana Des Forges and edited by Dougal Patmore.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Matthews Grant - What is Predestination?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vG-dDjVooCE</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vG-dDjVooCE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 6 Feb 2025 20:00:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you get your podcasts. Listen today: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Predestination is ultimate destiny, fate. It is the claim by some religions that a Supreme Being, whether a personal God or a cosmic force, has determined for individual lives their ultimate course. When God foreordains, whether for salvation or for damnation, nothing can resist. Is this fair? Does this make sense? Would you like such a God?

Make a tax-deductible donation to Closer To Truth to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions without paywalls: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Matthews Grant is an Associate Professor in the Department of Philosophy at the University of St. Thomas in St. Paul, Minnesota.

Browse the Closer To Truth merch store to purchase unique items like T-shirts, hoodies, mugs, and more: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2269 - Bret Weinstein</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7ted-qUqqU4</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7ted-qUqqU4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 6 Feb 2025 18:00:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dr. Bret Weinstein is an evolutionary biologist, podcaster, and author. He co-wrote "A Hunter-Gatherer's Guide to the 21st Century: Evolution and the Challenges of Modern Life" with his wife, Dr. Heather Heying, who is also a biologist. They both host the podcast "The DarkHorse Podcast."

http://www.bretweinstein.net

Go to https://www.expressvpn.com/ROGANYT and find out how you can get 4 months of ExpressVPN free!

Don’t miss out on all the action this week at DraftKings! Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using http://dkng.co/rogan or through my promo code ROGAN.

GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit http://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit http://ccpg.org (CT) or visit http://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD).21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS). 1 per new customer. Min. $5 deposit. Min. $5 bet. Max. $200 issued as non-withdrawable Bonus Bets that expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: http://dkng.co/dk-offer-terms. Ends 2/9/25 at 11:59 PM ET. Sponsored by DK.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Secure Communications in Embedded Systems with Ismael Valenzuela and John Wall</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2025/02/06/secure-communications-in-embedded-systems-with-ismael-valenzuela-and-john-wall/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=secure-communications-in-embedded-systems-with-ismael-valenzuela-and-john-wall</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED6211023223.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 6 Feb 2025 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[BlackBerry is a Canadian company known for its pivotal role in the smartphone market during the 2000s. Today, BlackBerry has adopted a major focus on cybersecurity.John Wall is the Chief Operating Officer and Head of Products, Engineering and Services at QNX, which is a division of BlackBerry. Ismael Valenzuela is the former Vice President of Threat Research and Intelligence at BlackBerry, where he led threat research, intelligence, and defensive innovation. John and Ismael join the podcast to talk about cybersecurity at Blackberry, including secure communications in embedded systems.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Build software that lasts! (Interview)</title><link>https://changelog.com/podcast/627</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/podcast/627/the-changelog-627.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 5 Feb 2025 20:15:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[After 30+ years in the software industry, Bert Hubert has experienced a lot. He founded PowerDNS, published articles for places like IETF / IEEE, and built his own parliament monitoring system. That just scratches the surface.Recently, Bert wrote about what it takes to build software for the long term. Let’s dig in.Changelog++ members get a bonus 10 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelogTemporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
DeleteMe – Text  to 64000 to join DeleteMe. They make it quick, easy, and safe to remove your personal data online.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2268 - Rick Caruso</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-44tAVI7OEg</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-44tAVI7OEg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 5 Feb 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Rick Caruso is a businessman, civic leader, and philanthropist. He is the owner and executive chairman of Caruso, one of the largest privately held real estate companies in the world, and founder of Steadfast LA: a nonprofit focused on private-sector involvement in rebuilding wildfire-affected communities.
http://www.steadfastla.com

This episode is brought to you by AG1.
Take ownership of your health with AG1 and get a FREE bottle of Vitamin D3+K2 AND 5 free Travel Packs with your first subscription. 

Go to http://drinkag1.com/joerogan

Don’t miss out on all the action this week at DraftKings! Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using http://dkng.co/rogan or through my promo code ROGAN. 

GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit http://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit http://ccpg.org (CT) or visit http://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD).21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS). 1 per new customer. Min. $5 deposit. Min. $5 bet. Max. $200 issued as non-withdrawable Bonus Bets that expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: http://dkng.co/dk-offer-terms. Ends 2/9/25 at 11:59 PM ET. Sponsored by DK.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Caves of Qud with Brian Bucklew</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2025/02/05/caves-of-qud-with-brian-bucklew/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=caves-of-qud-with-brian-bucklew</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED9626101996.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 5 Feb 2025 10:00:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Caves of Qud is a roguelike game set in a richly detailed, post-apocalyptic world blending science fiction and fantasy. The game is known for its deep lore, emergent gameplay, and wildly creative character customization. It is a massive indie success, and recently hit a major milestone with the release of version 1.0 after 15 years of development.Brian Bucklew is the cofounder of Freehold games which develops Caves of Qud. Brian joins the show to talk about his engineering background and the development of his game.Joe Nash is a developer, educator, and award-winning community builder, who has worked at companies including GitHub, Twilio, Unity, and PayPal. Joe got his start in software development by creating mods and running servers for Garry’s Mod, and game development remains his favorite way to experience and explore new technologies and concepts.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>2. The English Civil War: Roundheads vs Cavaliers</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-english-civil-war-roundheads-vs-cavaliers</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/679cc11d2a5cfef56231a2d5/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=V1L4cEQrcEb8e7NDrKGupBXQ9sApROngh652x1OG2IA" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 5 Feb 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Episode 2/2. In 1642, England was torn apart by a fierce struggle. Royalist armies, loyal to the defiant King Charles I, clashed with the forces of Parliament, igniting a violent civil war that would decide the fate of the monarchy and the nation. In this second episode, we hear about some of the bloodiest battles between Roundheads and Cavaliers, the leaders who came to the fore during these trying years and how the two sides eventually arrived at a shaky truce.For this, Dan is joined by Minoo Dinshaw, author of 'Friends in Youth: Choosing Sides in the English Civil War'. He explains this tumultuous period from the perspective of Bulstrode Whitelocke and Edward Hyde, two close friends who reluctantly found themselves on opposing sides of the conflict that split England in two.Produced by James Hickmann and edited by Max Carrey.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2267 - Dan Richards</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ol7PofIyZPI</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Ol7PofIyZPI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 4 Feb 2025 18:00:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dan Richards is an independent researcher whose YouTube channel, "DeDunking the Past," examines lost civilizations and alternative history.

http://www.youtube.com/@DeDunking

This episode is brought to you by BetterHelp. 
Get working on a better you with therapy.
Visit http://BetterHelp.com/JRE today to get 10% off your first month.

Don’t miss out on all the action this week at DraftKings! Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using http://dkng.co/rogan or through my promo code ROGAN. 

GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit http://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit http://ccpg.org (CT) or visit http://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD).21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS). 1 per new customer. Min. $5 deposit. Min. $5 bet. Max. $200 issued as non-withdrawable Bonus Bets that expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: http://dkng.co/dk-offer-terms. Ends 2/9/25 at 11:59 PM ET. Sponsored by DK.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>AI &amp; Aliens: New Eyes on Ancient Questions // Richard Cloete // #288</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/AI--Aliens-New-Eyes-on-Ancient-Questions--Richard-Cloete--288-e2udn14</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/98015716/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2025-1-4%2F394277793-44100-2-45d73bbd25586.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 4 Feb 2025 17:31:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ is a computer scientist and a Laukien-Oumuamua Postdoctoral Research Fellow at the Center for Astrophysics, Harvard University. He is a member of the Galileo Project working under the supervision of Professor Avi, having recently held a postdoctoral position at the University of Cambridge, UK.

AI & Aliens: New Eyes on Ancient Questions // MLOps Podcast #288 with Richard Cloete, 
Laukien-Oumuamua Postdoctoral Research Fellow at Harvard University.

// Abstract
Demetrios speaks with Dr. Richard Cloete, a Harvard computer scientist and founder of SEAQR Robotics, about his AI-driven work in tracking Unidentified Aerial Phenomena (UAPs) through the Galileo Project. Dr. Cloete explains their advanced sensor setup and the challenges of training AI in this niche field, leading to the creation of AeroSynth, a synthetic data tool.

He also discusses his collaboration with the Minor Planet Center on using AI to classify interstellar objects and upcoming telescope data. Additionally, he introduces Seeker Robotics, applying similar AI techniques to oceanic research with unmanned vehicles for marine monitoring. The conversation explores AI’s role in advancing our understanding of space and the ocean.

// Bio
Richard is a computer scientist and Laukien-Oumuamua Postdoctoral Research Fellow at the Center for Astrophysics, Harvard University. As a member of the Galileo Project under Professor Avi Loeb's supervision, he develops AI models for detecting and tracking aerial objects, specializing in Unidentified Anomalous Phenomena (UAP). 

Beyond UAP research, he collaborates with astronomers at the Minor Planet Center to create AI models for identifying potential interstellar objects using the upcoming Vera C. Rubin Observatory. 

Richard is also the CEO and co-founder of SEAQR Robotics, a startup developing advanced unmanned surface vehicles to accelerate the discovery of novel life and phenomena in Earth's oceans and atmosphere. 

Before joining Harvard, he completed a postdoctoral fellowship at the University of Cambridge, UK, where his research explored the intersection of emerging technologies and law.Grew up in Cape Town, South Africa, where I used to build Tesla Coils, plasma globes, radio stethoscopes, microwave guns, AM radios, and bombs...

// MLOps Swag/Merch
https://shop.mlops.community/

// Related Links
Website: www.seaqr.net
https://itc.cfa.harvard.edu/people/richard-cloete
 
--------------- ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ -------------
Join our slack community: https://go.mlops.community/slack
Follow us on Twitter: @mlopscommunity
Sign up for the next meetup: https://go.mlops.community/register
Catch all episodes, blogs, newsletters, and more: https://mlops.community/

Connect with Demetrios on LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dpbrinkm/
Connect with Richard on LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-cloete/

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Maximizing Cloud Efficiency with Jerzy Grzywinski and Brent Segner</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2025/02/04/maximizing-cloud-efficiency-with-jerzy-grzywinski-and-brent-segner/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=maximizing-cloud-efficiency-with-jerzy-grzywinski-and-brent-segner</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED1045788818.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 4 Feb 2025 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Compute optimization in a cloud environment is a common challenge because of the need to balance performance, cost, and resource availability. The growing use of GPUs for workloads, including AI, is also increasing the complexity and importance of optimization given the relatively high cost of GPU cloud computation.Jerzy Grzywinski is a Senior Director of Software Engineering and leads FinOps at Capital One. Brent Segner is a distinguished engineer at Capital One and is focused on performance engineering and cloud cost optimization. Jerzy and Brent joined the show with Sean Falconer to talk about methods to measure compute efficiency, horizontal versus vertical scaling, how to think about adopting new instance types, the effect of different languages on compute efficiency, and much more.Full Disclosure: This episode is sponsored by .]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Everyone knows your location (News)</title><link>https://changelog.com/news/130</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/news/130/changelog-news-130.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 3 Feb 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Tim Sh tracked himself down through in-app ads, Sniffnet comfortably monitors your Internet traffic, Cate Huston opines on what makes a good team, Victor Shepelev draws on 25 years of coding to share seven things he now knows & Grant Slatton tells you how to write a good design document.Changelog++ members support our work, get closer to the metal, and make the ads disappear. Join today!Augment Code – Developer AI that uses deep understanding of your large codebase and how you build software to deliver personalized code suggestions and insights. Augment provides relevant, contextualized code right in your IDE or Slack. It transforms scattered knowledge into code or answers, eliminating time spent searching docs or interrupting teammates.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Story: One Million Checkboxes - The Viral Game That Defied Convention</title><link>https://corecursive.com/one-million-checkboxes-with-nolen-royalty/</link><author>Adam@corecursive.com (Adam@corecursive.com)</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/corecursive/omcb.mp3?dest-id=628353" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 3 Feb 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://corecursive.com/">Podcast - CoRecursive</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[What if internet trolls could become your greatest collaborators? Nolen Royalty discovered this unexpected truth when his simple checkbox game went viral.It began with a school email prank that crashed servers but sparked a philosophy: creative constraints breed innovation. From "Flappy Dird" to "One Million Checkboxes," Nolen built games that turned limitations into playgrounds.But when his checkbox project became a battleground of organized chaos, Nolen faced a choice: suppress the chaos or lean into it.Discover how systematic constraints can channel creative anarchy - and why one developer now believes the best user experiences emerge when you code for controlled chaos of strangers meeting on the internet.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>1. The English Civil War: How it Started</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-english-civil-war-rising-tensions</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/679cb3ac9bbbbb6213943e5d/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=w0TZHctIzk6d5Q2HDkNBYuQRsuCSJN9LsuEBugPIBS0" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 3 Feb 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Episode 1/2. King Charles I's decision to rule without Parliament was just one of the many reasons that England found itself embroiled in a bloody civil war. In this first episode, we learn how subtle religious and political differences upset the balance of power in England, and plunged the kingdom into chaos.For this, Dan is joined by Minoo Dinshaw, author of 'Friends in Youth: Choosing Sides in the English Civil War'. He explains this tumultuous period from the perspective of Bulstrode Whitelocke and Edward Hyde, two close friends who reluctantly found themselves on opposing sides of the conflict that split England in two.Produced by James Hickmann and edited by Max Carrey.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>DeepSeek, China, OpenAI, NVIDIA, xAI, TSMC, Stargate, and AI Megaclusters | Lex Fridman Podcast #459</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_1f-o0nqpEI</link><author>Lex Fridman</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_1f-o0nqpEI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 3 Feb 2025 00:12:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSHZKyawb77ixDdsGog4iWA">Podcast - Lex Fridman</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dylan Patel is the founder of SemiAnalysis, a research & analysis company specializing in semiconductors, GPUs, CPUs, and AI hardware. Nathan Lambert is a research scientist at the Allen Institute for AI (Ai2) and the author of a blog on AI called Interconnects.
Thank you for listening ❤ Check out our sponsors: https://lexfridman.com/sponsors/ep459-sb
See below for timestamps, transcript, and to give feedback, submit questions, contact Lex, etc.

*Transcript:*
https://lexfridman.com/deepseek-dylan-patel-nathan-lambert-transcript

*CONTACT LEX:*
*Feedback* - give feedback to Lex: https://lexfridman.com/survey
*AMA* - submit questions, videos or call-in: https://lexfridman.com/ama
*Hiring* - join our team: https://lexfridman.com/hiring
*Other* - other ways to get in touch: https://lexfridman.com/contact

*EPISODE LINKS:*
Dylan's X: https://x.com/dylan522p
SemiAnalysis: https://semianalysis.com/
Nathan's X: https://x.com/natolambert
Nathan's Blog: https://www.interconnects.ai/
Nathan's Podcast: https://www.interconnects.ai/podcast
Nathan's Website: https://www.natolambert.com/
Nathan's YouTube: https://youtube.com/@natolambert
Nathan's Book: https://rlhfbook.com/

*SPONSORS:*
To support this podcast, check out our sponsors & get discounts:
*Invideo AI:* AI video generator.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/invideoai-ep459-sb
*GitHub:* Developer platform and AI code editor.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/github-ep459-sb
*Shopify:* Sell stuff online.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/shopify-ep459-sb
*NetSuite:* Business management software.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/netsuite-ep459-sb
*AG1:* All-in-one daily nutrition drinks.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/ag1-ep459-sb

*OUTLINE:*
0:00 - Introduction
3:33 - DeepSeek-R1 and DeepSeek-V3
25:07 - Low cost of training
51:25 - DeepSeek compute cluster
58:57 - Export controls on GPUs to China
1:09:16 - AGI timeline
1:18:41 - China's manufacturing capacity
1:26:36 - Cold war with China
1:31:05 - TSMC and Taiwan
1:54:44 - Best GPUs for AI
2:09:36 - Why DeepSeek is so cheap
2:22:55 - Espionage
2:31:57 - Censorship
2:44:52 - Andrej Karpathy and magic of RL
2:55:23 - OpenAI o3-mini vs DeepSeek r1
3:14:31 - NVIDIA
3:18:58 - GPU smuggling
3:25:36 - DeepSeek training on OpenAI data
3:36:04 - AI megaclusters
4:11:26 - Who wins the race to AGI?
4:21:39 - AI agents
4:30:21 - Programming and AI
4:37:49 - Open source
4:47:01 - Stargate
4:54:30 - Future of AI

*PODCAST LINKS:*
- Podcast Website: https://lexfridman.com/podcast
- Apple Podcasts: https://apple.co/2lwqZIr
- Spotify: https://spoti.fi/2nEwCF8
- RSS: https://lexfridman.com/feed/podcast/
- Podcast Playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrAXtmErZgOdP_8GztsuKi9nrraNbKKp4
- Clips Channel: https://www.youtube.com/lexclips

*SOCIAL LINKS:*
- X: https://x.com/lexfridman
- Instagram: https://instagram.com/lexfridman
- TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@lexfridman
- LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/lexfridman
- Facebook: https://facebook.com/lexfridman
- Patreon: https://patreon.com/lexfridman
- Telegram: https://t.me/lexfridman
- Reddit: https://reddit.com/r/lexfridman]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Over the top auth strategies (Friends)</title><link>https://changelog.com/friends/78</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/friends/78/changelog--friends-78.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dan Moore from FusionAuth joins us for a wide-ranging discussion about modern auth strategies. We talk magic links, OTP, MFA, passkeys, password managers & so much more.Changelog++ members get a bonus 9 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelogTemporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
Notion – Notion is a place where any team can write, plan, organize, and rediscover the joy of play. It’s a workspace designed not just for making progress, but getting inspired. Notion is for everyone — whether you’re a Fortune 500 company or freelance designer, starting a new startup or a student juggling classes and clubs.
A few more links from Dan]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2266 - Brian Simpson</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZBCf4SogPpI</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZBCf4SogPpI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 18:00:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Brian Simpson is a stand-up comic who hosts the "Bottom of the Barrel" improvised comedy show at the Comedy Mothership and his own podcast, "BS with Brian Simpson." Watch his new special, "Brian Simpson: Live from the Mothership," on Netflix.
http://www.briansimpsoncomedy.com

Take ownership of your health with AG1 and get a FREE bottle of Vitamin D3+K2 AND 5 free Travel Packs with your first subscription. Go to http://drinkag1.com/joerogan

Don’t miss out on all the action this week at DraftKings! Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using http://dkng.co/rogan or through my promo code ROGAN.

GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit http://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit http://ccpg.org (CT) or visit http://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD).21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS). 1 per new customer. Min. $5 deposit. Min. $5 bet. Max. $200 issued as non-withdrawable Bonus Bets that expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: http://dkng.co/dk-offer-terms. Ends 2/9/25 at 11:59 PM ET. Sponsored by DK.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Real LLM Success Stories: How They Actually Work // Alex Strick van Linschoten // #287</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/Real-LLM-Success-Stories-How-They-Actually-Work--Alex-Strick-van-Linschoten--287-e2tvfr2</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/97549602/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2025-0-25%2F393695538-44100-2-283541e0a6446.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 15:15:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Auschwitz Commandant: Rudolf Höss</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/rudolf-hoss-the-commandant-of-auschwitz</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/679a82fea7ace681d87aecfc/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=mPHD4kSeeG0cwmdvUu1dnItqTSj8rEcl2v0UcC3JD98" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Every day Rudolf Höss oversaw the killing of thousands of people at the death camp and then went home and acted like a doting father to his family. Höss was brought in by top Nazis to pioneer the industrialisation of the mass murder of Europe's Jews and others. He lived in a house that shared a wall with Auschwitz, metres from the crematorium, where he and his family enjoyed a happy domestic life - his wife once described their life at the house as 'paradise'.The house was home to a Polish family until last year when it was taken over by the Counter Extremism Project who invited History Hit to explore the house, which is largely as it was when the Hoss family lived there. Dan travels to Poland with historian and best-selling author Thomas Harding to discover more about Höss' role in the Holocaust and what the house teaches us about 'the banality of evil'. They learn about what went on there, what Holocaust artefacts were recently found in the attic and the future of the house as a centre to combat hate.Warning: this episode contains descriptions of human suffering and genocide which some listeners may find upsetting.With special thanks to the Counter Extremism Project, Dr Hans-Jakob Schindler, Keith Burnet and Thomas Harding.You can see the History Hit film about the house here:You can find out more in Thomas' book 'Hanns and Rudolf: The German Jew and the Hunt for the Kommandant of Auschwitz'. He also has a new book out for children. It's called 'The House on the Canal: The Story of the House that Hid Anne Frank.'Produced by Mariana Des Forges and edited by Max Carrey and Dougal Patmore]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>