<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Podcasts</title><link>https://securenza.github.io/SecurityFeed/</link><description></description><item><title>David Bentley Hart - Can Many Religions All Be True?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LNVJeo-SppQ</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LNVJeo-SppQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:00:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get member exclusives like early access to new content with a free Closer To Truth account: https://closertotruth.com/

Conflicting religions fill the world. Doctrines about God contradict one another. No one denies the diversity of religions and the apparent incompatibility of their core beliefs. Many believe only their own religion to be the truth. Some claim all religions reflect the same truth. Others assert that differing dogmas expose the emptiness of all religion.

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, new videos, musings, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

David Bentley Hart is an American philosopher, theologian, essayist, cultural commentator, fiction author, religious studies scholar. Reviewers have commented on Hart's baroque prose and provocative rhetoric in over one thousand essays, reviews, and papers as well as twenty-four books.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Annaka Harris Explores Consciousness and the Cosmos | Closer To Truth Chats</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jinkGDp-CZ8</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/jinkGDp-CZ8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 14:55:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In a follow-up to her seminal book, "Conscious", Annaka Harris' new audio original documentary offers beginners and experts alike a chance to unravel some of humankind’s most enduring puzzles. Where "Conscious"presents new questions about felt experience, "Lights On" seeks to find the answers.

"Lights On" is available for purchase now: https://amzn.to/4ibk66o

Annaka Harris is the New York Times bestselling author of "Conscious: A Brief Guide to the Fundamental Mystery of the Mind" and writer and producer of the new audio documentary series, "Lights On: How Understanding Consciousness Helps Us Understand the Universe".

Watch more CTT Chats here: https://t.ly/jJI7e

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and produced and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Can AI gain human consciousness?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KL5xGC6wRG0</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KL5xGC6wRG0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch Annaka Harris discuss AI, consciousness, and more in our new interview premiering tomorrow at 11am ET: https://shorturl.at/Al3a4 #shorts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>David Shatz - What is Free Will?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=brQxb_v3KsI</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/brQxb_v3KsI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Like Closer To Truth on Facebook for daily videos, updates, announcements, and much more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

For God to be God, God must be infallible and know the future perfectly, including all my actions from birth to death. For my will to be free, my actions must not be constrained. But if God knows the future – if God literally knows now what I am going to do later – then how are my actions later not constrained? How then free will?

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

David Shatz is an American philosopher and Ronald P. Stanton University Professor of Philosophy at Yeshiva University. He is known for his works on philosophy of religion and ethics.

Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Narendra Modi: Prime Minister of India - Power, Democracy, War &amp; Peace | Lex Fridman Podcast #460</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZPUtA3W-7_I</link><author>Lex Fridman</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZPUtA3W-7_I?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 11:02:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSHZKyawb77ixDdsGog4iWA">Podcast - Lex Fridman</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Narendra Modi is the Prime Minister of India. This episode is available in English, Hindi, Russian (and soon other languages). Captions and voice-over audio tracks are provided (for the main episode video on YouTube) in English, Hindi, Russian, and the original mixed-language version, with subtitles available in your preferred language. To listen to the original mixed-language version, please select the Hindi (Latin) audio track. The default is English overdub. To switch between languages on the main episode YouTube video, click: Settings (Gear Icon) ... Audio Track ... Choose Language. 
Thank you for listening ❤ Check out our sponsors: https://lexfridman.com/sponsors/ep460-sb
See below for timestamps, transcript, and to give feedback, submit questions, contact Lex, etc.

*Transcript:*
https://lexfridman.com/narendra-modi-transcript

*CONTACT LEX:*
*Feedback* - give feedback to Lex: https://lexfridman.com/survey
*AMA* - submit questions, videos or call-in: https://lexfridman.com/ama
*Hiring* - join our team: https://lexfridman.com/hiring
*Other* - other ways to get in touch: https://lexfridman.com/contact

*EXTRA FILES FOR EPISODE:*
If you need captions or videos with audio tracks for clips etc, go here: 
https://lexfridman.com/narendra-modi-files

*HOW TO SWITCH BETWEEN LANGUAGES:*
This episode is available in English, Hindi, Russian (and soon other languages). Captions and voice-over audio tracks are provided (for the main episode video on YouTube) in English, Hindi, Russian, and the original mixed-language version, with subtitles available in your preferred language. To listen to the original mixed-language version, please select the Hindi (Latin) audio track. The default is English overdub. To switch between languages on the main episode YouTube video, click: Settings (Gear Icon) ... Audio Track ... Choose Language.

*EPISODE LINKS:*
Narendra Modi's X: https://x.com/narendramodi
Narendra Modi's Instagram: https://instagram.com/narendramodi
Narendra Modi's YouTube: https://youtube.com/narendramodi
Narendra Modi's Website: https://narendramodi.in/

*SPONSORS:*
To support this podcast, check out our sponsors & get discounts:
*Brain.fm:* Music for focus.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/brainfm-ep460-sb
*Shopify:* Sell stuff online.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/shopify-ep460-sb
*MasterClass:* Online classes from world-class experts.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/masterclass-ep460-sb
*NetSuite:* Business management software.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/netsuite-ep460-sb
*AG1:* All-in-one daily nutrition drinks.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/ag1-ep460-sb
*LMNT:* Zero-sugar electrolyte drink mix.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/lmnt-ep460-sb

*OUTLINE:*
0:00 - In this episode...
3:07 - Introduction
9:19 - Fasting
21:38 - Early life
33:33 - Advice to Young People
39:16 - Journey in the Himalayas
50:45 - Becoming a monk
52:33 - RSS and Hindu nationalism
1:00:17 - Explaining India
1:04:27 - Mahatma Gandhi
1:16:23 - Path to peace in Ukraine
1:19:37 - India and Pakistan
1:25:16 - Cricket and Football
1:29:41 - Donald Trump
1:40:51 - China and Xi Jinping
1:47:56 - Gujarat riots in 2002
2:03:33 - Biggest democracy in the world
2:13:48 - Power
2:18:34 - Hard work
2:21:42 - Srinivasa Ramanujan
2:23:48 - Decision-making process
2:31:35 - AI
2:41:50 - Education
2:52:06 - Learning and focus
2:57:56 - Mantra
2:59:41 - Meditation
3:05:38 - Lex visiting India
3:10:04 - Siddhartha

*PODCAST LINKS:*
- Podcast Website: https://lexfridman.com/podcast
- Apple Podcasts: https://apple.co/2lwqZIr
- Spotify: https://spoti.fi/2nEwCF8
- RSS: https://lexfridman.com/feed/podcast/
- Podcast Playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrAXtmErZgOdP_8GztsuKi9nrraNbKKp4
- Clips Channel: https://www.youtube.com/lexclips

*SOCIAL LINKS:*
- X: https://x.com/lexfridman
- Instagram: https://instagram.com/lexfridman
- TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@lexfridman
- LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/lexfridman
- Facebook: https://facebook.com/lexfridman
- Patreon: https://patreon.com/lexfridman
- Telegram: https://t.me/lexfridman
- Reddit: https://reddit.com/r/lexfridman]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ilaria Puri Purini - Can Art Help Us Grasp Reality?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bQtHmuajjNw</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bQtHmuajjNw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for insights, updates, and more:
https://shorturl.at/twLQn

Great art is transcendent. Its impact reaches far beyond the art itself and the person who created it. Art can help us perceive reality in new ways and give new meaning to the physical world around us. But what makes art—from music and dance to sculpture and architecture—truly transcendent?

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

An art historian, curator, and scholar, Ilaria Puri Purini comes to the Academy from the Contemporary Art Society in London, where she has served as curator of programs, working with contemporary artists across Britain, with a special focus on expanding art-historical narratives and practices.

Shop Closer To Truth merch like notebooks, mugs, and sweatshirts in our online store: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Jeff Schloss - Is the Future Open?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H75dFiJICi0</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/H75dFiJICi0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 19:00:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Show your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Why is an ‘open’ future controversial among theologians? If the future is not ‘settled’, if there is no certainty from God’s viewpoint of how future events will turn out, then God’s providence, could not be as sure. If the future is truly open, then not even God could know the future because there are no future facts to know.

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, perspectives, and more: https://shorturl.at/2eJCn

Jeff Schloss is the Distinguished Professor of Biology, the T.B. Walker Chair of Natural and Behavioral Sciences, and the Director of the Center for Faith, Dr. Schloss has been at Westmont since 1981.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Can clones be conscious?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yoEmLBd9Yj0</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yoEmLBd9Yj0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:01:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Annaka Harris discusses the "nightmare" possibility of clones with a consciousness. Watch our new interview with her premiering Tuesday, March 18 at 11am ET #shorts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2290 - MIchael Kosta</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d4m1MOSI5n8</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/d4m1MOSI5n8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Michael Kosta is a standup comic, host of "The Daily Show," host of his own podcast, "Tennis Anyone," and author. His new book, "Lucky Loser: Adventures in Tennis and Comedy," is available now. 
http://www.michaelkosta.com

Save $20 on your first subscription of AG1 at http://drinkag1.com/joerogan

Visit http://LifeLock.com/JOEROGAN to save up to 40% off.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Denis Alexander - Arguments for Agnosticism?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2TxfsaUHA1g</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2TxfsaUHA1g?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Contrinute any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions without the need for paywalls: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Agnostics do not know whether or not God exists. Theists surmise they’re reprobates. Atheists suppose they’re cowards. Are there different kinds of agnostics? Can agnosticism deepen appreciation for God—what it would take to believe in God and what it would mean if indeed there were a God? A robust, energetic agnosticism is a credit to God if there is one.

Follow Closer To Truth on Instagram for daily updates and exciting announcements: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

Dr. Denis Alexander has spent 40 years in the biomedical research community. He is an Emeritus Fellow of St. Edmund’s College, Cambridge and an Emeritus Director of the Faraday Institute for Science and Religion, Cambridge which he co-founded with Bob White in 2006.

Register for a free Closer To Truth membership to get special exclusives like early access to new episodes, event discounts, and more: https://closertotruth.com/register/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2289 - Darryl Cooper</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DE9oFxGoMvE</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DE9oFxGoMvE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 17:00:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Darryl Cooper is the host of the "Martyr Made" podcast.
http://www.martyrmade.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Christopher Knight - How Should Religion Talk to Science?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eZHGn4ZJa14</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eZHGn4ZJa14?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 15:00:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sign up for a free Closer To Truth membership to receive special exclusives like early access to new episodes and more: https://closertotruth.com/.

To do good theology, religion must speak with science if only to avoid the embarrassment of supernatural explanations when natural explanations are doing just fine. If religion claims to be an approach to the entirety of existence, then it must embed the discoveries and insights of science. Religion has no choice. At its own risk, religion ignores science.

Find Closer To Truth on Instagram for new videos, announcements, and more: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

Christopher Knight, the Executive Secretary of the International Society for Science and Religion, is based at St.Edmund’s College, Cambridge, England, and has been teaching and writing about the dialogue between science and religion for many years. His most recent book is "The God of Nature: Incarnation and Contemporary Science".

Give what you can to support the show and help Closer To Truth continue exploring life's deepest questions: shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>N.T. Wright - How Does Atonement Work?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WeeofBKXLEE</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/WeeofBKXLEE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 19:00:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Shop our special edition merch in honor of the late Steven Weinberg, including mugs and T-shirts: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Christians are accustomed to hearing that “Jesus died for our sins”. But what would that mean literally? How would atonement work? What would be happening? Is there a process, a sequence of logical steps? One need not be a Christian to appreciate the philosophical obstacles.

Follow Closer To Truth on Facebook and discover daily videos, updates, announcements, and more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

Nicholas Thomas Wright FRSE, known as N. T. Wright or Tom Wright, is an English New Testament scholar, Pauline theologian and Anglican bishop. He was the bishop of Durham from 2003 to 2010.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2288 - Jacques Vallée</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vZEcVY2iZsk</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vZEcVY2iZsk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:01:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Jacques Vallée is a venture capitalist, technologist, and prominent figure in the field of unidentified aerial phenomena. His new book is Forbidden Science 6: Scattered Castles, The Journals of Jacques Vallee 2010-2019.
http://www.jacquesvallee.net

This episode is brought to you by Intuit TurboTax. Now this is taxes. Get an expert now at http://TurboTax.com

This video is sponsored by BetterHelp. Visit http://BetterHelp.com/JRE]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Elisabeth Schellekens - Aspects of Consciousness?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SLVjKkmASD8</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SLVjKkmASD8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help support Closer To Truth continue making content like this: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

We offer distinctive approaches to consciousness including cognitive science, phenomenology, and even the implications of aesthetics like fiction and films. We observe the richness of consciousness studies.

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Elisabeth Schellekens is a Swedish philosopher and Chair Professor of Aesthetics at Uppsala University. Previously, she was Senior Lecturer at Durham University. Schellekens is known for her works in aesthetics.

Check out the Closer To Truth merch store for unique items like notebooks, mugs, and hoodies: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why is there something rather than nothing?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w18CHGA6qo8</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/w18CHGA6qo8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 19:00:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Here’s the ultimate question: what if it were true that everything always and forever had been ‘nothing’? Imagine that not a single thing ever existed–not emptiness, not blankness, not even the existence of emptiness, or the meaning of blankness. If you can image that, now ask yourself: why is there anything at all? Philosopher John Leslie shares his philosophy. #shorts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2287 - Josh Dubin &amp; J.D. Tomlinson</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mx8813RLUtc</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Mx8813RLUtc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Josh Dubin is the Executive Director of the Perlmutter Center for Legal Justice, a criminal justice reform advocate, and civil rights attorney.
https://cardozo.yu.edu/directory/josh-dubin

J.D. Tomlinson is a lawyer and was previously Lorain County Prosecutor in Ohio.

https://www.freetheohio4.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Samir Okasha - Philosophy of Biology: Classifying Species &amp; Individuals</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZysBYH6Tkg8</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZysBYH6Tkg8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, new videos, musings, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

What is the classification system in biology, the taxonomy used to categorize organisms in a structured hierarchy? What are species and individuals in biological and evolutionary contexts, and what is the relationship between them?

Get member exclusives like early access to new content with a free Closer To Truth account: https://closertotruth.com/

Samir Okasha FBA, is a Professor of Philosophy of Science at University of Bristol. He was appointed a Fellow of the British Academy in 2018.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nancey Murphy - Arguing God from Moral Law?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kaBAxG6jxPU</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kaBAxG6jxPU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:01:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Like us on Facebook for daily videos, updates, announcements, and much more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

Humans have a sense of right and wrong. Does this mean that morality is absolute? And if it’s absolute, would God be needed to make it so? These are separate questions and both require particular answers to arrive at God. Even theologians are perplexed by God and morality; some even admit it.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Nancey Murphy is a philosopher and theologian who is Professor of Christian Philosophy at Fuller Theological Seminary in Pasadena, CA. She received a B.A. from Creighton University, a Ph.D. from University of California, Berkeley, and a Th.D. from the Graduate Theological Union.

Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Robert John Russell - Does a Fine-Tuned Universe Lead to God?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z6M5xCvlzFE</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Z6M5xCvlzFE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Contribute what you can to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

We human beings sit roughly midway between the sizes of atoms and galaxies, and both must be so perfectly structured for us to exist. It’s called ‘fine-tuning’ and it’s all so breathtakingly precise that it cries out for explanation. To some, fine-tuning leads to God. To others, there are non-supernatural explanations. Both are startling.

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Robert John Russell is founder and Director of the Center for Theology and the Natural Sciences. He is also the Ian G. Barbour Professor of Theology and Science in Residence at the Graduate Theological Union. He has written and edited extensively on possible scientific mechanisms of Christian belief. 

Browse Closer To Truth merch like notebooks, mugs, and sweatshirts in our online store: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Tom McLeish - Cosmology and Creation</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FwU_xc3VYZ4</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FwU_xc3VYZ4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 8 Mar 2025 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Show your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

How do physicists and philosophers who believe in God harmonize the discoveries of cosmology with the doctrine of creation? How does cosmology enhance or erode their belief in God? If God exists, must the universe have had a beginning? Conversely, if the universe had a beginning, must God exist?

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, perspectives, and more: https://shorturl.at/2eJCn

Thomas Charles Buckland was a British theoretical physicist. His work is renowned for increasing understanding of the properties of soft matter, which matter that can be easily changed by stress—including liquids, foams and biological materials. He was a professor in the Durham University Department of Physics and director of the Durham Centre for Soft Matter, a multidisciplinary team that works across physics, chemistry, mathematics and engineering. He also was the first Chair of Natural Philosophy at the University of York.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>