<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Podcasts</title><link>https://securenza.github.io/SecurityFeed/</link><description></description><item><title>Etzel Cardeña - Consciousness and Life After Death?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ac9ZhnFbeQE</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ac9ZhnFbeQE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get member exclusives like early access to new content with a free Closer To Truth account: https://closertotruth.com/

Life after death is explored in the context of diverse theories of consciousness, from strict materialism/physicalism to those of ancient wisdom traditions. We explore the view that the haunting and deeply personal question of life after death relates to theories of consciousness.

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, new videos, musings, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

Etzel Cardeña holds the Thorsen Chair in psychology including parapsychology and hypnosis at Lund University, Sweden. He was elected Fellow of the American Psychological Association (APA) and the Association for Psychological Science (APS), among other organizations. His research, theoretical, historical, and pedagogical contributions have received 25 awards from various academic and professional organizations.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Richard Dawkins - Philosophy of Extended Evolutionary Synthesis</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JOul25KphBE</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JOul25KphBE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 15:00:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for insights, updates, and more: https://shorturl.at/twLQn

What is the extended evolutionary synthesis (EES) and why better? Includes multilevel selection, transgenerational epigenetic inheritance, niche construction, evolvability, and ideas from evolutionary developmental biology. Why is EES controversial?

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Richard Dawkins is a British evolutionary biologist, zoologist, science communicator, and author. He is an emeritus fellow of New College, Oxford, and was Professor for Public Understanding of Science in the University of Oxford

Shop Closer To Truth merchandise like notebooks, mugs, and sweatshirts in our online store: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>JRE Fight Companion - March 22, 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xr-DqSmJEXI</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Xr-DqSmJEXI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 18:45:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Joe is joined by Gordon Ryan, Brendan Schaub & Eddie Bravo to watch the fights on March 22, 2025.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ThePrimeagen: Programming, AI, ADHD, Productivity, Addiction, and God | Lex Fridman Podcast #461</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tNZnLkRBYA8</link><author>Lex Fridman</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tNZnLkRBYA8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 17:15:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSHZKyawb77ixDdsGog4iWA">Podcast - Lex Fridman</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ThePrimeagen (aka Michael Paulson) is a programmer who has educated, entertained, and inspired millions of people to build software and have fun doing it.
Thank you for listening ❤ Check out our sponsors: https://lexfridman.com/sponsors/ep461-sb
See below for timestamps, transcript, and to give feedback, submit questions, contact Lex, etc.

*Transcript:*
https://lexfridman.com/theprimeagen-transcript

*CONTACT LEX:*
*Feedback* - give feedback to Lex: https://lexfridman.com/survey
*AMA* - submit questions, videos or call-in: https://lexfridman.com/ama
*Hiring* - join our team: https://lexfridman.com/hiring
*Other* - other ways to get in touch: https://lexfridman.com/contact

*SMALL CORRECTION NOTE:*
When Prime talks about how grateful he is for his amazing wife and family, we show an incorrect photo, so I blurred it. Here's some correct ones:
https://x.com/ThePrimeagen/status/1586458511810080769
https://x.com/ThePrimeagen/status/1771638039430771125

*EPISODE LINKS:*
ThePrimeagen's X: https://twitter.com/ThePrimeagen
ThePrimeagen's YouTube: https://youtube.com/ThePrimeTimeagen
ThePrimeagen's Twitch: https://twitch.tv/ThePrimeagen
ThePrimeagen's GitHub: https://github.com/theprimeagen
ThePrimeagen's TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@theprimeagen
ThePrimeagen's Coffee: https://www.terminal.shop/

*SPONSORS:*
To support this podcast, check out our sponsors & get discounts:
*Invideo AI:* AI video generator.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/invideoai-ep461-sb
*Shopify:* Sell stuff online.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/shopify-ep461-sb
*NetSuite:* Business management software.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/netsuite-ep461-sb
*BetterHelp:* Online therapy and counseling.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/betterhelp-ep461-sb
*AG1:* All-in-one daily nutrition drinks.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/ag1-ep461-sb

*OUTLINE:*
0:00 - Introduction
0:42 - Love for programming
10:15 - Hardest part of programming
12:31 - Types of programming
20:08 - Life story
30:12 - Hardship
31:44 - High school
37:30 - Porn addiction
47:16 - God
1:02:59 - Perseverance
1:12:55 - Netflix
1:25:23 - Groovy
1:30:27 - Printf() debugging
1:36:49 - Falcor
1:46:19 - Breaking production
1:49:04 - Pieter Levels
1:53:34 - Netflix, Twitch, and YouTube infrastructure
2:05:36 - ThePrimeagen origin story
2:20:52 - Learning programming languages
2:29:55 - Best programming languages in 2025
2:34:50 - Python
2:35:30 - HTML & CSS
2:36:20 - Bash
2:37:00 - FFmpeg
2:43:42 - Performance
2:46:15 - Rust
2:51:03 - Epic projects
3:04:27 - Asserts
3:13:41 - ADHD
3:21:49 - Productivity
3:26:13 - Programming setup
4:01:43 - Coffee
4:08:47 - Programming with AI
4:51:31 - Advice for young programmers
5:03:03 - Reddit questions
5:10:35 - God

*PODCAST LINKS:*
- Podcast Website: https://lexfridman.com/podcast
- Apple Podcasts: https://apple.co/2lwqZIr
- Spotify: https://spoti.fi/2nEwCF8
- RSS: https://lexfridman.com/feed/podcast/
- Podcast Playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrAXtmErZgOdP_8GztsuKi9nrraNbKKp4
- Clips Channel: https://www.youtube.com/lexclips

*SOCIAL LINKS:*
- X: https://x.com/lexfridman
- Instagram: https://instagram.com/lexfridman
- TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@lexfridman
- LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/lexfridman
- Facebook: https://facebook.com/lexfridman
- Patreon: https://patreon.com/lexfridman
- Telegram: https://t.me/lexfridman
- Reddit: https://reddit.com/r/lexfridman]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Denis Alexander - Fallacies in Proving God Exists?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S_HoOa4DZfk</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/S_HoOa4DZfk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 15:00:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Like us on Facebook for daily videos, updates, announcements, and much more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

The more we want God to exist, the more we must question so-called ‘proofs’ of God’s existence. God likely appreciates skeptics, those who genuinely seek and genuinely doubt. Skeptics provide real service: they help clear up or clean out poor arguments for God. Is it possible all the ‘God arguments’ are bad?

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Dr. Denis Alexander has spent 40 years in the biomedical research community. He is an Emeritus Fellow of St. Edmund’s College, Cambridge and an Emeritus Director of the Faraday Institute for Science and Religion, Cambridge which he co-founded with Bob White in 2006. 

Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dean Zimmerman - Are There Multiple Universes?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2OkCw-3h94Q</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2OkCw-3h94Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 19:00:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

What is the extent of God’s creation? If there are multiple universes, did God create each of them? If an infinite number of universes, did God create all of them? Theists may be conflicted: the centrality of human beings in this one universe, and, for Christians, the incarnation on Earth, versus the magnification of God with multiple universes.

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, perspectives, and more: https://shorturl.at/2eJCn

Dean W. Zimmerman is an American professor of philosophy at Rutgers University specializing in metaphysics and philosophy of religion.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2293 - Chris Williamson</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MjhXtJB_ZbU</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MjhXtJB_ZbU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 17:00:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Chris Williamson is the host of the "Modern Wisdom" podcast 
https://chriswillx.com/modernwisdom

This video is sponsored by BetterHelp. Visit http://BetterHelp.com/JRE for 90% off your first week.

Don’t miss out on all the action - Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using http://dkng.co/rogan or with my promo code ROGAN.

GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit http://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit http://ccpg.org (CT), or visit http://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD). 21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS). 1 per new customer. $5+ first-time bet req. Max. $200 issued as non-withdrawable Bonus Bets that expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: http://dkng.co/dk-offer-terms. Ends 3/30/25 at 11:59 PM ET.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Robert Saucy - A New Heaven &amp; A New Earth?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=81Zr18gxDgw</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/81Zr18gxDgw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 15:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Contribute what you can to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions without the need for paywalls: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

‘A new heaven and a new earth’ is the grand vision of the Bible. The Judeo-Christian scriptures tell of a future time when all things shall be made new. What could this mean? Does ‘all’ include the entire cosmos? Multiple universes, if there are such? Could such an ancient vision ever make sense? Believers say, “It’s God’s mystery.” They should say more.

Follow Closer To Truth on Instagram for daily updates and exciting announcements: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

Robert Lloyd Saucy was an American biblical scholar and professor of systematic theology.

Register for a free Closer To Truth membership to get special exclusives like early access to new episodes, event discounts, and more: https://closertotruth.com/register/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Liad Mudrik - Theories of Consciousness</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=07_DG3SOyfs</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/07_DG3SOyfs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sign up for a free Closer To Truth membership to receive special exclusives like early access to new episodes and more: https://closertotruth.com/.

Explore diverse theories of consciousness including materialism, dualism, panpsychism, idealism and diverse ways of thinking about consciousness from the perspectives of neuroscience, philosophy, wisdom traditions. Compare and contrast diverse theories of consciousness as they are arrayed on a “Landscape of Consciousness”.

Follow Closer To Truth on Instagram for new videos, announcements, and more: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

Professor Liad Mudrik is a researcher at the school of psychological sciences and Sagol school of neuroscience at Tel Aviv University. Her research focuses on conscious experience, its neural mechanisms and functions.

Contribute what you can to support the show and help Closer To Truth continue exploring life's deepest questions: shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Massimo Pigliucci - Biology, Race, and Ethnicity</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uXsFTm-ko2w</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/uXsFTm-ko2w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:00:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Shop our special edition merch in honor of the late Steven Weinberg, including mugs and T-shirts: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Race is obviously real—historically, socially, politically. What about biologically? What’s the relationship between color and race? Are human races subspecies of homo sapiens? Is race a “natural kind?” How to form a coherent theory of race?

Like Closer To Truth on Facebook and discover daily videos, updates, announcements, and more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

Massimo Pigliucci is an American philosopher and biologist who is professor of philosophy at the City College of New York, former co-host of the Rationally Speaking podcast, and former editor in chief for the online magazine Scientia Salon.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Annaka Harris: Conversations on Consciousness | Closer To Truth Chats</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5ULTkSgqYxg</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5ULTkSgqYxg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 17:17:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In the second part of our extensive interview with Annaka Harris, we trace the
arc of her new documentary's journey by going through each chapter and exploring the experts she interviewed for the project—including Sean Carroll, Brian Greene, Janna Levin, Philip Goff, and many more.

Annaka Harris is the New York Times bestselling author of "Conscious: A Brief Guide to the Fundamental Mystery of the Mind" and writer and producer of the new audio documentary series, "Lights On: How Understanding Consciousness Helps Us Understand the Universe".

Watch more CTT Chats here: https://t.ly/jJI7e

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and produced and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2292 - Josh Waitzkin</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xsqbdBiidWE</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/xsqbdBiidWE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 17:01:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Josh Waitzkin is a retired chess champion, martial artist, author, and foil surfer.
http://www.joshwaitzkin.com

This episode is brought to you by Intuit TurboTax. Now this is taxes. Get an expert now at http://TurboTax.com

Don’t miss out on all the action - Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using http://dkng.co/rogan or with my promo code ROGAN.

GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit http://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit http://ccpg.org (CT), or visit http://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD). 21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS). 1 per new customer. $5+ first-time bet req. Max. $200 issued as non-withdrawable Bonus Bets that expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: http://dkng.co/dk-offer-terms. Ends 3/30/25 at 11:59 PM ET.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Michael Almeida - Can Metaphysics Discern God?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WmjzYj8_wG0</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/WmjzYj8_wG0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help support Closer To Truth continue making content like this: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Metaphysics is the deepest probe of reality. It is the branch of philosophy that discerns the most general features of the world. When focused on God, metaphysics seeks insights not readily apparent, such as possible contradictions (or coherence) among various traits of God. Other topics include tensions between God and time, and God and abstract objects.

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Mike Almeida is Professor of Philosophy and chair of the Department of Philosophy and Classics at the University of Texas at San Antonio.

Check out the Closer To Truth merch store for unique items like notebooks, mugs, and hoodies: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2291 - Bert Kreischer</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FjaGb87pjMc</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FjaGb87pjMc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 17:00:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Bert Kreischer is a stand-up comic, podcaster, and actor. He's the host of "The Bertcast" podcast and YouTube cooking program "Something's Burning." He's also the co-host of the "2 Bears, 1 Cave" podcast with fellow comedian Tom Segura. Watch his latest special, "Lucky," on Netflix. 
http://www.bertbertbert.com

Go to http://ExpressVPN.com/ROGANYT to get 4 months free!

Save $20 on your first subscription of AG1 at http://drinkag1.com/joerogan]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>David Bentley Hart - Can Many Religions All Be True?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LNVJeo-SppQ</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LNVJeo-SppQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:00:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get member exclusives like early access to new content with a free Closer To Truth account: https://closertotruth.com/

Conflicting religions fill the world. Doctrines about God contradict one another. No one denies the diversity of religions and the apparent incompatibility of their core beliefs. Many believe only their own religion to be the truth. Some claim all religions reflect the same truth. Others assert that differing dogmas expose the emptiness of all religion.

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, new videos, musings, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

David Bentley Hart is an American philosopher, theologian, essayist, cultural commentator, fiction author, religious studies scholar. Reviewers have commented on Hart's baroque prose and provocative rhetoric in over one thousand essays, reviews, and papers as well as twenty-four books.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Annaka Harris Explores Consciousness and the Cosmos | Closer To Truth Chats</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jinkGDp-CZ8</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/jinkGDp-CZ8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 14:55:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In a follow-up to her seminal book, "Conscious", Annaka Harris' new audio original documentary offers beginners and experts alike a chance to unravel some of humankind’s most enduring puzzles. Where "Conscious"presents new questions about felt experience, "Lights On" seeks to find the answers.

"Lights On" is available for purchase now: https://amzn.to/4ibk66o

Annaka Harris is the New York Times bestselling author of "Conscious: A Brief Guide to the Fundamental Mystery of the Mind" and writer and producer of the new audio documentary series, "Lights On: How Understanding Consciousness Helps Us Understand the Universe".

Watch more CTT Chats here: https://t.ly/jJI7e

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and produced and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Can AI gain human consciousness?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KL5xGC6wRG0</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KL5xGC6wRG0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch Annaka Harris discuss AI, consciousness, and more in our new interview premiering tomorrow at 11am ET: https://shorturl.at/Al3a4 #shorts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>David Shatz - What is Free Will?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=brQxb_v3KsI</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/brQxb_v3KsI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Like Closer To Truth on Facebook for daily videos, updates, announcements, and much more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

For God to be God, God must be infallible and know the future perfectly, including all my actions from birth to death. For my will to be free, my actions must not be constrained. But if God knows the future – if God literally knows now what I am going to do later – then how are my actions later not constrained? How then free will?

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

David Shatz is an American philosopher and Ronald P. Stanton University Professor of Philosophy at Yeshiva University. He is known for his works on philosophy of religion and ethics.

Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Narendra Modi: Prime Minister of India - Power, Democracy, War &amp; Peace | Lex Fridman Podcast #460</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZPUtA3W-7_I</link><author>Lex Fridman</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZPUtA3W-7_I?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 11:02:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSHZKyawb77ixDdsGog4iWA">Podcast - Lex Fridman</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Narendra Modi is the Prime Minister of India. This episode is available in English, Hindi, Russian (and soon other languages). Captions and voice-over audio tracks are provided (for the main episode video on YouTube) in English, Hindi, Russian, and the original mixed-language version, with subtitles available in your preferred language. To listen to the original mixed-language version, please select the Hindi (Latin) audio track. The default is English overdub. To switch between languages on the main episode YouTube video, click: Settings (Gear Icon) ... Audio Track ... Choose Language. 
Thank you for listening ❤ Check out our sponsors: https://lexfridman.com/sponsors/ep460-sb
See below for timestamps, transcript, and to give feedback, submit questions, contact Lex, etc.

*Transcript:*
https://lexfridman.com/narendra-modi-transcript

*CONTACT LEX:*
*Feedback* - give feedback to Lex: https://lexfridman.com/survey
*AMA* - submit questions, videos or call-in: https://lexfridman.com/ama
*Hiring* - join our team: https://lexfridman.com/hiring
*Other* - other ways to get in touch: https://lexfridman.com/contact

*EXTRA FILES FOR EPISODE:*
If you need captions or videos with audio tracks for clips etc, go here: 
https://lexfridman.com/narendra-modi-files

*HOW TO SWITCH BETWEEN LANGUAGES:*
This episode is available in English, Hindi, Russian (and soon other languages). Captions and voice-over audio tracks are provided (for the main episode video on YouTube) in English, Hindi, Russian, and the original mixed-language version, with subtitles available in your preferred language. To listen to the original mixed-language version, please select the Hindi (Latin) audio track. The default is English overdub. To switch between languages on the main episode YouTube video, click: Settings (Gear Icon) ... Audio Track ... Choose Language.

*EPISODE LINKS:*
Narendra Modi's X: https://x.com/narendramodi
Narendra Modi's Instagram: https://instagram.com/narendramodi
Narendra Modi's YouTube: https://youtube.com/narendramodi
Narendra Modi's Website: https://narendramodi.in/

*SPONSORS:*
To support this podcast, check out our sponsors & get discounts:
*Brain.fm:* Music for focus.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/brainfm-ep460-sb
*Shopify:* Sell stuff online.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/shopify-ep460-sb
*MasterClass:* Online classes from world-class experts.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/masterclass-ep460-sb
*NetSuite:* Business management software.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/netsuite-ep460-sb
*AG1:* All-in-one daily nutrition drinks.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/ag1-ep460-sb
*LMNT:* Zero-sugar electrolyte drink mix.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/lmnt-ep460-sb

*OUTLINE:*
0:00 - In this episode...
3:07 - Introduction
9:19 - Fasting
21:38 - Early life
33:33 - Advice to Young People
39:16 - Journey in the Himalayas
50:45 - Becoming a monk
52:33 - RSS and Hindu nationalism
1:00:17 - Explaining India
1:04:27 - Mahatma Gandhi
1:16:23 - Path to peace in Ukraine
1:19:37 - India and Pakistan
1:25:16 - Cricket and Football
1:29:41 - Donald Trump
1:40:51 - China and Xi Jinping
1:47:56 - Gujarat riots in 2002
2:03:33 - Biggest democracy in the world
2:13:48 - Power
2:18:34 - Hard work
2:21:42 - Srinivasa Ramanujan
2:23:48 - Decision-making process
2:31:35 - AI
2:41:50 - Education
2:52:06 - Learning and focus
2:57:56 - Mantra
2:59:41 - Meditation
3:05:38 - Lex visiting India
3:10:04 - Siddhartha

*PODCAST LINKS:*
- Podcast Website: https://lexfridman.com/podcast
- Apple Podcasts: https://apple.co/2lwqZIr
- Spotify: https://spoti.fi/2nEwCF8
- RSS: https://lexfridman.com/feed/podcast/
- Podcast Playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrAXtmErZgOdP_8GztsuKi9nrraNbKKp4
- Clips Channel: https://www.youtube.com/lexclips

*SOCIAL LINKS:*
- X: https://x.com/lexfridman
- Instagram: https://instagram.com/lexfridman
- TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@lexfridman
- LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/lexfridman
- Facebook: https://facebook.com/lexfridman
- Patreon: https://patreon.com/lexfridman
- Telegram: https://t.me/lexfridman
- Reddit: https://reddit.com/r/lexfridman]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ilaria Puri Purini - Can Art Help Us Grasp Reality?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bQtHmuajjNw</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bQtHmuajjNw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for insights, updates, and more:
https://shorturl.at/twLQn

Great art is transcendent. Its impact reaches far beyond the art itself and the person who created it. Art can help us perceive reality in new ways and give new meaning to the physical world around us. But what makes art—from music and dance to sculpture and architecture—truly transcendent?

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

An art historian, curator, and scholar, Ilaria Puri Purini comes to the Academy from the Contemporary Art Society in London, where she has served as curator of programs, working with contemporary artists across Britain, with a special focus on expanding art-historical narratives and practices.

Shop Closer To Truth merch like notebooks, mugs, and sweatshirts in our online store: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>