<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Podcasts</title><link>http://site-url-not-set.io/you-can-set-it-in-liveboat-config</link><description></description><item><title>David Shatz - What is Free Will?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=brQxb_v3KsI</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/brQxb_v3KsI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Like Closer To Truth on Facebook for daily videos, updates, announcements, and much more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

For God to be God, God must be infallible and know the future perfectly, including all my actions from birth to death. For my will to be free, my actions must not be constrained. But if God knows the future – if God literally knows now what I am going to do later – then how are my actions later not constrained? How then free will?

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

David Shatz is an American philosopher and Ronald P. Stanton University Professor of Philosophy at Yeshiva University. He is known for his works on philosophy of religion and ethics.

Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Narendra Modi: Prime Minister of India - Power, Democracy, War &amp; Peace | Lex Fridman Podcast #460</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZPUtA3W-7_I</link><author>Lex Fridman</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZPUtA3W-7_I?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 11:02:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSHZKyawb77ixDdsGog4iWA">Podcast - Lex Fridman</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Narendra Modi is the Prime Minister of India. This episode is available in English, Hindi, Russian (and soon other languages). Captions and voice-over audio tracks are provided (for the main episode video on YouTube) in English, Hindi, Russian, and the original mixed-language version, with subtitles available in your preferred language. To listen to the original mixed-language version, please select the Hindi (Latin) audio track. The default is English overdub. To switch between languages on the main episode YouTube video, click: Settings (Gear Icon) ... Audio Track ... Choose Language. 
Thank you for listening ❤ Check out our sponsors: https://lexfridman.com/sponsors/ep460-sb
See below for timestamps, transcript, and to give feedback, submit questions, contact Lex, etc.

*Transcript:*
https://lexfridman.com/narendra-modi-transcript

*CONTACT LEX:*
*Feedback* - give feedback to Lex: https://lexfridman.com/survey
*AMA* - submit questions, videos or call-in: https://lexfridman.com/ama
*Hiring* - join our team: https://lexfridman.com/hiring
*Other* - other ways to get in touch: https://lexfridman.com/contact

*EXTRA FILES FOR EPISODE:*
If you need captions or videos with audio tracks for clips etc, go here: 
https://lexfridman.com/narendra-modi-files

*HOW TO SWITCH BETWEEN LANGUAGES:*
This episode is available in English, Hindi, Russian (and soon other languages). Captions and voice-over audio tracks are provided (for the main episode video on YouTube) in English, Hindi, Russian, and the original mixed-language version, with subtitles available in your preferred language. To listen to the original mixed-language version, please select the Hindi (Latin) audio track. The default is English overdub. To switch between languages on the main episode YouTube video, click: Settings (Gear Icon) ... Audio Track ... Choose Language.

*EPISODE LINKS:*
Narendra Modi's X: https://x.com/narendramodi
Narendra Modi's Instagram: https://instagram.com/narendramodi
Narendra Modi's YouTube: https://youtube.com/narendramodi
Narendra Modi's Website: https://narendramodi.in/

*SPONSORS:*
To support this podcast, check out our sponsors & get discounts:
*Brain.fm:* Music for focus.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/brainfm-ep460-sb
*Shopify:* Sell stuff online.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/shopify-ep460-sb
*MasterClass:* Online classes from world-class experts.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/masterclass-ep460-sb
*NetSuite:* Business management software.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/netsuite-ep460-sb
*AG1:* All-in-one daily nutrition drinks.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/ag1-ep460-sb
*LMNT:* Zero-sugar electrolyte drink mix.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/lmnt-ep460-sb

*OUTLINE:*
0:00 - In this episode...
3:07 - Introduction
9:19 - Fasting
21:38 - Early life
33:33 - Advice to Young People
39:16 - Journey in the Himalayas
50:45 - Becoming a monk
52:33 - RSS and Hindu nationalism
1:00:17 - Explaining India
1:04:27 - Mahatma Gandhi
1:16:23 - Path to peace in Ukraine
1:19:37 - India and Pakistan
1:25:16 - Cricket and Football
1:29:41 - Donald Trump
1:40:51 - China and Xi Jinping
1:47:56 - Gujarat riots in 2002
2:03:33 - Biggest democracy in the world
2:13:48 - Power
2:18:34 - Hard work
2:21:42 - Srinivasa Ramanujan
2:23:48 - Decision-making process
2:31:35 - AI
2:41:50 - Education
2:52:06 - Learning and focus
2:57:56 - Mantra
2:59:41 - Meditation
3:05:38 - Lex visiting India
3:10:04 - Siddhartha

*PODCAST LINKS:*
- Podcast Website: https://lexfridman.com/podcast
- Apple Podcasts: https://apple.co/2lwqZIr
- Spotify: https://spoti.fi/2nEwCF8
- RSS: https://lexfridman.com/feed/podcast/
- Podcast Playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrAXtmErZgOdP_8GztsuKi9nrraNbKKp4
- Clips Channel: https://www.youtube.com/lexclips

*SOCIAL LINKS:*
- X: https://x.com/lexfridman
- Instagram: https://instagram.com/lexfridman
- TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@lexfridman
- LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/lexfridman
- Facebook: https://facebook.com/lexfridman
- Patreon: https://patreon.com/lexfridman
- Telegram: https://t.me/lexfridman
- Reddit: https://reddit.com/r/lexfridman]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ilaria Puri Purini - Can Art Help Us Grasp Reality?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bQtHmuajjNw</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bQtHmuajjNw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for insights, updates, and more:
https://shorturl.at/twLQn

Great art is transcendent. Its impact reaches far beyond the art itself and the person who created it. Art can help us perceive reality in new ways and give new meaning to the physical world around us. But what makes art—from music and dance to sculpture and architecture—truly transcendent?

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

An art historian, curator, and scholar, Ilaria Puri Purini comes to the Academy from the Contemporary Art Society in London, where she has served as curator of programs, working with contemporary artists across Britain, with a special focus on expanding art-historical narratives and practices.

Shop Closer To Truth merch like notebooks, mugs, and sweatshirts in our online store: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Friends on the Frontend (Friends)</title><link>https://changelog.com/friends/84</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/friends/84/changelog--friends-84.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Adam’s friend on the frontend, John Long joins the show to explore his usage of AI, design tools and the stack he prefers. We talk Next.js vs Rails, maintaining open source, building websites with Framer, their mutual love for Figma, and more.Changelog++ members save 9 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelogAugment Code – Developer AI that uses deep understanding of your large codebase and how you build software to deliver personalized code suggestions and insights. Augment provides relevant, contextualized code right in your IDE or Slack. It transforms scattered knowledge into code or answers, eliminating time spent searching docs or interrupting teammates.
Temporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps close to your users — global Anycast load-balancing, zero-configuration private networking, hardware isolation, and instant WireGuard VPN connections. Push-button deployments that scale to thousands of instances. Check out the speedrun to get started in minutes.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Jeff Schloss - Is the Future Open?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H75dFiJICi0</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/H75dFiJICi0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 19:00:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Show your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Why is an ‘open’ future controversial among theologians? If the future is not ‘settled’, if there is no certainty from God’s viewpoint of how future events will turn out, then God’s providence, could not be as sure. If the future is truly open, then not even God could know the future because there are no future facts to know.

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, perspectives, and more: https://shorturl.at/2eJCn

Jeff Schloss is the Distinguished Professor of Biology, the T.B. Walker Chair of Natural and Behavioral Sciences, and the Director of the Center for Faith, Dr. Schloss has been at Westmont since 1981.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>GenAI Traffic: Why API Infrastructure Must Evolve... Again // Erica Hughberg // #296</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/GenAI-Traffic-Why-API-Infrastructure-Must-Evolve----Again--Erica-Hughberg--296-e30613k</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/99861044/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2025-2-14%2F396583502-44100-2-a81df2c45cdcf.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 18:01:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Are clones conscious?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yoEmLBd9Yj0</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yoEmLBd9Yj0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:01:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Annaka Harris discusses the "nightmare" possibility of clones with a consciousness. Watch our new interview with her premiering Tuesday, March 18 at 11am ET #shorts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2290 - MIchael Kosta</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d4m1MOSI5n8</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/d4m1MOSI5n8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Michael Kosta is a standup comic, host of "The Daily Show," host of his own podcast, "Tennis Anyone," and author. His new book, "Lucky Loser: Adventures in Tennis and Comedy," is available now. 
http://www.michaelkosta.com

Save $20 on your first subscription of AG1 at http://drinkag1.com/joerogan

Visit http://LifeLock.com/JOEROGAN to save up to 40% off.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Denis Alexander - Arguments for Agnosticism?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2TxfsaUHA1g</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2TxfsaUHA1g?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Contrinute any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions without the need for paywalls: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Agnostics do not know whether or not God exists. Theists surmise they’re reprobates. Atheists suppose they’re cowards. Are there different kinds of agnostics? Can agnosticism deepen appreciation for God—what it would take to believe in God and what it would mean if indeed there were a God? A robust, energetic agnosticism is a credit to God if there is one.

Follow Closer To Truth on Instagram for daily updates and exciting announcements: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

Dr. Denis Alexander has spent 40 years in the biomedical research community. He is an Emeritus Fellow of St. Edmund’s College, Cambridge and an Emeritus Director of the Faraday Institute for Science and Religion, Cambridge which he co-founded with Bob White in 2006.

Register for a free Closer To Truth membership to get special exclusives like early access to new episodes, event discounts, and more: https://closertotruth.com/register/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>THE LEADERS: Mussolini</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-leaders-mussolini</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/67cae84f55101d9644bc2cac/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=nGC7HSGEk7T199D1el4yox4TU_6lL08deFqVEMoaCKQ" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2289 - Darryl Cooper</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DE9oFxGoMvE</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DE9oFxGoMvE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 17:00:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Darryl Cooper is the host of the "Martyr Made" podcast.
http://www.martyrmade.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Christopher Knight - How Should Religion Talk to Science?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eZHGn4ZJa14</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eZHGn4ZJa14?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 15:00:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sign up for a free Closer To Truth membership to receive special exclusives like early access to new episodes and more: https://closertotruth.com/.

To do good theology, religion must speak with science if only to avoid the embarrassment of supernatural explanations when natural explanations are doing just fine. If religion claims to be an approach to the entirety of existence, then it must embed the discoveries and insights of science. Religion has no choice. At its own risk, religion ignores science.

Find Closer To Truth on Instagram for new videos, announcements, and more: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

Christopher Knight, the Executive Secretary of the International Society for Science and Religion, is based at St.Edmund’s College, Cambridge, England, and has been teaching and writing about the dialogue between science and religion for many years. His most recent book is "The God of Nature: Incarnation and Contemporary Science".

Give what you can to support the show and help Closer To Truth continue exploring life's deepest questions: shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Quantum Computing at Rigetti with David Rivas</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2025/03/13/quantum-computing-at-rigetti-with-david-rivas/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=quantum-computing-at-rigetti-with-david-rivas</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED4292642620.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 09:00:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Rigetti Computing is an American company specializing in quantum computing, founded in 2013. The company develops quantum processors and hybrid quantum-classical computing systems, and aims to make quantum computing more accessible for research and commercial applications.David Rivas is the CTO at Rigetti Computing. He joins the podcast with Kevin Ball to talk about the company, the fundamentals of quantum computing, the state of the technology, and where we’re headed.Kevin Ball or KBall, is the vice president of engineering at Mento and an independent coach for engineers and engineering leaders. He co-founded and served as CTO for two companies, founded the San Diego JavaScript meetup, and organizes the AI inaction discussion group through Latent Space.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Reaching industrial economies of scale (Interview)</title><link>https://changelog.com/podcast/632</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/podcast/632/the-changelog-632.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Beyang Liu, the CTO & Co-founder of Sourcegraph is back on the pod. Adam and Beyang go deep on the idea of “industrializing software development” using AI agents, using AI in general, using code generation. So much is happening in and around AI and Sourcegraph continues to innovate again and again. From their editor assistant called Cody, to Code Search, to AI agents, to Batch Changes, they’re really helping software teams to industrialize the process, the inner and the outer loop, of being a software developer on high performance teams with large codebases.Changelog++ members get a bonus 9 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelogAugment Code – Developer AI that uses deep understanding of your large codebase and how you build software to deliver personalized code suggestions and insights. Augment provides relevant, contextualized code right in your IDE or Slack. It transforms scattered knowledge into code or answers, eliminating time spent searching docs or interrupting teammates.
Temporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps close to your users — global Anycast load-balancing, zero-configuration private networking, hardware isolation, and instant WireGuard VPN connections. Push-button deployments that scale to thousands of instances. Check out the speedrun to get started in minutes.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>N.T. Wright - How Does Atonement Work?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WeeofBKXLEE</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/WeeofBKXLEE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 19:00:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Shop our special edition merch in honor of the late Steven Weinberg, including mugs and T-shirts: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Christians are accustomed to hearing that “Jesus died for our sins”. But what would that mean literally? How would atonement work? What would be happening? Is there a process, a sequence of logical steps? One need not be a Christian to appreciate the philosophical obstacles.

Follow Closer To Truth on Facebook and discover daily videos, updates, announcements, and more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

Nicholas Thomas Wright FRSE, known as N. T. Wright or Tom Wright, is an English New Testament scholar, Pauline theologian and Anglican bishop. He was the bishop of Durham from 2003 to 2010.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2288 - Jacques Vallée</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vZEcVY2iZsk</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vZEcVY2iZsk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 17:01:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Jacques Vallée is a venture capitalist, technologist, and prominent figure in the field of unidentified aerial phenomena. His new book is Forbidden Science 6: Scattered Castles, The Journals of Jacques Vallee 2010-2019.
http://www.jacquesvallee.net

This episode is brought to you by Intuit TurboTax. Now this is taxes. Get an expert now at http://TurboTax.com

This video is sponsored by BetterHelp. Visit http://BetterHelp.com/JRE]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Elisabeth Schellekens - Aspects of Consciousness?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SLVjKkmASD8</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SLVjKkmASD8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help support Closer To Truth continue making content like this: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

We offer distinctive approaches to consciousness including cognitive science, phenomenology, and even the implications of aesthetics like fiction and films. We observe the richness of consciousness studies.

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Elisabeth Schellekens is a Swedish philosopher and Chair Professor of Aesthetics at Uppsala University. Previously, she was Senior Lecturer at Durham University. Schellekens is known for her works in aesthetics.

Check out the Closer To Truth merch store for unique items like notebooks, mugs, and hoodies: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Finding Signal in the Noise with In Young Cho</title><link>https://signals-threads.simplecast.com/episodes/finding-signal-in-the-noise-with-in-young-cho-qBmfD9v_</link><author>Jane Street</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://cdn.simplecast.com/audio/173026e7-14f0-44e7-8362-8c1923903f77/episodes/ecc587de-3a66-4fbd-b70e-b377d7ce9672/audio/33a511f7-2a4a-4214-9e7d-2bb389130229/default_tc.mp3?aid=rss_feed&amp;feed=L9810DOa" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 14:41:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://signals-threads.simplecast.com/">Podcast - Signals and Threads</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In Young Cho thought she was going to be a doctor but fell into a trading internship at Jane Street. Now she helps lead the research group’s efforts in machine learning. In this episode, In Young and Ron touch on the porous boundaries between trading, research, and software engineering, which require different sensibilities but are often blended in a single person. They discuss the tension between flexible research tools and robust production systems; the challenges of ML in a low-data, high-noise environment subject to frequent regime changes; and the shift from simple linear models to deep neural networks.You can find the transcript for this episode on our website.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Origins of Jim Crow</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-origins-of-jim-crow</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/67cf1c54d64d9d8e86eefa65/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=BsnePbprmy9HgeeTXRDwUqmLjz6BLGqp2UScy-aVocY" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Jim Crow era is one of the darkest periods in American history. The country was divided by laws, customs and etiquettes that demeaned African Americans and segregated them from white Americans. But how exactly did this era begin? And was post-Civil War America always destined for racial segregation?To answer this question we're joined by Aaron Sheehan-Dean, a Professor of Southern Studies at Louisiana State University. He explains why America's attempts to build a multiracial democracy after the Civil War failed, and how the wheels of Jim Crow were set in motion.Produced by James Hickmann and edited by Dougal Patmore.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why is there something rather than nothing?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w18CHGA6qo8</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/w18CHGA6qo8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 19:00:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Here’s the ultimate question: what if it were true that everything always and forever had been ‘nothing’? Imagine that not a single thing ever existed–not emptiness, not blankness, not even the existence of emptiness, or the meaning of blankness. If you can image that, now ask yourself: why is there anything at all? Philosopher John Leslie shares his philosophy. #shorts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2287 - Josh Dubin &amp; J.D. Tomlinson</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mx8813RLUtc</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Mx8813RLUtc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Josh Dubin is the Executive Director of the Perlmutter Center for Legal Justice, a criminal justice reform advocate, and civil rights attorney.
https://cardozo.yu.edu/directory/josh-dubin

J.D. Tomlinson is a lawyer and was previously Lorain County Prosecutor in Ohio.

https://www.freetheohio4.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Unbearable Lightness of Data // Rohit Krishnan // #295</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/The-Unbearable-Lightness-of-Data--Rohit-Krishnan--295-e300ujv</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/99694655/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2025-2-11%2F396371951-44100-2-fe661592cbabd.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:05:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Unbearable Lightness of Data // MLOps Podcast #295 with Rohit Krishnan, Chief Product Officer at bodo.ai.Join the Community: https://go.mlops.community/YTJoinIn  Get the newsletter: https://go.mlops.community/YTNewsletter // AbstractRohit Krishnan, Chief Product Officer at Bodo.AI, joins Demetrios to discuss AI's evolving landscape. They explore interactive reasoning models, AI's impact on jobs, scalability challenges, and the path to AGI. Rohit also shares insights on Bodo.AI’s open-source move and its impact on data science.// BioBuilding products, writing, messing around with AI pretty much everywhere// Related LinksWebsite: www.strangeloopcanon.comIn life, my kids. Professionally, https://github.com/bodo-ai/Bodo ... Otherwise personally, it's writing every single day at strangeloopcanon.com! ~~~~~~~~ ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ ~~~~~~~Catch all episodes, blogs, newsletters, and more: https://go.mlops.community/TYExploreJoin our slack community [https://go.mlops.community/slack]Follow us on X/Twitter [@mlopscommunity](https://x.com/mlopscommunity) or [LinkedIn](https://go.mlops.community/linkedin)] Sign up for the next meetup: [https://go.mlops.community/register]MLOps Swag/Merch: [https://shop.mlops.community/]Connect with Demetrios on LinkedIn: /dpbrinkmConnect with Rohit on LinkedIn: /rkris]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Samir Okasha - Philosophy of Biology: Classifying Species &amp; Individuals</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZysBYH6Tkg8</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZysBYH6Tkg8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, new videos, musings, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

What is the classification system in biology, the taxonomy used to categorize organisms in a structured hierarchy? What are species and individuals in biological and evolutionary contexts, and what is the relationship between them?

Get member exclusives like early access to new content with a free Closer To Truth account: https://closertotruth.com/

Samir Okasha FBA, is a Professor of Philosophy of Science at University of Bristol. He was appointed a Fellow of the British Academy in 2018.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The State of the Ethereum Blockchain with Andrew Koller</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2025/03/11/the-state-of-the-ethereum-blockchain-with-andrew-koller/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-state-of-the-ethereum-blockchain-with-andrew-koller</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED4255543830.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 09:00:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Ethereum is a decentralized blockchain platform that was created by Vitalik Buterin and Gavin Wood in 2015. It uses a cryptocurrency called Ether as its native token to power transactions and operations on the Ethereum network. Ethereum’s proponents envision a future where the network forms the foundation for a second platform layer, called L2, where decentralized applications are run.As we approach the 10th anniversary of Ethereum’s creation we wanted to understand the state of the technology so we spoke with Andrew Koller who is an engineer at Kraken, which is a software company and popular cryptocurrency exchange. In this conversation Andrew talks about Kraken, security considerations at an exchange, the history of Ethereum, L2, and the future of Ethereum.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Everyone is talking about MCP (News)</title><link>https://changelog.com/news/135</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/news/135/changelog-news-135.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Vibe coding is the new vibe, AI engineers are all taking about MCP, Tom Usher wants you to kill your algorithmic feeds, Curiositry shares his troubleshooting expertise, Nikola Ðuza thinks we should keep blogging for the LLMs & James Stanier answers the question, should managers still code?Changelog++ members save 1 minute on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Temporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nancey Murphy - Arguing God from Moral Law?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kaBAxG6jxPU</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kaBAxG6jxPU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:01:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Like us on Facebook for daily videos, updates, announcements, and much more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

Humans have a sense of right and wrong. Does this mean that morality is absolute? And if it’s absolute, would God be needed to make it so? These are separate questions and both require particular answers to arrive at God. Even theologians are perplexed by God and morality; some even admit it.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Nancey Murphy is a philosopher and theologian who is Professor of Christian Philosophy at Fuller Theological Seminary in Pasadena, CA. She received a B.A. from Creighton University, a Ph.D. from University of California, Berkeley, and a Th.D. from the Graduate Theological Union.

Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Sphinx</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-sphinx</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/67c99971fc5f88b98d88db92/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=Ny2jz0WJhZWoGFy6wT3sHklkR2Hs2Bbxor5HoXtuSx4" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Great Sphinx of Giza is probably the most recognisable statue in the world but it’s also one of the most mysterious...with conflicting stories about who built it and why have circulated since ancient times. These include tales of what lies inside…To bust some of these myths, we're sharing this episode of Echoes of History, the podcast that delves into the history behind the Assassin's Creed games. In this episode, Egyptologist Dr Chris Naunton joins host Matt Lewis to explain everything you’ve always wanted to know about the mysteries of the Sphinx…Echoes of History is a History Hit podcast available on all podcast players.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Robert John Russell - Does a Fine-Tuned Universe Lead to God?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z6M5xCvlzFE</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Z6M5xCvlzFE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Contribute what you can to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

We human beings sit roughly midway between the sizes of atoms and galaxies, and both must be so perfectly structured for us to exist. It’s called ‘fine-tuning’ and it’s all so breathtakingly precise that it cries out for explanation. To some, fine-tuning leads to God. To others, there are non-supernatural explanations. Both are startling.

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Robert John Russell is founder and Director of the Center for Theology and the Natural Sciences. He is also the Ian G. Barbour Professor of Theology and Science in Residence at the Graduate Theological Union. He has written and edited extensively on possible scientific mechanisms of Christian belief. 

Browse Closer To Truth merch like notebooks, mugs, and sweatshirts in our online store: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Tom McLeish - Cosmology and Creation</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FwU_xc3VYZ4</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FwU_xc3VYZ4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 8 Mar 2025 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Show your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

How do physicists and philosophers who believe in God harmonize the discoveries of cosmology with the doctrine of creation? How does cosmology enhance or erode their belief in God? If God exists, must the universe have had a beginning? Conversely, if the universe had a beginning, must God exist?

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, perspectives, and more: https://shorturl.at/2eJCn

Thomas Charles Buckland was a British theoretical physicist. His work is renowned for increasing understanding of the properties of soft matter, which matter that can be easily changed by stress—including liquids, foams and biological materials. He was a professor in the Durham University Department of Physics and director of the Durham Centre for Soft Matter, a multidisciplinary team that works across physics, chemistry, mathematics and engineering. He also was the first Chair of Natural Philosophy at the University of York.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Friendly Feud: JS Party Edition (Friends)</title><link>https://changelog.com/friends/83</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/friends/83/changelog--friends-83.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2025 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Our award-winning JS Party game show is back with a new name, a new channel, and the same ol’ survey-response-guessing fun! The JS Party crew join us to see who knows y’all best. Survey says!Changelog++ members save 9 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Augment Code – Developer AI that uses deep understanding of your large codebase and how you build software to deliver personalized code suggestions and insights. Augment provides relevant, contextualized code right in your IDE or Slack. It transforms scattered knowledge into code or answers, eliminating time spent searching docs or interrupting teammates.
Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelogTemporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2286 - Antonio Brown</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NZBjSE6HQ0I</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NZBjSE6HQ0I?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2025 18:00:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Antonio Brown is a former professional football player, entertainer, and entrepreneur.  
https://x.com/AB84]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Victoria Harrison - Alternative Concepts of God?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-M0DdMjzD6o</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-M0DdMjzD6o?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Contribute any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions without the need for paywalls: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Is God, if there is a God, a personal, conscious, all-powerful Supreme Being? Some offer radically different concepts of ‘God’, exploring novel ideas of what God may be like. They challenge theism—the God of Judaism, Christianity and Islam—with radically new kinds of gods. Is this ‘heresy’? Or enlarging our vision of what the Ultimate can be like?

Follow Closer To Truth on Instagram for daily updates and exciting announcements: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

Victoria S. Harrison is a Professor of Philosophy and Associate Dean of the Faculty of Arts and Humanities at the University of Macau in China. She serves on the Board of Directors of the Center for East Asian and Comparative Philosophy (CEACOP), City University, Hong Kong. There she was a core member of the project Eastern and Western Conceptions of Oneness, Virtue, and Human Happiness (funded by the John Templeton Foundation).

Register for a free Closer To Truth membership to get special exclusives like early access to new episodes, event discounts, and more: https://closertotruth.com/register/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Antirez returns to Redis! (Interview)</title><link>https://changelog.com/podcast/631</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/podcast/631/the-changelog-631.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Antirez has returned to Redis! Yes, Salvatore Sanfilippo (aka Antirez), the creator of Redis has returned to Redis and he joined us to share the backstory on Redis, what’s going on with the tech and the company, the possible (likely) move back to open source via the AGPL license, the new possibilities of AI and vector embeddings in Redis, and some good ’ol LLM inference discussions.Changelog++ members get a bonus 5 minutes at the end of this episode and zero ads. Join today!Augment Code – Developer AI that uses deep understanding of your large codebase and how you build software to deliver personalized code suggestions and insights. Augment provides relevant, contextualized code right in your IDE or Slack. It transforms scattered knowledge into code or answers, eliminating time spent searching docs or interrupting teammates.
Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelogTemporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
Fly.io – The home of Changelog.com — Deploy your apps close to your users — global Anycast load-balancing, zero-configuration private networking, hardware isolation, and instant WireGuard VPN connections. Push-button deployments that scale to thousands of instances. Check out the speedrun to get started in minutes.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Kubernetes, AI Gateways, and the Future of MLOps // Alexa Griffith // #294</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/Kubernetes--AI-Gateways--and-the-Future-of-MLOps--Alexa-Griffith--294-e2vq5uk</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/99472788/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2025-2-6%2F396095316-44100-2-f001bd1bdf392.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2025 14:51:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Kubernetes, AI Gateways, and the Future of MLOps // MLOps Podcast #294 with Alexa Griffith, Senior Software Engineer at Bloomberg.Alexa shares her journey into software engineering, from early struggles with Airflow and Kubernetes to leading open-source projects like the Envoy AI Gateway. She and Demetrios discuss AI model deployment, tooling differences across tech roles, and the importance of abstraction. They highlight aligning technical work with business goals and improving cross-team communication, offering key insights into MLOps and AI infrastructure.Alexa Griffith is a Senior Software Engineer at Bloomberg, where she builds scalable inference platforms for machine learning workflows and contributes to open-source projects like KServe. She began her career at Bluecore working in data science infrastructure, and holds an honors degree in Chemistry from the University of Tennessee, Knoxville. She shares her insights through her podcast, Alexa’s Input (AI), technical blogs, and active engagement with the tech community at conferences and meetups.~~~~~~~~ ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ ~~~~~~~]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>THE LEADERS: Churchill</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-leaders-churchill</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/67c889513384591a38ab4faf/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=LhVLl_xKjSbsTNAvq0fE1i_513jXl6b9JSxf9980vGo" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Mar 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Susan Schneider on AI, Chatbots, and Consciousness | Closer To Truth Chats</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=exaBoY-t9OY</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/exaBoY-t9OY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 6 Mar 2025 20:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Professor Susan Schneider discusses the rise of AI chatbots like ChatGPT and others, transhumanism, and the future of artificial intelligence.

MindFest 2025: "Sentience, Autonomy, and the Future of Human-AI Interaction" is a two-day event from March 12-13 presented by the Center for the Future Mind. For more information, and to purchase tickets, click here: https://shorturl.at/pAszN

Dr. Susan Schneider is a philosopher and artificial intelligence (AI) expert. She is the founding director of the Center for the Future Mind at Florida Atlantic University where she also holds the William F. Dietrich Distinguished Professorship. Schneider has also held the Baruch S. Blumberg NASA/Library of Congress Chair in Astrobiology, Exploration, and Scientific Innovation at NASA and the Distinguished Scholar Chair at the Library of Congress.

Watch more CTT Chats here: https://t.ly/jJI7e

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and produced and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2285 - Andrew Schulz</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ihfM3qgWz6I</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ihfM3qgWz6I?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 6 Mar 2025 18:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Andrew Schulz is a stand-up comic, actor, and podcaster. He's the host of the "Flagrant" podcast with Akaash Singh, and the "Brilliant Idiots" podcast with Charlamagne Tha God. Look for his new special "Life" on March 4 on Netflix.
http://www.theandrewschulz.com
https://www.netflix.com/title/81741999

Try ZipRecruiter FOR FREE at http://ziprecruiter.com/rogan

Visit http://www.squarespace.com/ROGAN to save 10% off your first purchase of a website.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>StackHawk and Shift-Left API Security with Scott Gerlach</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2025/03/06/stackhawk-and-shift-left-api-security-with-scott-gerlach/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=stackhawk-and-shift-left-api-security-with-scott-gerlach</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED1603999548.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 6 Mar 2025 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[APIs are a fundamental part of modern software systems and enable communication between services, applications, and third-party integrations. However, their openness and accessibility also make them a prime target for security threats, and this makes APIs a growing focus on software teams.StackHawk is a company that scans and monitors source code to obtain the full scope of an organization’s APIs and applications, and runs tests to identify vulnerabilities and address them pre-production.Scott Gerlach is the Co-Founder and Chief Security Officer at StackHawk and previously worked at SendGrid and GoDaddy. He has an extensive background running security operations and engineering and, in this episode, he joins the show to talk about the challenges around API security and leading-edge strategies to address them.Full Disclosure: This episode is sponsored by]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2284 - Ian Carroll</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jJeRWPioGbQ</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/jJeRWPioGbQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 5 Mar 2025 18:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Ian Carroll is an independent researcher, entrepreneur, and host of "The Ian Carroll Show" on YouTube.
http://www.youtube.com/@Iancarrollshow
http://www.cancelthisclothingcompany.com

Go to http://ExpressVPN.com/ROGAN to get 4 months free!

Don’t miss out on all the action - Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using http://dkng.co/rogan or with my promo code ROGAN.

GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit http://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit http://ccpg.org (CT), or visit http://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD).21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS).1 per new customer. $5+ first-time bet req. Max. $150 issued as non-withdrawable Bonus Bets that expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: http://sportsbook.draftkings.com/promos. Ends 3/16/25 at 11:59 PM ET. Sponsored by DK.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>D-day to Berlin: The Americans Cross the Rhine</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-battle-of-remagen-the-americans-cross-the-rhine</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/67c1a747e5091241f34c73e7/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=eDkQHz4Tm4M0LvfzyUClsxiBXy1cBJsuo83j7KerLq0" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 5 Mar 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[80 years ago this week, American forces unexpectedly discovered an intact bridge across the river Rhine - the last natural defence of the crumbling Third Reich. They mounted a ferocious assault and after a bloody battle with the determined German defenders, were able to capture it, and push into the German heartland.In the latest episode of our 'D-Day to Berlin' series, Dan is joined again by John C. McManus. John explains how the American assault played out, and how it helped to hasten the end of the war.Produced by James Hickmann and edited by Dougal Patmore.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2283 - Billy Corgan</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OFt_pIzTrHU</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/OFt_pIzTrHU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 4 Mar 2025 18:00:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Billy Corgan is the lead singer of The Smashing Pumpkins and host of "The Magnificent Others" podcast. The Smashing Pumpkins' latest album, "Aghori Mhori Me," is available now. 
http://www.smashingpumpkins.com

This video is sponsored by BetterHelp. Visit http://BetterHelp.com/JRE

Don’t miss out on all the action - Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using http://dkng.co/rogan or with my promo code ROGAN.

GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit http://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit http://ccpg.org (CT), or visit http://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD).21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS).1 per new customer. $5+ first-time bet req. Max. $150 issued as non-withdrawable Bonus Bets that expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: http://sportsbook.draftkings.com/promos. Ends 3/16/25 at 11:59 PM ET. Sponsored by DK.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Future of Software, Agents in the Enterprise, and Inception Stage Company Building // Eliot Durbin // #293</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/Future-of-Software--Agents-in-the-Enterprise--and-Inception-Stage-Company-Building--Eliot-Durbin--293-e2vml7u</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/99357374/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2025-2-4%2F395952273-44100-2-072fa4fe55c3e.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 4 Mar 2025 16:42:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[// AbstractKey lessons for founders that are thinking about or starting their companies. 15 years of inception stage investing from how data science companies like Yhat went to market in 2013-14 and how that's evolved, to building companies around OSS frameworks like CrewAI; Eliot share's key learnings and questions for founders starting out.// BioEliot is a General Partner @ boldstart ventures since it's founding in 2010. boldstart an inception stage lead investor for technical founders building the next generation of enterprise companies such as Clay, Snyk, BigID, Kustomer, Superhuman, and CrewAI. ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>NVIDIA RAPIDS and Open Source ML Acceleration with Chris Deotte and Jean-Francois Puget</title><link>https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2025/03/04/nvidia-rapids-and-open-source-ml-acceleration-with-chris-deotte-and-jean-francois-puget/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=nvidia-rapids-and-open-source-ml-acceleration-with-chris-deotte-and-jean-francois-puget</link><author>SEDaily</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.megaphone.fm/SED6685234821.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 4 Mar 2025 10:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://softwareengineeringdaily.com/category/all-episodes/exclusive-content/podcast/">Podcast - Software Engineering Daily</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[NVIDIA RAPIDS is an open-source suite of GPU-accelerated data science and AI libraries. It leverages CUDA and significantly enhances the performance of core Python frameworks including Polars, pandas, scikit-learn and NetworkX.Chris Deotte is a Senior Data Scientist at NVIDIA and Jean-Francois Puget is the Director and a Distinguished Engineer at NVIDIA. Chris and Jean-Francois are also Kaggle Grandmasters, which is the highest rank a data scientist or machine learning practitioner can achieve on Kaggle, a competitive platform for data science challenges.In this episode, they join the podcast with Sean Falconer to talk about Kaggle, GPU-acceleration for data science applications, where they’ve achieved the biggest performance gains, the unexpected challenges with tabular data, and much more.Sean’s been an academic, startup founder, and Googler. He has published works covering a wide range of topics from AI to quantum computing. Currently, Sean is an AI Entrepreneur in Residence at Confluent where he works on AI strategy and thought leadership. You can connect with Sean on LinkedIn.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>JavaScript fatigue strikes back (News)</title><link>https://changelog.com/news/134</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/news/134/changelog-news-134.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 3 Mar 2025 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Allen Pike on the JavaScript ecosystem after a decade away, Lars Wirzenius was there at the birth of Linux, Piotr Migdał archives things in Markdown, Jacob Stopak is gamifying Git with Devlands & Juan Diego Rodríguez runs down how CSS functions (will) work.Changelog++ members save 1 minute on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Augment Code – Developer AI that uses deep understanding of your large codebase and how you build software to deliver personalized code suggestions and insights. Augment provides relevant, contextualized code right in your IDE or Slack. It transforms scattered knowledge into code or answers, eliminating time spent searching docs or interrupting teammates.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Story: Hatetris - Obsession, Friendship, and World Records</title><link>https://corecursive.com/hateris-with-david-and-felipe/</link><author>Adam@corecursive.com (Adam@corecursive.com)</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/corecursive/hateris.mp3?dest-id=628353" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 3 Mar 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="http://corecursive.com/">Podcast - CoRecursive</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[What if a simple game became a gateway to computational breakthroughs? David Freiberg and Felipe set out on a journey to conquer Hatetris, a notoriously difficult JavaScript game. Their interest ignited when a new world record was set, showing that surpassing the game's high score was possible.Their journey was full of challenges, from building an emulator in different programming languages to tackling complex algorithms. They pushed the boundaries of what's possible but the story didn't end there.Collaborating with fellow enthusiasts, including a Japanese Tetris expert, led to further breakthroughs. By sharing insights and building on each other's work, they set a records after records. Their story highlights the power of curiosity, collaboration, and the joy of discovery.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Agent Exchange: Practitioner Insights</title><link>https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/mlops/episodes/The-Agent-Exchange-Practitioner-Insights-e2vkc8v</link><author>Demetrios</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://anchor.fm/s/174cb1b8/podcast/play/99282655/https%3A%2F%2Fd3ctxlq1ktw2nl.cloudfront.net%2Fstaging%2F2025-2-3%2F395856045-44100-2-e9a90a655924f.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 3 Mar 2025 07:01:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mlops.community/">Podcast - MLOps</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Agents in Production [Podcast Limited Series] - Episode Five, Dmitri Jarnikov, Chiara Caratelli, and Steven Vester join Demetrios to explore AI agents in e-commerce. They discuss the trade-offs between generic and specialized agents, with Dmitri noting the need for a balance between scalability and precision. Chiara highlights how agents can dynamically blend both approaches, while Steven predicts specialized agents will dominate initially before trust in generic agents grows. The panel also examines how e-commerce platforms may resist but eventually collaborate with AI agents. Trust remains a key factor in adoption, with opportunities emerging for new agent-driven business models. Guest speakers: Dmitri Jarnikov - Senior Director of Data Science at ProsusChiara Caratelli - Data Scientist at Prosus GroupSteven Vester - Head of Product at OLXHost:Demetrios Brinkmann - Founder of MLOps Community~~~~~~~~ ✌️Connect With Us ✌️ ~~~~~~~Catch all episodes, blogs, newsletters, and more: https://go.mlops.community/TYExploreJoin our slack community [https://go.mlops.community/slack]Follow us on X/Twitter [@mlopscommunity](https://x.com/mlopscommunity) or [LinkedIn](https://go.mlops.community/linkedin)] Sign up for the next meetup: [https://go.mlops.community/register]MLOps Swag/Merch: [https://shop.mlops.community/]Connect with Demetrios on LinkedIn: /dpbrinkm]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>THE LEADERS: Hitler</title><link>https://shows.acast.com/dansnowshistoryhit/episodes/the-leaders-hitler</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://sphinx.acast.com/p/acast/s/dansnowshistoryhit/e/67c07cca24bc0fa2a1863585/media.mp3?tk=eyJ0ayI6ImRlZmF1bHQiLCJhZHMiOnRydWUsInNwb25zIjp0cnVlLCJzdGF0dXMiOiJwdWJsaWMifQ==&amp;sig=K0hrdchVGdG5bCC2l0Hy8M-GGHimt83Z1FuH6kmkrsE" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 3 Mar 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.historyhit.com/podcasts/">Podcast - HistoryHit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2282 - Bill Murray</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f_fM6v64-NQ</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/f_fM6v64-NQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 1 Mar 2025 18:00:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Bill Murray is an actor and comedian. He is currently starring in "Riff Raff." Look for him in "The Friend" in theaters on April 4. 

https://www.riffraffthemovie.com
https://bleeckerstreetmedia.com/the-friend

Save $20 on your first subscription of AG1 at drinkag1.com/joerogan]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Kaizen! Pipely goes BAM (Friends)</title><link>https://changelog.com/friends/82</link><author></author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://op3.dev/e/https://cdn.changelog.com/uploads/friends/82/changelog--friends-82.mp3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://changelog.com/podcast">Podcast - Changelog</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[It’s Kaizen 18! Can you believe it? We discuss the recent Fly.io outage, some little features we’ve added since our last Kaizen, our new video-first production, and of course, catch up on all things Pipely! Oh, and Gerhard surprises us (once again). BAM!Changelog++ members save 7 minutes on this episode because they made the ads disappear. Join today!Retool – The low-code platform for developers to build internal tools — Some of the best teams out there trust Retool…Brex, Coinbase, Plaid, Doordash, LegalGenius, Amazon, Allbirds, Peloton, and so many more – the developers at these teams trust Retool as the platform to build their internal tools. Try it free at retool.com/changelogSentry – Use the code  when you sign up to get $100 off the team plan.
Temporal – Build invincible applications. Manage failures, network outages, flaky endpoints, long-running processes and more, ensuring your workflows never fail. Register for Replay in London, March 3-5 to break free from the status quo.
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Delegation is a Love Language</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YN2aJvRjW5c</link><author>DevConf</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/YN2aJvRjW5c?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:38:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCmYAQDZIQGm_kPvemBc_qwg">Podcast - DevConfs</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Speaker(s): Jeff Ligon
The act of delegating work to someone else can be a gift or a curse. Come learn about how to make it more useful for you and the delegate. We'll walk through examples of doing it well and doing it badly, and examine the consequences of both. You might even leave the talk with an assignment designed to help you! homework is optional of course]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>