<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Podcasts</title><link>https://securenza.github.io/SecurityFeed/</link><description></description><item><title>Galen Strawson - What is Consciousness: Data or Information?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uBrcozQzkYE</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/uBrcozQzkYE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 9 Apr 2025 15:01:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, new videos, musings, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

To study consciousness comprehensively and rigorously, what kinds of data or information are relevant? Data/information for Materialism theories, which are subject to the scientific method, can be well defined. But what about non-Materialism theories?

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Galen John Strawson is a British analytic philosopher and literary critic who works primarily on philosophy of mind, metaphysics, John Locke, David Hume, Immanuel Kant, and Friedrich Nietzsche.

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dave Smith: Israel, Ukraine, Epstein, Mossad, Conspiracies &amp; Antisemitism | Lex Fridman Podcast #464</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1V0bJfqEaa4</link><author>Lex Fridman</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1V0bJfqEaa4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 8 Apr 2025 22:15:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSHZKyawb77ixDdsGog4iWA">Podcast - Lex Fridman</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dave Smith is a comedian, libertarian, political commentator, and the host of Part of the Problem podcast.
Thank you for listening ❤ Check out our sponsors: https://lexfridman.com/sponsors/ep464-sb
See below for timestamps, and to give feedback, submit questions, contact Lex, etc.

*CONTACT LEX:*
*Feedback* - give feedback to Lex: https://lexfridman.com/survey
*AMA* - submit questions, videos or call-in: https://lexfridman.com/ama
*Hiring* - join our team: https://lexfridman.com/hiring
*Other* - other ways to get in touch: https://lexfridman.com/contact

*EPISODE LINKS:*
Dave's X: https://x.com/ComicDaveSmith
Dave's YouTube: https://youtube.com/DSmithcomic
Dave's Instagram: https://instagram.com/theproblemdavesmith
Dave's Website: https://comicdavesmith.com/
Part of the Problem Podcast: https://partoftheproblem.com/

*SPONSORS:*
To support this podcast, check out our sponsors & get discounts:
*Call of Duty:* First-person shooter video game.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/call_of_duty-ep464-sb
*Tax Network USA:* Full-service tax firm.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/tax_network_usa-ep464-sb
*Notion:* Note-taking and team collaboration.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/notion-ep464-sb
*Shopify:* Sell stuff online.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/shopify-ep464-sb
*BetterHelp:* Online therapy and counseling.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/betterhelp-ep464-sb

*OUTLINE:*
0:00 - Episode highlight
1:26 - Introduction
1:45 - Libertarianism
3:00 - Ron Paul
6:13 - Military–industrial complex
13:06 - War on Terror
25:25 - China and Taiwan
33:13 - Just war theory
40:22 - Israel and Gaza
57:49 - Douglas Murray
1:05:42 - Hamas
1:22:01 - Hitler and Stalin
1:24:15 - Darryl Cooper
1:33:27 - Antisemitism
1:47:00 - World leaders
1:59:34 - Jeffrey Epstein
2:07:37 - Sam Harris
2:20:21 - Ukraine and Russia
2:39:46 - Joe Rogan
2:52:15 - Conspiracy theories
3:10:06 - Hope

*PODCAST LINKS:*
- Podcast Website: https://lexfridman.com/podcast
- Apple Podcasts: https://apple.co/2lwqZIr
- Spotify: https://spoti.fi/2nEwCF8
- RSS: https://lexfridman.com/feed/podcast/
- Podcast Playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrAXtmErZgOdP_8GztsuKi9nrraNbKKp4
- Clips Channel: https://www.youtube.com/lexclips

*SOCIAL LINKS:*
- X: https://x.com/lexfridman
- Instagram: https://instagram.com/lexfridman
- TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@lexfridman
- LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/lexfridman
- Facebook: https://facebook.com/lexfridman
- Patreon: https://patreon.com/lexfridman
- Telegram: https://t.me/lexfridman
- Reddit: https://reddit.com/r/lexfridman]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Bede Rundle - Is God Necessary?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FLTZpqqLjdA</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FLTZpqqLjdA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 8 Apr 2025 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get member exclusives like early access to new content with a free Closer To Truth account: https://closertotruth.com/

Whether God exists may depend on whether God is necessary. ‘Necessary’, in the philosophical sense, means ‘impossible not to exist’. Even if God exists, would it have been possible for God not to exist? Namely, even if God does exist, could it have been otherwise? If it were possible that God not exist, then why would God, as God is defined, exist at all?

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, new videos, musings, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

Bede Rundle is an Emeritus Fellow in Philosophy at Trinity College, Oxford. Educated in New Zealand at the Victoria University of Wellington and at Oxford, he has been a Junior Research Fellow at the Queen's College, Oxford, and has held visiting appointments in North America.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2301 - Ben Lamm</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRVEkc9lxH0</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NRVEkc9lxH0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 7 Apr 2025 17:03:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Ben Lamm is a serial entrepreneur and the founder and CEO of Colossal Biosciences, a company dedicated to genetic engineering and de-extinction projects. Colossal’s mission includes bringing back extinct species like the woolly mammoth and advancing conservation efforts through cutting-edge biotechnology.

https://www.colossal.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Bernardo Kastrup - Panpsychism: Arguing Pro and Con</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zcqKRJvM0Ng</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zcqKRJvM0Ng?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 7 Apr 2025 15:01:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Register for member exclusives like early access to new content with a free Closer To Truth account: https://closertotruth.com/

Panpsychism is the theory that consciousness is irreducible and exists fundamentally at the foundations of reality. Panpsychism forms include ‘micropsychism,’ where fundamental particles or fields are in some sense conscious, and ‘Cosmopsychism,’ where the entire universe is in some sense conscious. What are the arguments for and against Panpsychism like the ‘combination problem’?

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, new videos, musings, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

Bernardo Kastrup is a Brazilian-born Dutch philosopher and computer scientist best known for his work in the field of consciousness studies, particularly his development of analytic idealism, a form of metaphysical idealism grounded in the analytic philosophical tradition.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Marilyn Schlitz - Do Angels and Demons Exist?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qVBjzEkJt2Q</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qVBjzEkJt2Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 6 Apr 2025 15:01:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Shop the Closer To Truth merch store for unique items like notebooks, mugs, hoodies, and more: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Many theologians take angels and demons seriously. Why? Certainly, most human beings believe in angels and demons. Anecdotal cases are legion. Certainly, such nonphysical beings, in one form or another, populate most of the world’s religions. But angels and demons seem out of place, anachronistic, in our modern world. Is there anything here we should take seriously?

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help support Closer To Truth continue making content like this: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Marilyn Mandala Schlitz, PhD, is a clinical research scientist, medical anthropologist, writer, speaker, thought leader, and change consultant. Her work over the past three decades explores the interface of consciousness, science, and healing.

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2300 - Kyle Dunnigan</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-9shy1j8wjM</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-9shy1j8wjM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 5 Apr 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Kyle Dunnigan is an Emmy, Peabody and Writer’s Guild Award winning comedy writer. He also is the creator and host of “The Kyle Dunnigan Show." tour tickets at  https://www.kyledunnigancomedy.com/

Get a free welcome kit with your first subscription of AG1 at https://drinkag1.com/joerogan

Go to https://ExpressVPN.com/ROGAN to get 4 months free!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Stephen Barr - Can Philosophy Clarify Science vs. Religion?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sG9ezl1aCDc</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sG9ezl1aCDc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 5 Apr 2025 15:01:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Science and theology have a tumultuous history of conflict and strife on the one hand, and attempts to seek consilience and consonance on the other. Can philosophy help discern what may be true from what is clearly false? Which principles or methods of philosophy can adjudicate science vs theology?

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for insights, updates, and more: https://shorturl.at/twLQn

Stephen Matthew Barr is an American physicist who is a professor emeritus of physics at the University of Delaware. A member of its Bartol Research Institute, Barr does research in theoretical particle physics and cosmology. 

Shop Closer To Truth merchandise like notebooks, mugs, and sweatshirts in our online store: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Peter van Inwagen - Is the Soul Immortal?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zUjULrOoc5o</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zUjULrOoc5o?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 4 Apr 2025 19:00:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Contribute what you can to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions without the need for paywalls: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

The claim that human beings have or are an ‘immortal soul’ goes back to the ancient Greeks, if not further. In a pre-scientific world, it would seem absurd for our inner awareness not to continue, irrespective of what happens to our bodies. Today science rejects the soul, yet there are diverse viewpoints around.

Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Peter van Inwagen is an American analytic philosopher and the John Cardinal O'Hara Professor of Philosophy at the University of Notre Dame. He is also a research professor of philosophy at Duke University each spring.

Like Closer To Truth on Facebook for daily videos, updates, announcements, and much more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hubert Dreyfus - Does Philosophy Inform Religion?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OooNBHCOBiA</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/OooNBHCOBiA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 4 Apr 2025 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Follow Closer To Truth on Instagram for new videos, announcements, and more: https://www.instagram.com/closertotruth/

What can philosophy bring to religion? Philosophy is a systematic way of thinking about ideas and concepts, often fundamental features of the world. The philosophy of religion uses philosophical methodologies to examine religion, from the existence and attributes of God to the problems of evil, diverse religions, and conflicting belief systems.

Register for a free Closer To Truth membership to receive special exclusives like early access to new episodes and more: https://closertotruth.com/.

Hubert Lederer Dreyfus was an American philosopher and a professor of philosophy at the University of California, Berkeley. His main interests included phenomenology, existentialism and the philosophy of both psychology and literature, as well as the philosophical implications of artificial intelligence

Contribute what you can to support the show and help Closer To Truth continue exploring life's deepest questions: shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2299 - Dave Smith</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EmNE6yNxruc</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EmNE6yNxruc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 3 Apr 2025 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dave Smith is a stand-up comedian, libertarian political commentator, and podcaster. He's the host of the "Part of the Problem" podcast, as well as a co-host of the "Legion of Skanks” podcast.
https://www.comicdavesmith.com

50% off your first box at https://www.thefarmersdog.com/rogan!

Try ZipRecruiter FOR FREE at https://ziprecruiter.com/rogan]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Kevin Timpe - Why is There Evil?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EOw3TNbt7sU</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EOw3TNbt7sU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 3 Apr 2025 15:00:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Wear your support for the show with a Closer To Truth merch purchase: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Can God and the enormity of evil both exist? To theists, it’s the problem of evil, which they struggle to resolve. To atheists, it’s the argument from evil, which they wield like a sword. Theists try to absolve God by differentiating ‘God allowing evil’ from ‘God creating evil’. But if God is all-powerful and all-knowing, how could God not have created evil?

Like Closer To Truth on Facebook for daily videos, updates, announcements, and much more: https://shorturl.at/tak4l

Kevin Timpe currently holds the William H. Jellema Chair in Christian Philosophy at Calvin College. He's been a visiting faculty or scholar at Calvin Theological Seminary, Innsbruck University, Oxford University, and Peking University. He has written or edited ten books and published nearly 50 articles.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help Closer To Truth continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Alex Gómez-Marín - Can Near-Death Experiences Affect Consciousness Theories?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2zYSBKO9iXc</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2zYSBKO9iXc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 2 Apr 2025 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help support Closer To Truth continue making content like this: https://shorturl.at/OnyRq

Many people believe that out-of-body experiences (OBEs) and near-death experiences (NDEs) are real. We do not assess the evidence and arguments, pro or con. We do explore what OBEs and NDEs would mean, if real, for theories of consciousness.

Subscribe to the Closer To Truth podcast on Apple, Spotify, or wherever you listen: https://shorturl.at/mtJP4

Alex Gómez-Marín is a Spanish physicist turned neuroscientist. He holds a PhD in theoretical physics and a Masters in biophysics from the University of Barcelona. He was a research fellow at the EMBL-CRG Centre for Genomic Regulation and at the Champalimaud Centre for the Unknown in Lisbon. His research spans from the origins of the arrow of time in inert systems, to the neurobiology of action-perception in living organisms such as flies, worms, mice, and humans.

Shop the Closer To Truth merch store for unique items like notebooks, mugs, hoodies, and more: https://bit.ly/3P2ogje

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Joe Rogan Experience #2298 - Kurt Metzger</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bJbKgC_bMpI</link><author>PowerfulJRE</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bJbKgC_bMpI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 2 Apr 2025 17:00:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCzQUP1qoWDoEbmsQxvdjxgQ">Podcast - Joe Rogan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Kurt Metzger is a stand-up comic, writer, and host of the "Can't Get Right with Kurt Metzger" podcast. His latest special, "30 Minutes with Kurt Metzger," is available on YouTube. 
https://www.kurtmetzgercomedy.com

Get 10% off perfect boots at https://Tecovas.com/Rogan

Don’t miss out on all the action - Download the DraftKings app today! Sign-up using https://dkng.co/rogan or with my promo code ROGAN.

GAMBLING PROBLEM? CALL 1-800-GAMBLER, (800) 327-5050 or visit https://gamblinghelplinema.org (MA). Call 877-8-HOPENY/text HOPENY (467369) (NY). Please Gamble Responsibly. 888-789-7777/visit https://ccpg.org (CT), or visit https://www.mdgamblinghelp.org (MD). 21+ and present in most states. (18+ DC/KY/NH/WY). Void in ONT/OR/NH. Eligibility restrictions apply. On behalf of Boot Hill Casino & Resort (KS).1 per new customer. $5+ first-time bet req. Max. $150 issued as non-withdrawable Bonus Bets that expire in 7 days (168 hours). Stake removed from payout. Terms: https://sportsbook.draftkings.com/promos. Ends 4/13/25 at 11:59 PM ET. Sponsored by DK.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Eric Steinhart - Alternative Concepts of God?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zcCLwwVtYyY</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zcCLwwVtYyY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 2 Apr 2025 15:01:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, new videos, musings, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

Is God, if there is a God, a personal, conscious, all-powerful Supreme Being? Some offer radically different concepts of ‘God’, exploring novel ideas of what God may be like. They challenge theism – the God of Judaism, Christianity and Islam – with radically new kinds of gods. Is this ‘heresy’? Or enlarging our vision of what the Ultimate can be like?

Eric Charles Steinhart is Professor of Philosophy at William Paterson University. Among many articles and books, he has authored Your Digital Afterlives: Computational Theories of Life after Death and Believing in Dawkins: The New Spiritual Atheism.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Annaka Harris on Questions About Consciousness | Closer To Truth Chats</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gazcmEACMTA</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gazcmEACMTA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 1 Apr 2025 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Robert Lawrence Kuhn poses rapid-fire questions on consciousness to Annaka Harris, including inquiries like: Is consciousness fundamental? What is required for consciousness? What things are conscious? Can AI ever be conscious?

Annaka Harris is the New York Times bestselling author of "Conscious: A Brief Guide to the Fundamental Mystery of the Mind" and writer and producer of the new audio documentary series, "Lights On: How Understanding Consciousness Helps Us Understand the Universe".

The documentary is available for purchase now: https://amzn.to/3FHUKi3

Watch more CTT Chats here: https://t.ly/jJI7e

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn and produced and directed by Peter Getzels, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What things have awareness?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6af9OVuUWNo</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6af9OVuUWNo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 1 Apr 2025 13:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Do animals have awareness? Plants? Scientist Michael Graziano explores this question. #shorts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Edi Bilimoria - Evaluating Theories of Consciousness</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mCct-v6i8Ig</link><author>Closer To Truth</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mCct-v6i8Ig?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 15:01:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl9StMQ79LtEvlrskzjoYbQ">Podcast - Closer to Truth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get member exclusives like early access to new content with a free Closer To Truth account: https://closertotruth.com/

Given the myriad theories of consciousness on offer, how can they be assessed? What criteria should we use to compare and contrast diverse theories? Evaluating Materialism theories, like seeking neural correlates of consciousness, use the scientific method. But what about theories that are not Materialism?

Closer To Truth is now on BlueSky! Follow us for updates, new videos, musings, and more: https://bsky.app/profile/closertotruth.bsky.social

Edi Bilimoria has been a student of the perennial philosophy for over half a century. He has given courses and lectured extensively in the UK, and internationally in California, the Netherlands, India, and Australia, to encourage the cross fertilization of ideas in the fields of science, religion, and practical philosophy. Edi has published widely in the disciplines of science, engineering, esoteric philosophy, and occult science.

Make a tax-deductible donation of any amount to help us continue exploring the world's deepest questions: https://closertotruth.com/donate/

Closer To Truth, hosted by Robert Lawrence Kuhn, presents the world’s greatest thinkers exploring humanity’s deepest questions. Discover fundamental issues of existence. Engage new and diverse ways of thinking. Appreciate intense debates. Share your own opinions. Seek your own answers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Douglas Murray: Putin, Zelenskyy, Trump, Israel, Netanyahu, Hamas &amp; Gaza | Lex Fridman Podcast #463</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HvI42TyE5Ww</link><author>Lex Fridman</author><category>podcast</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HvI42TyE5Ww?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 20:12:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSHZKyawb77ixDdsGog4iWA">Podcast - Lex Fridman</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Douglas Murray is the author of On Democracies and Death Cults, The War on The West, and The Madness of Crowds.
Thank you for listening ❤ Check out our sponsors: https://lexfridman.com/sponsors/ep463-sb
See below for timestamps, transcript, and to give feedback, submit questions, contact Lex, etc.

*Transcript:*
https://lexfridman.com/douglas-murray-2-transcript

*CONTACT LEX:*
*Feedback* - give feedback to Lex: https://lexfridman.com/survey
*AMA* - submit questions, videos or call-in: https://lexfridman.com/ama
*Hiring* - join our team: https://lexfridman.com/hiring
*Other* - other ways to get in touch: https://lexfridman.com/contact

*EPISODE LINKS:*
Douglas's X: https://x.com/DouglasKMurray
Douglas's YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/@douglasmurray
Douglas's Instagram: https://instagram.com/douglaskmurray
Douglas's Website: https://douglasmurray.net
On Democracies and Death Cults (book): https://amzn.to/4jahsxL
The War on the West (book): https://amzn.to/38L7B36

*SPONSORS:*
To support this podcast, check out our sponsors & get discounts:
*Call of Duty:* First-person shooter video game.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/call_of_duty-ep463-sb
*Oracle:* Cloud infrastructure.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/oracle-ep463-sb
*LMNT:* Zero-sugar electrolyte drink mix.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/lmnt-ep463-sb
*AG1:* All-in-one daily nutrition drink.
Go to https://lexfridman.com/s/ag1-ep463-sb

*OUTLINE:*
0:00 - Episode highlight
0:24 - Introduction
2:38 - War in Ukraine
6:24 - Trump and Zelenskyy
20:54 - Putin
41:47 - Peace
51:38 - Zelenskyy
1:06:17 - Israel-Palestine
1:17:04 - Hamas
1:31:37 - Corruption
1:34:47 - Gaza
1:55:25 - Benjamin Netanyahu
2:12:36 - Hate
2:37:06 - Iran
2:47:55 - Interview advice
3:02:19 - War

*PODCAST LINKS:*
- Podcast Website: https://lexfridman.com/podcast
- Apple Podcasts: https://apple.co/2lwqZIr
- Spotify: https://spoti.fi/2nEwCF8
- RSS: https://lexfridman.com/feed/podcast/
- Podcast Playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrAXtmErZgOdP_8GztsuKi9nrraNbKKp4
- Clips Channel: https://www.youtube.com/lexclips

*SOCIAL LINKS:*
- X: https://x.com/lexfridman
- Instagram: https://instagram.com/lexfridman
- TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@lexfridman
- LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/lexfridman
- Facebook: https://facebook.com/lexfridman
- Patreon: https://patreon.com/lexfridman
- Telegram: https://t.me/lexfridman
- Reddit: https://reddit.com/r/lexfridman]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>